<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Obama on alper.nl</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/obama/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Obama on alper.nl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 15:10:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/obama/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A World That Donates As One</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/07/a-world-that-donates-as-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2008 15:10:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=325</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://my.barackobama.com/page/content/berlinvideo/&#34;&gt;Barack&amp;rsquo;s visit to Europe&lt;/a&gt; again makes clear how important it is to people over here who exactly is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POTUS&#34;&gt;POTUS&lt;/a&gt;. A lot of people in Europe are interested and invested in American politics and for good reason if you see the effect the American&amp;rsquo;s actions can have on the rest of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.focus.de/politik/diverses/umfrage-obama-erhaelt-positive-resonanz_aid_320391.html&#34;&gt;Polls show&lt;/a&gt; that Europeans overwhelmingly support Barack Obama and would like to see him in office as opposed to McCain. This makes it extra annoying that our power to influence the process is severely limited. American elections are in a large part dominated by money and &lt;a href=&#34;https://donate.barackobama.com/&#34;&gt;the raising of it&lt;/a&gt;. Unfortunately &lt;a href=&#34;http://my.barackobama.com/page/community/post/harryroes/gGCSfZ/commentary&#34;&gt;non-Americans are excluded&lt;/a&gt; from making donations. Something about foreigners not being allowed to elect the American President.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Een perfectere samenleving</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/03/een-perfectere-samenleving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2008 15:00:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/03/een-perfectere-samenleving/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Voor Mark en eigenlijk voor iedereen: de toespraak die Obama vorige week hield over ras. De voorganger van zijn zwarte kerk had een paar politiek-incorrecte uitspraken gedaan die uiteraard uit den treure herhaald werden op de Amerikaanse &lt;em&gt;news networks&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama liet zich niet kennen en deed niet aan reactieve damage control. Hij schreef in twee dagen een speech om naar aanleiding van die gewraakte uitspraken het grotere en belangrijkere probleem van ras aan de orde te stellen dat boven Amerika maar vooral boven deze verkiezingscampagne hangt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
