<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Berlin on alper.nl</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/berlin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Berlin on alper.nl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:27:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/berlin/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18379/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 16:27:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/2025/10/18379/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cycling home from having done groceries yesterday night, I wondered why there were police officers with machine guns standing on the sidewalk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turns out this was why: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.berlin.de/polizei/polizeimeldungen/2025/pressemitteilung.1606865.php&#34;&gt;https://www.berlin.de/polizei/polizeimeldungen/2025/pressemitteilung.1606865.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>U-Bahn Takes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/u-bahn-takes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 21:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18324</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Subway Takes is publishing episodes they filmed in Berlin’s U-Bahn, and the results are both amusing and unexpectedly revealing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show itself needs almost no introduction since it’s become a mainstream online phenomenon. Subway Takes features comedian and musician Kareem talking to NYC personalities who share their “takes” during brief subway rides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He ventures outside of New York once in a while, and after London and Paris, has now turned up in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18305/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Sep 2025 10:26:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18305</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much time for an innovative/edgy/creative agency to copy this (poorly) in Berlin?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/pursuit-scavenger-hunt-san-francisco&#34;&gt;https://www.wired.com/story/pursuit-scavenger-hunt-san-francisco&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18183/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 20:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18183</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have kids in two parallel classes at school which lets us compare things directly and gives us insights many of the other parents don&amp;rsquo;t have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One class was doing great and the other one was struggling, this also made the parents of that class become frustrated and non-constructive. I&amp;rsquo;m in two Whatsapp groups and can compare the vibe and noise level of both directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the class that was struggling got a clinch new staff member and the class that was doing well&amp;rsquo;s teachers got disbanded and the atmosphere among the parents changed night and day. Now the parents who were chill are creating way more noise and the other parents are much more constructive and relaxed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18071/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 08:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18071</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hundred percent sure that if the same policy would be applied to Berlin most car traffic would evaporate from our streets here immediately. Most traffic in my neighborhood is people without really that much to do who could be doing something other than driving and drug dealers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fastcompany.com/91272434/a-million-cars-have-disappeared-what-nyc-is-like-after-one-month-of-congestion-pricing&#34;&gt;https://www.fastcompany.com/91272434/a-million-cars-have-disappeared-what-nyc-is-like-after-one-month-of-congestion-pricing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18066/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 08:30:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18066</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve revived our tech blog and will be sharing a bunch of stuff around our AI process and what it means to be an &amp;ldquo;AI first&amp;rdquo; company. Here&amp;rsquo;s an in-depth first piece about what it takes to develop a successful real life product with LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://choco.com/us/stories/life-at-choco/scaling-ai-applications-with-llms&#34;&gt;https://choco.com/us/stories/life-at-choco/scaling-ai-applications-with-llms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December Adventure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/december-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17749</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I felt I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really bring myself to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com&#34;&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt; this year since I have more than enough other things to do (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcane_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/333640/Caves_of_Qud/&#34;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt;) and with work and the kids, it&amp;rsquo;s always pretty miserable to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this thing called &lt;a href=&#34;https://eli.li/december-adventure&#34;&gt;December Adventure&lt;/a&gt; though and that fits in nicely with my current push to release a major update for &lt;a href=&#34;https://cuppin.gs&#34;&gt;Cuppings&lt;/a&gt;. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be programming until late this month, then I&amp;rsquo;d prefer it to be on something that I can release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17725/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 22:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17725</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nicolas from &lt;a href=&#34;https://allaboutberlin.com&#34;&gt;All About Berlin&lt;/a&gt; has done so much to make living in this administrative nightmare bearable for people. It&amp;rsquo;s a very clear example of what kind of 10-100x improvements are there to be had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nicolasbouliane.com/projects/all-about-berlin&#34;&gt;https://nicolasbouliane.com/projects/all-about-berlin&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Renaming half a street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17708/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 18:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17708</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting article to read about how the city botched renaming the Manteuffelstraße to Audrey-Lord-Straße. I cycle past this street every day and I don&amp;rsquo;t think it&amp;rsquo;s a bad change. Unfortunately, they&amp;rsquo;ve done it in such a bad way that it&amp;rsquo;ll poison every person who hears about it against the very concept of government:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They failed to notify the people living there until after the change had already passed (incompetent!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They decided to only rename part of the street (insane!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Renaming part of the street forces the street numbers to be re-allocated (insane!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;„Im Nachhinein ist das eine ­gute Frage“, sagt Werner Heck von der ­Bezirksverordnetenversammlung (BVV) Friedrichshain-Kreuzberg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GIFT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gift/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 08:39:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17699</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Watched “Evil Does Not Exist” as GIFT, the recut and rescored (silent) version performed live by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eiko_Ishibashi&#34;&gt;Eiko Ishibashi&lt;/a&gt; at HAU1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;IMG_7406.jpeg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has a shorter runtime than the movie because a lot of fluff is cut out and we are only left with a very summary story. That is a good choice and I can&amp;rsquo;t say the movie suffers from it very much even though this is version is very much its own thing (i.e. not a narrative movie).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17669/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 17:37:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17669</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love having the kids be off school every 6 weeks or so which means we get a week of everybody adjusting to them being at home and then another week of adjusting them being back at school. All thanks to the trash tier school logistics of Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reckoning with the Greens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reckoning-with-the-greens/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 06:52:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17567</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After some occasional brushes with party politics and reading up on the minimal political agency that we foreigners get here, I dove in. The rise of right-wing sentiment seemed to be a good reason to become a member of the Greens just like I imagine it did for a number of people. Much good that did do if you see the continued rise of that sentiment and this Green government all but enabling right-wing parties with their politics of austerity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17632/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 20:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17632</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanted to show the kids some chiaroscuro for their art class about light and dark tomorrow and ran through some of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.artrenewal.org/artists/caravaggio/589&#34;&gt;the all time greats from Caravaggio&lt;/a&gt;. They were particularly impressed by Holofernes being beheaded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always stunning to see how good these paintings are and a bit sad for how long it&amp;rsquo;s been since I saw one for real. But &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spsg.de/en/palaces-gardens/object/picture-gallery-of-sanssouci&#34;&gt;Sanssouci&lt;/a&gt; has the picture of Doubting Thomas so that can be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17624/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 10:39:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17624</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mspr0.de/newsletter/&#34;&gt;Krasse Links&lt;/a&gt; looks like yet another collection of links but the German wall of text notwithstanding, it&amp;rsquo;s a remarkable act of curation and contextualisation. Remarkable and unique for sure in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few people here who have the desire and skills to be able to look beyond the borders, beyond the &lt;em&gt;Tellerrand&lt;/em&gt;, and who feel that what the German state and establishment press and media serve you is simply not good enough. I&amp;rsquo;d be hard pressed to suggest anything at the same level as what Michael Seemann here and any German interested in the intersection of technology and politics would be well served to read this newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17606/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:26:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17606</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Trying for years to explain to people that Germany has almost zero &lt;a href=&#34;https://adamtooze.substack.com/p/chartbook-296-project-power-hegemony&#34;&gt;project power&lt;/a&gt; and is incapable of any progress and then suddenly &lt;a href=&#34;https://eu-acc.com&#34;&gt;a movement springs up&lt;/a&gt; that agrees entirely with that assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure if I should be pleased or miffed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Waarom ik geen ID-Check kan gebruiken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/waarom-ik-geen-id-check-kan-gebruiken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2024 07:51:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17600</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Met een nieuwe identiteitskaart of paspoort die je in het buitenland krijgt (als je niet meer in Nederland woont), kun je niet meer ID-Check van DigiD gebruiken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik vroeg me af waarom dat was en kreeg dit antwoord:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Identiteitsbewijzen die in het buitenland worden uitgegeven, worden door de Rijksdienst voor Identiteitsgegevens (RvIG - uitgever van de Nederlandse identiteitskaart en paspoort) niet in de Basisregistratie Personen (BRP) geregistreerd. DigiD gebruikt de BRP tijdens de ID-check om te controleren of het identiteitsbewijs (ID) een geldig ID is dat bij die gebruiker hoort. Dat kan dus niet wanneer het ID-bewijs in het buitenland is uitgegeven. Om deze grote groep mensen in het buitenland toch te helpen, controleert de DigiD app tijdens de ID-check het burgerservicenummer (BSN) in de chip van identiteitsbewijzen die in het buitenland zijn uitgegeven. En vergelijkt dan of dat overeenkomt met het BSN dat hoort bij het DigiD-account van de gebruiker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17584/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 15:11:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17584</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Always nice to be able to write stuff that the team has been doing and share it with the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kubernetes is a very maligned technology but if properly managed it can be part of an entirely boring infrastructure portfolio. Realistically it&amp;rsquo;s not doing that much more than running docker on a bunch of machines and pulling images. React has a similarly bad reputation which is not stopping lots of developers from getting tons of work done with it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17552/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 08:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17552</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember when I got banned from the forum of one of Germany&amp;rsquo;s larger liberal podcasts for saying that Bitcoin is mostly something by and for criminals. I think that statement was pretty much entirely correct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of the Texas Bitcoin mine is sad but we&amp;rsquo;re living through something similar now where the construction site has installed yet another permanent noise device (a pump) next to our home. The noise level is not too high, but even if it were, it&amp;rsquo;s not like anything would be done in Berlin about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17513/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 11:28:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17513</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Netzpolitik has done a lot of good things, no doubt. But I&amp;rsquo;m left with a bit of a double feeling after reading Beckedahl&amp;rsquo;s farewell post. Imagine having spent 20 years to improve the state of the German internet (“eine bessere digitale Welt möglich ist”) and you leave with the situation like it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://netzpolitik.org/2024/abschied-danke-netzpolitik-org/&#34;&gt;https://netzpolitik.org/2024/abschied-danke-netzpolitik-org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17505/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 23:48:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17505</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The news that an OSINT researcher spent 30 minutes to find a fugitive that the German police couldn&amp;rsquo;t find in the past 30 years says a lot about how government works here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most likely the police would say that they couldn&amp;rsquo;t use any modern tools or data sources here because of &lt;em&gt;Datenschutz&lt;/em&gt; (data protection) reasons. Datenschutz is 1. a great excuse for people who don&amp;rsquo;t want to do their jobs and 2. a way to protect every kind of crook and criminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17496/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 18:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17496</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come to Berlin, they said. There&amp;rsquo;s lots of space here, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the mean time in Berlin everything is full and anything related to children is wildly under-provisioned (because Germany out of principle does not invest in anything). That creates waiting lists and insane competition for everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rbb24.de/panorama/beitrag/2024/02/berlin-infrastruktur-kinder-kein-platz-wartelisten-teuer.html&#34;&gt;https://www.rbb24.de/panorama/beitrag/2024/02/berlin-infrastruktur-kinder-kein-platz-wartelisten-teuer.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17492/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:40:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17492</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I found a new German podcast crush in Hart Unfair which is my favorite format: three people (Anna Dushime, Yelda Türkmen and Ari Christmann) rambling through one another but in a way that&amp;rsquo;s funny, intelligent and diverse. It&amp;rsquo;s a shame that they publish so irregularly that I can&amp;rsquo;t tell if the podcast is dead or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the hosts dropped a casual &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/c/hasanabi&#34;&gt;Hasan Piker&lt;/a&gt; reference (in a conversation about pop culture and leftist politics) and… I didn&amp;rsquo;t even know there were Germans who know who that is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17479/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 09:36:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17479</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ProgrammerDude/status/1758148576134177246&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/ProgrammerDude/status/1758148576134177246&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin has a not very well-known facility that allows you to request a Meldebescheinigung online, pay for it online and receive it by mail. I attended Arian to it and it saved his bacon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people here will deny that government digitalisation here is possible or desirable both of which are statements that are untrue and deranged. It &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; possible to create better services for people. Germans just choose to live in abject squalor for no reason.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SPY x Family - Das Leben der Anderen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17455/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17455</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying another light season of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spy_%C3%83%E2%80%94_Family&#34;&gt;SPY x FAMILY&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a light anime whose premise is that of a spy (Loid) who needs live in deep cover in hostile territory and forms a family of convenience. He finds a woman (Yor) who&amp;rsquo;s secretly an assassin also in need of cover and an orphan child (Anya) who&amp;rsquo;s a telepath. It&amp;rsquo;s great fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;IMG_5912.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Season 2 goes on with the story arc and some filler segments thrown in between. Of these, in the third episode ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://trakt.tv/shows/spy-x-family/seasons/2/episodes/3&#34;&gt;S02E03&lt;/a&gt;) they pull off a stunning take on &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/film/the-lives-of-others/&#34;&gt;“Das Leben der Anderen”&lt;/a&gt;. I was watching it and by the time it was over I couldn&amp;rsquo;t believe they&amp;rsquo;d done this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17438/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 12:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17438</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As somebody who dove pretty deep into how to run a creative agency in a way that&amp;rsquo;s innovative and goes against the grain, I really like what Village One here in Berlin are doing with their cooperative approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be following them closely and I hope they survive on their terms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.village.one/garden/library/what-is-a-cooperative&#34;&gt;https://www.village.one/garden/library/what-is-a-cooperative&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17418/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 17:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17418</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t really buy this idea that Japan&amp;rsquo;s urban environment has been the key factor to create its immense specialization in crafts. Compare it to Berlin where rents have been incredibly cheap and zoning mixed but without the necessary human capital the only thing those factors generated were cheap bars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://resnikoff.substack.com/p/why-osaka-gets-to-have-nice-things&#34;&gt;https://resnikoff.substack.com/p/why-osaka-gets-to-have-nice-things&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2023-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17382</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back on 2023 I can say that we made lemonade out of an overall pretty shit year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not to worry. This is probably just one shit year in a sequence of many more shit years to come. No sign of anything getting better in our near future and lots of trends pointing downward. Does it have to be like this? Not in any way but the majority of people are stupid and we all suffer together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17357/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 11:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17357</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last episode of Spaßbremse treats the history of German-Israeli relations and clarifies what the strategic foundations of the current complex are: white-washing and moral standing for one side and economic reparations and industrial capacity building for the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thinly veiled racism and colonialism is just the rotten cherry on top.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://podtail.com/de/podcast/spassbremse/52-whitewashing-and-statebuilding-german-israeli-r/&#34;&gt;https://podtail.com/de/podcast/spassbremse/52-whitewashing-and-statebuilding-german-israeli-r/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fragment Ones and Tooze: Live from Berlin - Lindner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/fragment-ones-and-tooze-live-from-berlin-lindner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 12:06:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17325</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Given the current developments around the German debt brake, I think it&amp;rsquo;s good to refer to this bit about German financial politics and Adam Tooze&amp;rsquo;s initial prediction ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/8edcb755-b05a-4ee4-940c-f3660d4240c5&#34;&gt;FT&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://adamtooze.com/2021/10/27/it-would-be-a-mistake-to-grant-him-his-wish/&#34;&gt;Zeit&lt;/a&gt;) that Christian Lindner as finance minister would not be good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fragment from around 45:00 clipped below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;audio controls preload=&#34;metadata&#34;&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;volkskorper.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mp3&#34;&gt;
  Your browser does not support the audio element.
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We got quite a lot of shit for doing that actually. Not entirely popular with my German colleagues. ‘Nicht zum Volkskörper zugehörig’ is a phrase that was used. ‘Wie trauen sie sich ein solches Urteil zu.’&lt;br&gt;
Not belonging to the body politic of Germany. How dare you make a judgement like that.&lt;br&gt;
We don&amp;rsquo;t have any reason to regret it. We were clearly right.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17317/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 09:12:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17317</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An unexpected deep dive on the problem of unaffordable and underutilized land as it relates to Berlin. It manages to even sneak in some mentions of land reform and land value taxes (which would solve this problem pretty much instantaneously).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://interaktiv.tagesspiegel.de/lab/ausgebaut-berlins-explodierende-bodenpreise-machen-wohnungsbau-unbezahlbar/&#34;&gt;https://interaktiv.tagesspiegel.de/lab/ausgebaut-berlins-explodierende-bodenpreise-machen-wohnungsbau-unbezahlbar/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17312/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 15:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17312</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding time for side projects and putting out new versions of Cuppings is difficult as always, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad we have a new version out this week again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of things still to do is long as ever but for now enjoy the newest most up to date version of your favourite coffee drinking guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/de/app/cuppings/id652901707?l=en-GB&#34;&gt;https://apps.apple.com/de/app/cuppings/id652901707?l=en-GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17308/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2023 17:45:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17308</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SOMETIME IN THE 2000S,&lt;/strong&gt; a group of mostly Turkish women from an immigrant group called Neighborhood Mothers began meeting in the Neukölln district of Berlin to learn about the Holocaust. Their history lessons were part of a program facilitated by members of the Action Reconciliation Service for Peace, a Christian organization dedicated to German atonement for the Shoah. The Neighborhood Mothers were terrified by what they learned in these sessions. “How could a society turn so fanatical?”a group member named Nazmiye later recalled thinking. “We began to ask ourselves if they could do such a thing to us as well . . . whether we would find ourselves in the same position as the Jews.”But when they expressed this fear on a church visit organized by the program, their German hosts became apoplectic. “They told us to go back to our countries if this is how we think,”Nazmiye said. The session was abruptly ended and the women were asked to leave.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17185/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 22:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17185</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this podcast episode a court case is treated (with the public prosecutor) where during a fluke accident a girl riding along on a bike is killed by a bus in Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thoroughness and consideration with which that is done contrasted immensely with how things run in Berlin and made it clear to me (again) how unserious this city is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://art19.com/shows/napleiten/episodes/88038eb8-3146-499d-983d-ebadce4c3e8f&#34;&gt;https://art19.com/shows/napleiten/episodes/88038eb8-3146-499d-983d-ebadce4c3e8f&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17095/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 07:55:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17095</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s super lovely that Berlin has a lab which does these kind of user tested innovations on city processes. The work that needs to be done is written up here and it&amp;rsquo;s relatively straight-forward (there are just no short-cuts).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What we need with the Bürgeramt though is not 10% more appointments but the automation of at least half of the processes there to no longer need human intervention. We needed that 10 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17033/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2023 09:42:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17033</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Important prototyping work to show how German government forms can be much better and much friendlier than what&amp;rsquo;s out there right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting anything like this to production will be very very difficult without a lot of systemic changes and groundwork done first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://citylab-berlin.org/de/blog/nutzerzentrierte-digitale-verwaltung-bessere-online-antraege-durch-co-kreation-mit-buergerinnen/&#34;&gt;https://citylab-berlin.org/de/blog/nutzerzentrierte-digitale-verwaltung-bessere-online-antraege-durch-co-kreation-mit-buergerinnen/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17010/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 23:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17010</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my notes, a bunch of receipts about just one of the dark pasts of the German Green Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.patreon.com/posts/meet-german-from-60420980&#34;&gt;https://www.patreon.com/posts/meet-german-from-60420980&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16991/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:31:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16991</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Always nice to have the company you work for be covered by the local newspaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/berliner-start-up-choco-die-app-fur-den-chefkoch-9250776.html&#34;&gt;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/berliner-start-up-choco-die-app-fur-den-chefkoch-9250776.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16977/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2023 11:28:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16977</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Love to see these updates from the German Digital Service. Not sure everybody knows that that organization exists now and what they&amp;rsquo;re busy with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work they&amp;rsquo;re doing is really good but what&amp;rsquo;s really staggering is how much of a gap they have to bridge here. These are basic buildings blocks of digital transformation that advanced societies tackled 10-20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://digitalservice.bund.de/blog/mit-kommunikationsdesign-nutzerzentrierte-verwaltungsmodernisierung-unterstuetzen&#34;&gt;https://digitalservice.bund.de/blog/mit-kommunikationsdesign-nutzerzentrierte-verwaltungsmodernisierung-unterstuetzen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16854/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 11:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16854</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/SteveFi04457564/status/1558065690820624387&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/SteveFi04457564/status/1558065690820624387&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something we&amp;rsquo;re also noticing here is that people with dogs gather in courtyards and on fields in groups and let their dogs roam free, illegally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do this in groups together so that if somebody tells them not to, they can use their numbers to intimidate and as described here they use that and many other strategies with officers of the law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owning a dog in a dense urban environment is a questionable choice already, but the people around us here take the cake. There are quite a number of socially at-risk individuals who have dogs where both the animal and the human are deeply and certifiably deranged. Both of them accost any human who walks by and it&amp;rsquo;s often a question of who&amp;rsquo;s louder the dog&amp;rsquo;s barking or its owner&amp;rsquo;s ranting.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16785/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 19:52:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16785</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lots of hours put in over the past year to achieve this and the only thing it means is that I get to put lots more hours in. Let&amp;rsquo;s go!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://techcrunch.com/2022/04/11/choco-unicorn-food-waste-supply-chain/amp/?guccounter=1&#34;&gt;https://techcrunch.com/2022/04/11/choco-unicorn-food-waste-supply-chain/amp/?guccounter=1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16739/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:11:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16739</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not verified but an interesting data point in how German civil servants don&amp;rsquo;t have that attractive a position and can get better deals working indirectly for the people &amp;lsquo;at the engines of the global economy&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That makes you wonder why the engines of the global economy are not here or if they are why it&amp;rsquo;s not possible to pay civil servants competitive both in compensation and in job satisfaction. To be able to get the best talent and create the kind of state capacity that justifies having a state, the best people working in the civil service should be paid competitively with the top of society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Property dealings in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16736/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 12:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16736</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://parisinstitute.org/the-real-academy-in-exile/#ref1&#34;&gt;https://parisinstitute.org/the-real-academy-in-exile/#ref1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back when I read this exposé in November it struck me as gripping but also as something that could become messy. Turns out that&amp;rsquo;s true since the piece now has the mark &amp;ldquo;Censored&amp;rdquo; and some choice parts of text have been blanked out. I did a quick search but can&amp;rsquo;t find any updates what might have happened. If I find time later, I&amp;rsquo;ll look in the Wayback Machine to see what pieces of text disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16718/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 21:45:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16718</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was on a Dutch podcast about working in Germany: FSG podcast over de Duitse digitale achterstand with Derk Marseille and Ruurd van der Weide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.springcast.fm/14601/fsg-podcast-over-de-duitse-digitale-achterstand&#34;&gt;https://app.springcast.fm/14601/fsg-podcast-over-de-duitse-digitale-achterstand&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year Note 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/year-note-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16685</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The days are long but the years are short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more year over and these are starting to look like a blur, so here&amp;rsquo;s what changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave notice between Christmas and New Year 2020 and spent the first three months of the year in a weird in-between state mostly done with the old job, waiting for the new one to start, in between daycare closures and being sick.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update on the construction site</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/update-on-the-construction-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 22:03:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16655</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2021/11/chasing-down-noise-complaints-for-the-construction-site-next-to-our-house/&#34;&gt;construction site next&lt;/a&gt; to our house is still spewing forth noise and fumes at all hours. The city is unable to do anything here it seems and calling the people at the construction site we are met with nothing but deflection and lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They have built a housing around the heater which has maybe reduced the noise by 5dB and we are still left with a value that is far above what is allowed here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chasing down noise complaints for the construction site next to our house</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/chasing-down-noise-complaints-for-the-construction-site-next-to-our-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 21:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16630</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The construction site that surrounds our house has started a bunch of space heaters this week. The devices had been there for a while but only started being annoying now that they&amp;rsquo;re turned on. These things run day and night, they make a ridiculous amount of noise (some 60 dB at our window) and because they burns diesel oil they also pollute and stink up the entire courtyard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;IMG_1458-1.jpg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are used to some noise and annoyance during the day time with this construction site. Some of the noise we went through was truly unbelievable and for some periods we have received a reduction in our rent. We thought that with most external construction being done, we would finally be able to get some peace but now these things are running and will probably run all winter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tram lines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tram-lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 08:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16583</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking at this map of expansions we may have a tram line in front of our house in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/regineguenther/status/1430834098910674946?s=11&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/regineguenther/status/1430834098910674946?s=11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16538/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 15:57:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16538</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;dass deutsche Behörden und bürokratische Prozesse mitverantwortlich sind am Scheitern des Start-ups.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A kind of magical thinking that would rely on collaborating with German government institutions for your startup. The only way that is going to work is if you have a very special (paid for) in into the CDU. Also otherwise a hilarious story about the weird world of cyber.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.br.de/nachrichten/netzwelt/cyberwaffen-made-in-berlin,Sbzq3WP&#34;&gt;https://www.br.de/nachrichten/netzwelt/cyberwaffen-made-in-berlin,Sbzq3WP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16461/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 10:49:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16461</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another big volley towards more tenants’ rights in Berlin that if won will provoke a vast shift in thinking around housing politics both locally and globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/NlBV9E9PBpg?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16310/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 19:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16310</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government has made it clear that its main purpose is not to save lives or protect the vulnerable. It exists to ensure that assets never depreciate and that wealth is never redistributed downward. Capital has never seemed so fictitious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://rhizome.org/editorial/2020/apr/22/notes-from-quar-daniel-keller/&#34;&gt;https://rhizome.org/editorial/2020/apr/22/notes-from-quar-daniel-keller/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16145/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 10:30:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16145</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some friends of ours have started a coworking space in Berlin hat includes childcare. The space looks great and I think that flexible solutions like this could alleviate a lot of the burden on parents right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://littlevillage.berlin/&#34;&gt;https://littlevillage.berlin/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16104/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 19:00:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16104</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was saddened by reading that Iepe, a Dutch fixture here in Berlin, had passed away suddenly and far too young.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rtlnieuws.nl/columns/column/5125346/iepe-rubingh-overleden-berlijn-column-jeroen-akkermans&#34;&gt;https://www.rtlnieuws.nl/columns/column/5125346/iepe-rubingh-overleden-berlijn-column-jeroen-akkermans&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15896/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 08:34:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15896</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;German publications fail cyclists in all of the ways described here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bicycling.com/news/a29993123/failing-cyclists-with-words/&#34;&gt;https://www.bicycling.com/news/a29993123/failing-cyclists-with-words/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15873/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 11:31:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15873</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bunch of incredibly grim stories of people whose lives were destroyed in the DDR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/nov/06/ive-been-shafted-twice-stasi-victims-and-their-quest-for-compensation?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/nov/06/ive-been-shafted-twice-stasi-victims-and-their-quest-for-compensation?CMP=Share_iOSApp_Other&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15843/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:33:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15843</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;English language critique of Turkish rap produced in my backyard here in Berlin. That&amp;rsquo;s the way I like it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kenan&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/kenan&lt;/a&gt;_sharpe/status/1195723219430342657&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15839/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 12:05:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15839</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a part of the Berlin Dad&amp;rsquo;s Slack for a while now which is proving to be an essential resource for dads who want to live a balanced life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would very much suggest you join if you&amp;rsquo;re a dad as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://papiberlin.de/pages/slack&#34;&gt;https://papiberlin.de/pages/slack&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My easily incensed people</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/my-easily-incensed-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 13:52:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/2019/11/my-easily-incensed-people/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Turkish guy in a van turns the corner tight enough to almost run us over. He then stops and pulls down the window: &amp;ldquo;Möchtest du mir etwas sagen?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To which I better don&amp;rsquo;t reply: &amp;ldquo;Ja, &amp;lsquo;senin ananı babanı sikeyim.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These guys are so easily triggered. Once I did say this and the dude followed me through half of Schöneberg in his car.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15821/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 09:36:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15821</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Always nice to read a positive career history from somebody, like this one by Alicia Hickey, but especially nice if you&amp;rsquo;re in it named as the team lead who made a crucial suggestion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@lonelypeanut/finding-out-what-sticks-1f124bda0c19&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/@lonelypeanut/finding-out-what-sticks-1f124bda0c19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15816/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2019 09:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15816</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember some very early conversations about the Basslet (now Lofelt) and its creative possibilities. Building their own design tools for this medium is a key move and I look forward to trying it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lofelt.com/blog/lofelt-composer-designing-audio-haptic-experiences-for-ios&#34;&gt;https://lofelt.com/blog/lofelt-composer-designing-audio-haptic-experiences-for-ios&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15775/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2019 19:46:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15775</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wir üben keinen Druck auf unsere Mieter aus. Kein Mieter wird bei uns verdrängt. Das würde gegen unsere Werte verstoßen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A quote by Ralf Spann the boss of Akelius, a private housing corporation in Berlin, who are known to intentionally shut down hot water and other amenities to get people to vacate their apartments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Akelius is one of the corporations that is on the chopping block to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dwenteignen.de/&#34;&gt;expropriated&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://taz.de/Mietendeckel-in-Berlin/!5628554/&#34;&gt;https://taz.de/Mietendeckel-in-Berlin/!5628554/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15688/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 21:54:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15688</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin is finally thinking of fixing its totally and utterly broken website. That&amp;rsquo;s good news but a shame that we have had to use this monstrosity for the past ten years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/kommunales-klickmonster-senat-verhandelt-ueber-zukunft-von-berlin-de/24940368.html&#34;&gt;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/kommunales-klickmonster-senat-verhandelt-ueber-zukunft-von-berlin-de/24940368.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15664/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:54:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15664</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This lament on SF does not sound that far off from where Berlin is. The city is a lot bigger and less boring, but without measures, it could go the same way when it comes to property prices and hollowing out of public services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/jul/01/san-francisco-big-tech-workers-industry&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/cities/2019/jul/01/san-francisco-big-tech-workers-industry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15659/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:24:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15659</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were represented at PM Camp last week and here&amp;rsquo;s a blog post (in German) by Alicia, one of my team members about the way we work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://berlin.pm-camp.org/2019/08/22/der-wind-in-unseren-segeln/&#34;&gt;https://berlin.pm-camp.org/2019/08/22/der-wind-in-unseren-segeln/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15655/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 19:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15655</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin is instituting a rent cap which honestly is the only way the city will remain liveable for the majority of its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.morgenpost.de/berlin/article226873469/Mietendeckel-in-Berlin-Mueller-distanziert-sich-von-Bausenatorin-Lompscher.html&#34;&gt;https://www.morgenpost.de/berlin/article226873469/Mietendeckel-in-Berlin-Mueller-distanziert-sich-von-Bausenatorin-Lompscher.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Answer GKV Spitzenverband</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/answer-gkv-spitzenverband/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2019 12:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Mr. Alper Cugun,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your request.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A good coverage with medical services and an adequate access for all population groups belong to the central intentions of Health Policy. The question how many doctors will be needed for a suitable supply of the people and how an adequate distribution of doctors can be reached is as nearly as old as the statutory health insurance itself. The GKV-Spitzenverband is a member of the &amp;ldquo;Gemeinsamer Bundesausschuss (G-BA)&amp;rdquo;, a committee that decides on legal norms on a federal level, including the &amp;ldquo;Bedarfsplanungs-Richtlinie&amp;rdquo;. That is the fundamental basis of the planning policy for outpatient doctors in the regions. Actually, the G-BA decided to change some of the norms and to increase the number of paediatricians by approximately 400.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15627/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 21:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15627</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I offer this: literature can save a life. Just one life at a time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teju Cole is a treasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2019/07/05/carrying-a-single-life-on-literature-translation/&#34;&gt;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2019/07/05/carrying-a-single-life-on-literature-translation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15612/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 11:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15612</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First I hear about &lt;em&gt;Mauerkrankheit&lt;/em&gt;—and I&amp;rsquo;m not the only one—but a politically triggered rise in mental health problems would explain many things both past and present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2019/jul/31/philip-pocock-best-photograph-miriam-berlin-punk-and-her-rat-bestia&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2019/jul/31/philip-pocock-best-photograph-miriam-berlin-punk-and-her-rat-bestia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15598/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Aug 2019 22:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15598</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin right now is the frontline for transportation applications with 4 scooter services alone. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that Jon has made a comprehensive overview of multi-modal transportation apps because I sure as hell wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to have the time for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jonworth.eu/the-definitive-guide-to-berlin-multi-mode-mobility-apps/&#34;&gt;https://jonworth.eu/the-definitive-guide-to-berlin-multi-mode-mobility-apps/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15577/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 12:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15577</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cath writes some very salient points about growing into leadership that on the one hand should be more widespread, but on the other hand, everybody will likely have to find out for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also nice to see this local group of people taking the next steps in their careers if even only witnessed from afar like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@ohrworm/what-ive-learnt-about-leadership-3ff83b06a1de&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/@ohrworm/what-ive-learnt-about-leadership-3ff83b06a1de&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15572/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 19:33:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15572</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My foray into local politics showed me that more than anything the Grüne are a party of yuppies without much or any social face behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/jun/24/german-greens-rise-nation-divided&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/commentisfree/2019/jun/24/german-greens-rise-nation-divided&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Figuring out why there is a shortage of pediatricians</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/finding-a-pediatrician-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 11:34:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15529</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just like almost every public service in Berlin the pediatrician situation is absolute squalor. It&amp;rsquo;s impossible to find one who picks up the phone or takes on new patients ((Don&amp;rsquo;t bother tipping me a pediatrician unless you&amp;rsquo;re sure they take new patients.)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve had some bad incidents in the past with sketchy doctors because of this and now I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out why this is the way it is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15522/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 20:48:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15522</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading about Amsterdam canceling 10&#39;000 parking spaces, does make me feel as if I&amp;rsquo;m living in an idiot&amp;rsquo;s city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/06/amsterdam-parking-spots-removal-cars-bikes-parks-playground/591067/&#34;&gt;https://www.citylab.com/transportation/2019/06/amsterdam-parking-spots-removal-cars-bikes-parks-playground/591067/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Living without a car in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/living-without-a-car-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 21:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15480</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/berlin/comments/bv66jt/senatorin_will_zwangsbvgticket_f%C3%BCr_autofahrer/epnd77d/&#34;&gt;From a thread&lt;/a&gt; about whether it is possible or not to live in Berlin without a car (gasp!). This is what a normal odd day of mine looks like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The car isn&amp;rsquo;t the problem or more like: having a car would be a problem. During those rush hours, doing the same journeys by car would take at least twice as long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;07:00 aufstehen, Kinder anziehen, KiTa brot machen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;07:45 Lastenrad holen, noch was anziehen usw., Kinder überzeugen einzusteigen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;08:10 Abfahrt zum Kita (andere Seite von Kreuzberg, 2.8km)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;08:25 Kita Ankunft&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;08:40 Idealfall Abfahrt Kita zur Arbeit (Schöneberg, 7.7km)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;09:10 Sitze auf dem Arbeitsplatz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16:30 Abfahrt Arbeit (weil ich sie gebracht habe muss ich sie jetzt nicht abholen, kann auch 16:00 sein oder 17:00)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;16:45 Biomarkt wenn wir noch einkaufen brauchen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;17:10 Abfahrt Biomarkt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;17:25 spätestens wieder zu Hause&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Den nächsten Tag tue ich das gleiche andersrum mit dem Zwilingsrad und hole die um 15:30 ab beim Kita. Ich fahre ungefähr 15km Rad pro Tag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15468/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 22:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15468</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had no idea but it seems Berlin has a booming Chinese art scene.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2019/05/why-chinas-expat-artists-move-berlin/589951/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share&#34;&gt;https://www.theatlantic.com/international/archive/2019/05/why-chinas-expat-artists-move-berlin/589951/?utm_source=twitter&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_campaign=share&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15437/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 12:15:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15437</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin will also regularly call on McKinsey to ‘fix’ its problems. As this description of them giving Puerto Rico the Greece-treatment shows, where they come nothing good will follow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2019/04/mckinsey-in-puerto-rico.html&#34;&gt;http://nymag.com/intelligencer/2019/04/mckinsey-in-puerto-rico.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15388/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 22:53:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15388</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A paean for canteens something of which Berlin has ample for a variety of historic reasons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dinnerdocument.com/2019/04/30/i-dream-of-canteens/&#34;&gt;https://dinnerdocument.com/2019/04/30/i-dream-of-canteens/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15325/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 21:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15325</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to the Micromobility Summit coming to Berlin this year. I hope we manage to have some serious progress on infrastructure and street legal scooters by then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://tickets.micromobility.io/&#34;&gt;http://tickets.micromobility.io/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15321/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 21:50:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15321</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Barcelona is implementing a traffic transition we here in Berlin can only dream of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/4/11/18273896/barcelona-spain-politics-superblocks&#34;&gt;https://www.vox.com/energy-and-environment/2019/4/11/18273896/barcelona-spain-politics-superblocks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15317/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 21:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15317</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin opens its first mobility hub and makes it look about as shabby as the average parking lot in Kreuzberg (which is what it is).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/abschied-vom-auto-erster-mobilitaets-hub-in-berlin-eroeffnet/24212946.html&#34;&gt;https://www.tagesspiegel.de/berlin/abschied-vom-auto-erster-mobilitaets-hub-in-berlin-eroeffnet/24212946.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15313/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 21:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15313</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If Berlin votes to expropriate Deutsche Wohnen, it will be a welcome step towards decommodification of housing. Not to mention the long overdue correction that it will give the local housing market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.taz.de/!5587292/&#34;&gt;http://www.taz.de/!5587292/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15300/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2019 22:11:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15300</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be proud to live in Berlin when the home owner expropriations are passed and the real estate madness is curtailed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Article 15 of the Country’s Basic Law states that “land, natural resources and means of production may, for the purpose of nationalization, be transferred to public ownership or other forms of public enterprise by a law that determines the nature and extent of compensation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thenation.com/article/berlin-housing-gentrification-referendum/&#34;&gt;https://www.thenation.com/article/berlin-housing-gentrification-referendum/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Late arrival to VerrÃ¼cktes Blut</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/late-arrival-to-verrucktes-blut/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 23:25:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15270</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was supposed to see &lt;a href=&#34;https://gorki.de/index.php/de/verruecktes-blut&#34;&gt;this play&lt;/a&gt; six years ago. Let&amp;rsquo;s say better late than never. Seen Wednesday, March 20th at the Maxim Gorki Theater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It starts off very chaotically with everybody shouting. It is very hard to understand what anybody says. This gets better later on but I still had to peek at the surtitles regularly. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ve been spoiled by Dutch theaters where they strap microphones to their actors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scooters in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/scooters-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 22:22:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15255</guid> 
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;JPEG-image-33A58FAF2AC2-1-1.jpeg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scooters are not legal in Germany yet but in select locations like here in Berlin you can try them out on private land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was my first ride and they are an immense pleasure to use once you get your feet positioned properly. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure yet what happens if you fall off one but I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure it will be bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law allowing these on the road has supposedly been signed but still has to work its way through some German institutions. What will happen when these are legal is obvious:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15219/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 22:40:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15219</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A well written defense by Markthalle IX in Berlin that sounds good but still paints a much more rosy picture of reality than is justified. Let&amp;rsquo;s be totally clear: removing the ALDI will advance the area&amp;rsquo;s socio-economic cleansing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://markthalleneun.de/news/ein-brief-an-alle-nachbarn-kunden-und-gaeste-der-m&#34;&gt;https://markthalleneun.de/news/ein-brief-an-alle-nachbarn-kunden-und-gaeste-der-m&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15183/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 21:52:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15183</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very necessary housing revolution is underway in Berlin that has the potential to halt market forces that are running amok. After Barcelona, now Berlin. Who&amp;rsquo;s next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.citylab.com/equity/2019/02/berlin-germany-housing-rent-how-much-price-landlord-policies/582898/&#34;&gt;https://www.citylab.com/equity/2019/02/berlin-germany-housing-rent-how-much-price-landlord-policies/582898/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Parklets BergmannstraÃŸe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/parklets-bergmannstrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 May 2018 18:17:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6007</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got around to visiting the Parklets in the Bergmannstraße. That is a plural because there are two of them during this pilot and that’s it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/41360827625/in/dateposted-public/&#34; title=&#34;Parklet Bergmannstrasse&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Parklet Bergmannstrasse&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/969/41360827625_73f763512b_c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as quality and usage goes I don’t think there is anything to complain about. The benches look and feel nice and they are being used by the tons of people passing through this street. It is nice to have some extra seating here that is non-commercial.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UIKonf Unconference: Gradual Coordinators</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/uikonf-unconference-gradual-coordinators/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 May 2018 07:05:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5997</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I dropped by the UIKonf unconference yesterday and gave a quick code/architecture talk. Normally I do mostly design/strategy type talks which are a lot more handwavy, so this felt a bit out of my water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides actual code I threw in some talk about impostor syndrome, the value of cleaning and maintenance, gradualism as defined by parkour and Christopher Alexander&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Pattern_Language&#34;&gt;“A Pattern Language”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there is a lot of value in getting more different perspectives into the standard programming talk. I have seen enough engineering talks by now and many of them suffer from a lack of diversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UX and Messaging of Chatbots</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-ux-and-messaging-of-chatbots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 16:05:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5806</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One for the archives, this a talk I gave last summer that I thought went pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/xOPl9c9PGxM?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A possible agenda for a tech workers solidarity movement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-possible-agenda-for-a-tech-workers-solidarity-movement/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2017 10:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5746</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The USA example of resistance against Trump in the form of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TechSolidarity&#34;&gt;Tech Solidarity&lt;/a&gt; quickly gained a following in the Netherlands with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techsolidarity.nl/&#34;&gt;TechSolidarity.nl&lt;/a&gt; and here in Berlin with some &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/Tech-Solidarity-Berlin/&#34;&gt;Tech-Solidarity-Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a small role in both of those groups&amp;rsquo; creation but I&amp;rsquo;m currently not an active participant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech Solidarity&amp;rsquo;s success is of course unique to the local environment and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Pinboard&#34;&gt;Pinboard&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; prior activism in tech. That said there are a lot of similarities that make similar movements over here possible and necessary. The Netherlands and Germany have elections this year and are faced with similar populist disruptions. The technology industries here are also very heavily dependent on expat workers who have specific issues and interests. The time seems ripe for people in technology to organize themselves.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welt am Draht</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/welt-am-draht/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 08:41:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5587</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I strolled through the massive exhibition ‘Welt am Draht’ at Leipziger Strasse this weekend. This is a selection of video art from the massive &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.julia-stoschek-collection.net/&#34;&gt;Julia Stoschek Collection&lt;/a&gt; exhibited in the former Czech Cultural center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like everybody says the quality of video art in general is extremely inconsistent. That is true in this exhibit as well. There are a bunch of works where it is not at all obvious why somebody finished it, somebody approved it and somebody paid money for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why KÃ¤the Kollwitz is one of Germany&#39;s most important figurative artists</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kathe-kollwitz-museum-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 16:58:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5567</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I got a tour of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kaethe-kollwitz.de/&#34;&gt;Käthe Kollwitz museum&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin. I had wanted to visit this museum for a while but this proved the concrete reason to finally go (though &lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/caf%C3%A9-restaurant-wintergarten/4adcda78f964a5205c4621e3&#34;&gt;the café next door&lt;/a&gt; makes some mean pancakes if you find yourself in the area).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was recently attended to her existence by MacGregor&amp;rsquo;s series on German history ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b04k6t0s&#34;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt;). I now believe that she is one of the most important German artists of the past couple of centuries. If there are any other significant candidates, I would like to hear about them ((I discount Caspar David Friedrich because he was a painter of landscapes.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>That spread in Elsevier</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/that-spread-in-elsevier/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 07:35:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I shared it elsewhere but to briefly clip it here as well. I took a bunch more pictures with the photographer that were a lot of fun but of course this is the one they chose.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/25944532150/in/dateposted-public/&#34; title=&#34;Spread with me in Elsevier&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Spread with me in Elsevier&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm2.staticflickr.com/1551/25944532150_2b6ca8e0cb_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sleep by Max Richter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sleep-by-max-richter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 07:33:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5513</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/rknLA&#34;&gt;Kevin&lt;/a&gt; posted yesterday that he had an extra ticket for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berlinerfestspiele.de/de/aktuell/festivals/maerzmusik/mm16_programm/mm16_programm_sleep/mm16_Veranstaltungsdetail_sleep_150936.php&#34;&gt;Max Richter&amp;rsquo;s Sleep&lt;/a&gt; at Kraftwerk Berlin yesterday. Without a moment&amp;rsquo;s hesitation I packed my sleeping bag and cycled there with him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kraftwerk Mitte is a disused power plant in the middle (Mitte) of the city that is now a club venue and host to a variety of events. The most striking features of it are large open spaces and lots of exposed concrete everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New beginnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/new-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2016 22:01:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5465</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2015 personal and professional changes made it clear to us that we would &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/2016/01/engaging-sleep-mode/&#34;&gt;not continue Hubbub in its current form&lt;/a&gt;. That realization made me reorient myself in Berlin and refocus on my core skills as an engineer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set myself the goal to work on a significant product as part of a larger team. I thought it would be useful to change up my professional life which thusfar had consisted only of freelance and client work. A long story short, as of this week I&amp;rsquo;m employed as a software engineer at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.researchgate.net/&#34;&gt;ResearchGate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mann/Frau</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mann-frau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 08:29:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5368</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The idea that German television is necessarily terrible has to be reconsidered. I&amp;rsquo;ve recently started watching &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deutschland_83&#34;&gt;Deutschland &amp;lsquo;83&lt;/a&gt; which is amazing (more on that later) and yesterday I finished season two of the web series Mann/Frau by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.br.de/puls/index.html&#34;&gt;BR PULS&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.br.de/mannfrau/&#34;&gt;Mann/Frau&lt;/a&gt; is a mirror format byte-sized episodic where each installment details the interactions of a man and a woman their relations and lives. It treats most of the themes occupying people around my age living in Berlin but manages to do so drawing more from slapstick than from cliché.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Les Contes d&#39;Hoffmann</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/les-contes-dhoffmann/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 16:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5336</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.komische-oper-berlin.de/spielplan/les-contes-d-hoffmann/&#34;&gt;“Les Contes d&amp;rsquo;Hoffmann”&lt;/a&gt; yesterday in one of Berlin&amp;rsquo;s three operas thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theguardian.com/music/2015/oct/08/berlin-opera-weekend-staatsoper-komische-oper-deutsche-oper&#34;&gt;this piece in the Guardian&lt;/a&gt;. Yes, I have to rely on a British paper for reliable cultural advice about Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Komische Oper is a ten minute bike ride from my house and you can get a discounted ticket with some mild visual obstruction for €18. This makes it a fairly ideal way to spend a Sunday in Berlin which otherwise can be fairly quiet (stores aren&amp;rsquo;t open, most places close at five or six).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The redesign of Moritzplatz roundabout</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-redesign-of-moritzplatz-roundabout/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 09:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5237</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is turning into a traffic blog more than anything else. After taking stock of &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2015/05/encounter-zone-maasenstrase/&#34;&gt;the plans for the new Maaßenstraße&lt;/a&gt; which is very slowly nearing completion, now let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at another place close to my heart: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/maps?q=moritzplatz%2C%20berlin&#34;&gt;Moritzplatz&lt;/a&gt;. The square is right underneath my office and as such I cross it several times daily both on foot and by bike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/19875484324/in/dateposted-public/&#34; title=&#34;Cyclist get hits on Moritzplatz&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cyclist get hits on Moritzplatz&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm1.staticflickr.com/489/19875484324_d2634140ea_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; A couple of weeks ago week an accident took place there where a cyclist was touched by a car. No big deal in his case, but it could have been worse considering the way motorists behave here. I have to pay close attention every time I cross this roundabout otherwise this could happen to me as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Encounter Zone MaaÃŸenstraÃŸe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/encounter-zone-maasenstrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 May 2015 13:18:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5215</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin is rebuilding the Maaßenstraße into the first Begegnungszone (‘Encounter Zone’) of its kind in the city. Works are underway now after &lt;a href=&#34;https://begegnungszonen.berlin.de/&#34;&gt;a public consultation&lt;/a&gt; was finished last year or the year before. I looked around a bit but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find the plans for what they are actually building there. A quick e-mail to the senate solved that problem and I got &lt;a href=&#34;06-Flyer_Begegnungszone_maassenstr.pdf&#34;&gt;a PDF of the plan&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/17361704548&#34; title=&#34;Redesigning Maaßenstraße by Alper Çuğun, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Redesigning Maaßenstraße&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5445/17361704548_cb4465b6a7_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Session of the traffic commission of the Berlin borough of NeukÃ¶lln</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/session-of-the-traffic-commission-of-the-berlin-borough-of-neukolln/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Mar 2015 00:24:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5167</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/16579780102&#34; title=&#34;Neukölln committee for traffic meeting by Alper Çuğun, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Neukölln committee for traffic meeting&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7349/16579780102_6f86aa18a1_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I heard about the session of the traffic commission of Berlin-Neukölln through the great &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/urbanist_mag&#34;&gt;Urbanist Magazine&lt;/a&gt; who wrote that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbanist-magazin.de/2015/02/jede-stadt-hat-die-radwege/?utm_content=buffer3f5b2&amp;amp;utm_medium=social&amp;amp;utm_source=twitter.com&amp;amp;utm_campaign=buffer&#34;&gt;cities get the bike paths they deserve&lt;/a&gt; and that being present at political sessions is a prerequisite to change things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I made my way over to Rathaus Neukölln during rush hour yesterday to listen in on the session. Even though these things are deadly boring, they are at the same time extremely revealing of the workings and attitudes of our governments and just for that fact worthwhile to occasionally visit. At the same time I think it is a civic duty to attend these sessions for the things that you are interested in. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, others will.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DOTA night at Meltdown Esports Bar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dota-night-at-meltdown-esports-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2015 17:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5164</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/16544389286&#34; title=&#34;Dota night at Meltdown by Alper Çuğun, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dota night at Meltdown&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7332/16544389286_480c94066a_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I attended the weekly &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dota2.com/&#34;&gt;Dota2&lt;/a&gt; night at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meltdown.bar/berlin&#34;&gt;Meltdown esports bar&lt;/a&gt; for the first time. I&amp;rsquo;m looking for people who I can play with regularly because going out into solo queue is becoming a bit tedious and unpredictable. There is a small crowd of people there who play 5v5&amp;rsquo;s in a private lobby against the Meltdown London cafe. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot of shouting and mostly fun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berlin real estate development Victoriapark edition</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/berlin-real-estate-development-victoriapark-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 12:27:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4988</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Sunday the Senate&amp;rsquo;s plan to build on Tempelhof was voted off thankfully. Not just to preserve the field which is a one-of-a-kind but to signal to the city that their way of managing construction and housing is not the right way ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spreeblick.com/2014/05/26/als-ginge-es-nur-um-das-tempelhofer-feld/&#34;&gt;a full treatment in German&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then yesterday I went for a run in the nearby &lt;a href=&#34;https://goo.gl/maps/g0Evt&#34;&gt;Viktoriapark&lt;/a&gt;. Out of necessity because I was trying out a running track which turned out to be closed to the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tempelhofer Park and the union between local government and property developers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tempelhofer-park-and-the-union-between-local-government-and-property-developers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2014 07:59:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4965</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a shack on Tempelhofer Feld that explains the senate&amp;rsquo;s plans with the park and the construction they plan to do there:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/13400451765&#34; title=&#34;One sided citizen participation because that is how this city rolls by Alper Çuğun, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;One sided citizen participation because that is how this city rolls&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7242/13400451765_6d1d1654b8.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/thf100&#34;&gt;100% Tempelhofer Feld&lt;/a&gt; with an alternate view are not allowed to express their view on the park itself. Reading through their facebook feed for the past weeks is a collection of absurdism that beggars belief. Truth is stranger than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Union issue</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-union-issue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 07:40:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4955</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been long flummoxed by how terrible the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CDU/CSU&#34;&gt;CDU/CSU&lt;/a&gt; complex in Germany is. I could not understand how people could be that stupid and that conservative to the detriment of everybody including themselves. The number of examples is near infinite, but this post was prompted by yesterday&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://juberlin.de/2014/04/08/raeumung-des-oranienplatzes-danke-frank/&#34;&gt;action by the young Union Berlin&lt;/a&gt; ((Who will never ever demonstrate except at the opportune moment where they can celebrate the state&amp;rsquo;s boot crushing down on the poor and the oppressed. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vice.com/de/vice-news/berlin-oranienplatz-refugee-camp-raeumung&#34;&gt;this VICE report&lt;/a&gt; to see how incredibly fucked that situation is.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the panther</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/unleash-the-panther/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 10:07:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4879</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday evening I was in the Volksbühne for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.we-are-stargaze.com/&#34;&gt;Stargaze&lt;/a&gt; among others to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cantusdomus.de/&#34;&gt;Cantus Domus&lt;/a&gt; perform a set with an odd German band called 1000 Robota. After that there was an intermission and the main performance of the evening by Pantha du Prince and The Bell Laboratory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/12585602454/&#34; title=&#34;Pantha du Prince &amp;amp; The Bell Laboratory by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Pantha du Prince &amp;amp; The Bell Laboratory&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7335/12585602454_c27340d1cc_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The artistic mandate of the evening bordered a bit on the odd. &lt;a href=&#34;http://1000robota.com/&#34;&gt;1000 Robota&lt;/a&gt; is more or less a lunatic act part of the melodramatic German singer-songwriter movement. Pantha du Prince &amp;amp; The Bell Laboratory were forced to interpret &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Terry_Riley&#34;&gt;Terry Riley&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; in C as part of the program. Of course they said it was a great inspiration to them and they did quite a good job of it. After the official part of the program they started making some real music and the entire Volksbühne got to its feet ((I had a similar experience in the same venue where &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/05/war-and-peace-under-the-shadow-of-the-apparat/&#34;&gt;a performance by Apparat was mired by a boring play&lt;/a&gt; about Russian nobility.)). I asked myself: ‘What the fuck were we doing up until this point?’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Germany still isn&#39;t really a democracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/4806/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 16:34:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4806</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I tried to register to vote for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berliner-energietisch.net/&#34;&gt;the buyback of the Berlin energy grid&lt;/a&gt; and then I got this letter back informing me that I cannot vote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/10482559644/&#34; title=&#34;IMG_0001 by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IMG_0001&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2850/10482559644_520dc08bcb_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already knew that I cannot vote for national German elections and I don&amp;rsquo;t care much for them anyway. That I can&amp;rsquo;t vote at the local level where I live and where I am taxed is however somewhat annoying. Especially given the number of new entrants to the city, the fact that none of them receive any representation for their taxation is a outrageous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 335</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-335/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 09:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4782</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A funny week and with these weeknotes falling ever further behind it is also becoming increasingly vague what ever did happen back then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something I didn&amp;rsquo;t publish back then but I might as well now is [this horrible ancient picture](&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.netzpiloten.de/barcamp-berlin-blogger-interviewen-blogger/&#34;&gt;http://www.netzpiloten.de/barcamp-berlin-blogger-interviewen-blogger/&lt;/a&gt; work) that Peter dug up of me from a long ago visit to Berlin. That was in a certain year during the first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.web2expo.com/webexberlin2008/&#34;&gt;Web 2.0 Expo&lt;/a&gt; that was held in Berlin by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly. We made it out here with a Dutch group and attended the event along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://barcampberlin3.mixxt.org/&#34;&gt;Barcamp Berlin&lt;/a&gt; and lots of parties. Fun times in a Berlin that was very different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Symphonie CinÃ©tique</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/symphonie-cinetique/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2013 07:29:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4769</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight I saw the magical &lt;a href=&#34;http://made-blog.com/2013/09/symphonie-cinetique-the-pieces/&#34;&gt;Symphonie Cinétique works at MADE in Berlin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iepe.net/&#34;&gt;Iepe Rubingh&lt;/a&gt; who I to my shame only met last night told me about these beautiful works of art by Joachim Sauter (and music by Ólafur Arnalds) and this being the last chance to see them. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I have really seen a music and installation piece before where both parts combine this well. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.julioleparc.org/&#34;&gt;Julio Le Parc&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; kinetic &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.palaisdetokyo.com/fr/expositions/archives-expositions&#34;&gt;work in the Palais de Tokyo&lt;/a&gt; is comparable, but this is better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Voting advice for the German elections</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/voting-advice-for-the-german-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 20:50:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4745</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I will be gone during the peak of the horrible German election campaigns (in fact I&amp;rsquo;m just back and voting is this Sunday). The only thing that is keeping things somewhat bearable are the low-budget fake news broadcasts by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCIvthGRDv___2gL2JGiDryQ&#34;&gt;Tagesschaum&lt;/a&gt;. I pay taxes in this damned country but I am not eligible to vote. That&amp;rsquo;s why I penned this election advice before I left for those that are. I didn&amp;rsquo;t have time to polish it then but here it is, better late than never.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 334</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-334/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 05:04:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4751</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this from Japan after seeing I have fallen seriously off the blogging horse. I think this particular week I was a bit under the weather but I did manage to get out a minimal prototype for AJI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9470037243/&#34; title=&#34;Sashimi by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Sashimi&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3802/9470037243_0d490e775d_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the week of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.somewherehq.com/&#34;&gt;the Somewhere cocktails event&lt;/a&gt; here a lot of friends were present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9472827176/&#34; title=&#34;Somewhere Team by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Somewhere Team&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7282/9472827176_e07516fb12_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Co-up had their summer barbecue which was a fun grill and beer on the street.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 333</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-333/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2013 13:23:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4724</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week was a bit more stationary than the last thankfully. I tried out a competitor to &lt;a href=&#34;http://cuppin.gs&#34;&gt;Cuppings&lt;/a&gt; called Bean Seeker which is a rather terrible app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That night I attended the IoT Berlin meetup organized by Martin and had dinner with a rather interesting set of people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9398441551/&#34; title=&#34;IoT Berlin Meetup by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;IoT Berlin Meetup&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3669/9398441551_eab3b9e44a_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9398444077/&#34; title=&#34;Dinner by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dinner&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7334/9398444077_cf4702e3c1_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also started playing &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.dota2.com/&#34;&gt;DOTA2&lt;/a&gt; this week for which there is a working Mac client available and which is a deep but somewhat too hardcore experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 332</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-332/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 07:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4719</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, this week. This week was how to put it rather intense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got visits again from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruk&#34;&gt;Peter Rukavina&lt;/a&gt; and this time &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mygdal&#34;&gt;Thomas&lt;/a&gt; dropped in as well to make it a proper Reboot reunion. I decided to join Peter (Bihr) to go to London in October to attend Playful and Mozilla Festival and potentially &lt;a href=&#34;http://gamecity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Gamecity&lt;/a&gt; too which is supposed to be an awesome conference in Nottingham. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been outside of London so that alone may be worth the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Declaration for a Better Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-declaration-for-a-better-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2013 14:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4726</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Right now in Berlin we are being bombarded with the election campaign but I do not know anybody who looks forward to voting come September. I cannot vote but if I were allowed I would also face a tough choice. None of the options are appealing and what we will get seems so certain and terrible that potential alternatives pale. Germany being as it is the election focuses on the heartland and there isn&amp;rsquo;t that much being discussed that people living in a city can relate to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 331</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-331/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2013 07:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4713</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With KANT we were still figuring out mostly what it is we are doing and seeing as we are neither a collective or a coworking space it was up in the air a bit. I &lt;a href=&#34;http://kantberlin.com/offering&#34;&gt;wrote up our offering&lt;/a&gt; in a more straight-forward and streamlined way where you can very easily find what it is you may be looking for. In other news we are discussing next steps for KANT in the future but anything on that order is off for at least 6-12 months.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 329</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-329/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 08:28:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4698</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most of the time this week was spent doing heads down work ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/category/weeknotes/&#34;&gt;notes on which elsewhere&lt;/a&gt;). Meeting with &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/zeigor&#34;&gt;Igor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TijmenR&#34;&gt;Tijmen&lt;/a&gt; and hanging out in parks. Summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9184055367/&#34; title=&#34;Dessert by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dessert&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7313/9184055367_27bd905bd3_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That week I went to the Liepnitzsee for a swim. The key to surviving the summer in Berlin is to get out of the city and usually coincide that wit a trip to one of the many many lakes. Most of these are just bedding of the Havel/Spree/Oder passing through so they are not very deep or cool, but the Liepnitzsee is an exception and may be one of the best distance/quality lakes in the area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 327: car-freeness, banging Q&amp;A, the fabled Autobahn and the administrative organization of infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-327-car-freeness-banging-qa-the-fabled-autobahn-and-the-administrative-organization-of-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 16:03:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4687</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was the week that Kars returned from his honeymoon on Bali. And all for the better as well, because I had worked through most of our stack —we didn&amp;rsquo;t have any running projects at the time— and I was getting so annoyed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/&#34;&gt;Dopplr&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; performance that I was about to write a clean implementation of its trip model to store my upcoming travels in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9076313037/&#34; title=&#34;Autofreies Kreuzberg über die Manteuffelstrasse by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Autofreies Kreuzberg über die Manteuffelstrasse&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7310/9076313037_4ec87e899b_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 326</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-326/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2013 15:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4683</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As my work based weeknotes are being catered for rather nicely both at &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/&#34;&gt;Hubbub&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://kantberlin.com/&#34;&gt;KANT&lt;/a&gt;, I&amp;rsquo;m going to keep writing weeknotes here, but instead of making an overview of the week&amp;rsquo;s work, I&amp;rsquo;ll do some more long form reflecting on stuff that happened. A bit more casual and personal than we are used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9004988190/&#34; title=&#34;This ridge intentionally placed to fuck with cyclists. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;This ridge intentionally placed to fuck with cyclists.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7406/9004988190_23dc395639_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autofreies Kreuzberg: ManteuffelstraÃŸe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/autofreies-kreuzberg-manteuffelstrase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 20:52:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4669</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today I went to the meeting of &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/autofrei&#34;&gt;Autofreies Kreuzberg&lt;/a&gt; about the traffic calming of the Manteuffelstraße between Skalitzer and Naunynstraße.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not an inhabitant of the area, but I like to sit at &lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/g%C3%B6rlitzer-bahnhof/4d5105e74015b1f725f96bcf&#34;&gt;Görlitzer Bahnhof cafe&lt;/a&gt; quite regularly and the car and traffic situation in that street is pretty bad.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found out recently that there is an initiative underway to close that street off for traffic which would solve the problem of passing traffic going to Köpenicker Straße passing through and also the double parked cars that are endemic in Kreuzberg ((It is a mystery to me why the Ordnungsamt does not do anything about this.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting building permits in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/getting-building-permits-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2013 13:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4660</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an absurd amount of construction being done in my neighborhood and I presumed that as a resident somewhere you would be entitled to see the changes that are being planned in the area. Not to mention to be able to know the traffic blockades that result from this construction (which almost exclusively seem to black the foot/bike paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I tried to request these wholesale or in part from my local council. I could think of a bunch of interesting open data work that you could do on a current list of building permits starting with: inform the public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 323</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-323/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 08:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4629</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week started with Pentecost. Trying to get stuff done in Germany during the bank holiday flurry that is May is always a challenge. I spent more time working on Cuppings. In all likelihood this app will never make any serious money, but there are other advantages to building apps which may become apparent in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week I gave an interview to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sz.de/&#34;&gt;Süddeutsche Zeitung&lt;/a&gt; about our project &lt;a href=&#34;http://politwoops.de/&#34;&gt;Politwoops&lt;/a&gt; which turned out pretty well:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Almost hit and run</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/4575/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2013 15:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4575</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/05/4575/screen-shot-2013-05-18-at-5-33-27-pm/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Screen Shot 2013-05-18 at 5.33.27 PM&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/4575/Screen-Shot-2013-05-18-at-5.33.27-PM.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The turn above from Rosa-Luxemburg-Straße into Schönhauser Allee yesterday around 19:15 is where I almost got hit by a woman driving a black car with license plates &lt;strong&gt;LDS HS 179&lt;/strong&gt;. Shaken but not too shaken I pursued them up the street to demonstrate my discontent and to write down the plate number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should have seen that they weren&amp;rsquo;t going to stop though they usually do but this was rather unexpected during a leisurely evening ride where absolutely nothing should have gone wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving into KANT</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/moving-into-kant/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 19:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So that cat is out of the bag: I&amp;rsquo;ve taken up residency at KANT, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/kant--kreuzberg-academy-for-nerdery-and-tinkering/51238e70e4b04e6a13aaddc9&#34;&gt;Kreuzberg Academy for Nerdery and Tinkering&lt;/a&gt;. Peter who you may have read before on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thewavingcat.com/&#34;&gt;The Waving Cat&lt;/a&gt; just wrote &lt;a href=&#34;http://kantberlin.tumblr.com/post/50347362153/hello-world&#34;&gt;the inaugural post&lt;/a&gt; on our freshly pressed Tumblr (tweets are still &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kantberlin&#34;&gt;forthcoming&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8719801383/&#34; title=&#34;The new (temporary) arrangement with @fidothe working in the background by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The new (temporary) arrangement with @fidothe working in the background&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7323/8719801383_1c16dcd1c8_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m in the process of moving over, getting my things in order and doing all of my other work, but I do believe that we have struck upon a mix here that has all of the right kinds of volatile creativity with a solid dash of make.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>War and Peace under the shadow of the Apparat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/war-and-peace-under-the-shadow-of-the-apparat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2013 21:02:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4533</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve learned my lessons: I will not go to traditional German theater anymore and I will never again book a play without first checking its duration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday night I went to the Volksbühne to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.centraltheater-leipzig.de/centraltheater/programm/centraltheater/inszenierung/archiv/krieg_und_frieden/&#34;&gt;Krieg und Frieden&lt;/a&gt;, five hours of 19th century Russian war drama, by the Centraltheater Leipzig as part of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.berlinerfestspiele.de/en/aktuell/festivals/theatertreffen/tt13_programm/tt13_programm_gesamt/tt13_veranstaltungsdetail_62427.php&#34;&gt;Theatertreffen&lt;/a&gt;. I had been listening to its soundtrack by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apparat.net/&#34;&gt;Apparat&lt;/a&gt; for the past months. It used to be freely available on Soundcloud and is &lt;a href=&#34;http://open.spotify.com/album/6oXRnGZ8V9w4cpS6FWEnOp&#34;&gt;out now on Spotify&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 318</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-318/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 13:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4524</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbelievable how many weeks behind I am on these. That&amp;rsquo;s not wholly intended, but the last couple of weeks have been a bit busier than usual. This was the week of April 15th which I spent mostly in Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a full day with the team on Tuesday working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/?s=kaigara&amp;amp;searchsubmit=Search&#34;&gt;KAIGARA&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8654049797/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8118/8654049797_ebe61f6e3e_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drank very awesome coffee that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevillagecoffee.nl/&#34;&gt;Angelo had brought back&lt;/a&gt; from his road trip along the west coast of the USA:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8656916145/&#34; title=&#34;Angelo got that fresh package from the states by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Angelo got that fresh package from the states&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8113/8656916145_4181687733_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 317</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-317/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 19:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4508</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before this on Monday (almost two weeks ago), I went to a lecture by Graham Harman. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/04/graham-harman-at-the-universitat-der-kunste/&#34;&gt;Notes on that&lt;/a&gt; were blogged in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That week also involved a one-day trip to Munich to present on the work we did for a client there. More on that on the Hubbub blog in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8638417758/&#34; title=&#34;My desk optically flipped (not an Instagram filter) by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My desk optically flipped (not an Instagram filter)&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8638417758_05037692c5_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 316</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-316/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 08:01:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4494</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before this is getting a bit boring, but as soon as the current project is over I promise that adventures will resume again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German lessons continued even with one of our participants being back in the Netherlands:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8616827814/&#34; title=&#34;Language class remote by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Language class remote&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8385/8616827814_2cee632e76_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sun was enjoyed at last after the gruelling Berlin winter we had to endure:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8626945399/&#34; title=&#34;Drinking a filter coffee in the sun. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Drinking a filter coffee in the sun.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8533/8626945399_a8b1e8fa11_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graham Harman at the UniversitÃ¤t der Kunste</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/graham-harman-at-the-universitat-der-kunste/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 21:20:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4496</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday I heard &lt;a href=&#34;http://doctorzamalek2.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Graham Harman&lt;/a&gt; give &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flusser-archive.org/publications/internationalflusserlectures&#34;&gt;the International Flusser Lecture&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin. The lecture was in German and for me as a non-native speaker somewhat hard to follow, but the present Germans loved it. ‘The English dominated academia’ seems to be problematic for them ((I have been in that conundrum myself and experienced that talking in English to a traditional German audience results in a &amp;gt; 75% loss of signal and a total negation of empathy.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeks 313-4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/weeks-313-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4463</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two week notes in one because last week seems to have been too busy to write any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8552432673/&#34; title=&#34;Rushing through the snow towards Amsterdam by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Rushing through the snow towards Amsterdam&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8233/8552432673_d375951613_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 313 was spent in the Netherlands with a somewhat hectic visit. I spent a lot of time at the Hubbub studio and at the Open Coop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8557842180/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8086/8557842180_b73b4d0c07_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course the inevitable five (!) visits to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevillagecoffee.nl/&#34;&gt;the Village&lt;/a&gt; who were serving only &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coffeecollective.dk/&#34;&gt;Coffee Collective&lt;/a&gt; coffees when I was there:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 311</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-311/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2013 10:04:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4385</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week we were on something of a tear continuously shipping things (it beats continuous integration). As Kars mentioned in &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/2013/03/week-184/&#34;&gt;the Hubbub weeknotes&lt;/a&gt; I was featured in the rather shiny &lt;a href=&#34;http://thenextweb.com/magazine/&#34;&gt;TNW magazine&lt;/a&gt; about the subject of gamification. Much to my surprise this issue was filled with blabbering by Gabe Zichermann. It&amp;rsquo;s not only that we take issue with the way he approaches games, it looks like everything about the man is shameful. You can &lt;a href=&#34;http://slavin.tumblr.com/post/43893717103/futuristgerd-to-meet-these-needs-we-believe&#34;&gt;read unparalleled levels of douchebaggery over at Kevin Slavin&lt;/a&gt; and to my dismay even &lt;a href=&#34;http://gigaom.com/&#34;&gt;GigaOM&lt;/a&gt; ((I thought GigaOM was a spark of light in the cesspool of tech journalism but it turns out I was wrong.)) is complicit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recess! 4 â€” Glass</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/recess-4-glass/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 19:37:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4352</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi Niels &amp;amp; Kars,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m checking in with you guys straight from what used to be &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ibogost/status/304379141820661761&#34;&gt;Cold War Berlin&lt;/a&gt;. Berlin is still in a state of conflict, mostly because of growing pains and a lack of a coherent identity (today &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/world/2013/feb/27/berlin-wall-paintings-threatened-developers&#34;&gt;they started demolishing the last bit of that wall&lt;/a&gt; to make place for luxury apartments). An interesting example of that conflict on the streets is the civil disobedience and destruction themed game &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.indymedia.org.uk/en/2013/01/505401.html&#34;&gt;Camover&lt;/a&gt;. The idea is generally that people with balaclavas go around destroy security cameras and documenting the fact to gain points. Now as if that wasn&amp;rsquo;t controversial enough, an activist associated with it &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/padeluun/status/306063554778378241&#34;&gt;suggested to extend the game to ‘data goggles’&lt;/a&gt; and destroy those of people recording your visage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 310</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-310/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2013 15:19:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4346</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/thornet/status/303586923719557122&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/thornet/status/303586923719557122&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week was off to a smashing smart with the irregular Iron Blogger Berlin drinks. For some people it is an expensive drinking club, for me with my iron blogging resolve it is more an expensed drinking club.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8488133407/&#34; title=&#34;Bath tub by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Bath tub&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8101/8488133407_68fddb0b28.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berlin weather has been crazy last week. Also again we did tons of stuff for Hubbub, see it over there on &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/2013/02/week-183/&#34;&gt;Week 183&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at Open State we are still recruiting a managing director to take over operations and lead us up onto the next level of open government and civic innovation. If you are reading this and you are inclined towards getting things done and civic responsibility, do get in touch with us:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/alper/status/304548937942069248&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/alper/status/304548937942069248&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>V. in Ballhaus Ost</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/v-in-ballhaus-ost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2013 12:57:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4327</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I swore to myself never to go to the theater again ((Just after seeing mightysociety10 in Amsterdam.)) which took a lot of the pressure off. But yesterday I did go to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://ballhausost.de/spip.php?article512&#34;&gt;V. in Ballhaus Ost&lt;/a&gt;. The posters hanging around town piqued my interest that a group in Berlin would stage a text by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Pynchon&#34;&gt;Thomas Pynchon&lt;/a&gt;. And if anyone should break my rules, it should be me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;German reinterpretations of English works are often problematic because of the language and culture ravine that lies between. That&amp;rsquo;s no different here. I often had the feeling that the people treating it or doing it don&amp;rsquo;t really understand the text and they&amp;rsquo;re just doing something. Just reading a text by Pynchon is no mean feat, let alone creating an adaptation to the stage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 307</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-307/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2013 08:09:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4254</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday &lt;a href=&#34;http://uber.com/&#34;&gt;Uber&lt;/a&gt; had drinks here in Berlin and took a complimentary Uber there to chat with their Berlin team. The experience was extremely comfortable but given big city traffic it wasn&amp;rsquo;t very fast ((I could have done the same distance quicker by public transportation and even a well-trained runner may have beat the S Class Mercedes.)). In cities where the cab market is unreliable and corrupt I can definitely imagine the appeal of Uber. People working on transit apps should take note, this is the way it should work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grindinâ€™ at the office</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/grindin-at-the-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2013 09:28:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4277</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here in the Berlin office we grind by hand:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/02/grindin-at-the-office/grindin-alper/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Grindin Alper&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/grindin-at-the-office/Grindin-Alper.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who still thinks in Germany?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/who-still-thinks-in-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 10:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4066</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;German friends some things need to be written but don&amp;rsquo;t take them personally. If anything, as I write below, this presents a very large opportunity for who will take it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my misgivings about what passes for intellectualism in Germany both in the newspapers and in the public debate. Germans pride themselves on being a country of &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dichter_und_Denker&#34;&gt;Dichter und Denker&lt;/a&gt; (poets and thinkers) but traces of both are thin on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 303: starting everything back up again</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-303-starting-everything-back-up-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2013 07:32:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4172</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nothing much happened during the Christmas week before, so I decided to skip that note. Most of Berlin shut down into a deep hibernation normally only witnessed in student towns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8344943963/&#34; title=&#34;Goulash for my sore throat #wander by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Goulash for my sore throat #wander&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8076/8344943963_26e2921fd6.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything only got into gear again on by Thursday when I got my copy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/14739231-gun-machine&#34;&gt;Gun Machine&lt;/a&gt; (and finished it two days after) and caught up studio flows with Hubbub Utrecht. I did my work on &lt;em&gt;TORREON&lt;/em&gt; and had lunch with the vvvv guys.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mailing books within Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mailing-books-within-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 15:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4022</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3200604927/&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Amazon.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3346/3200604927_5508e9388d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I learned that the German mail service has a special rate for mailing books because if you use normal package rates, shipping books becomes prohibitively difficult for more purposes ((Something I found out when I tried to sell my library second hand. Besides the absurd amount of work, sending books away in the Netherlands amounted to taking a loss.)). So there&amp;rsquo;s a special tariff for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deutschepost.de/dpag?xmlFile=link1015117_893&#34;&gt;“Büchersendung”&lt;/a&gt; and it is incredibly cheap: €1,00 for a half kilo book or €1,65 to ship a kilogram of paper anywhere you would like within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 300: odds and ends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-300/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 11:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4061</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was a week without travel or deadlines so a lot of stuff that had been lying around for too long got done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did some more work on the small secret project ((I regret not picking a codename for it now. Henceforth it shall be known as REYNOSA.)). Also going forward with work on TORREON.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Eidhof dropped by briefly at Praxis and told me about his &lt;a href=&#34;http://iosinberlin.launchrock.com/&#34;&gt;plans to organize an iOS conference&lt;/a&gt; in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games on Ignite Berlin #3</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/games-on-ignite-berlin-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 11:41:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3965</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I &lt;a href=&#34;http://igniteberlin.com/2012/10/alper-cugun-new-games-for-new-cities/&#34;&gt;presented at the Berlin Ignite&lt;/a&gt;. I had been present at the last one and greatly enjoyed, so I looked what I could add to the mix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I threw most of the thinking in the studios for the past 1-2 years on the floor with post-its and distilled the pertinent threads from that. As it happens &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/2011/05/new-games-for-new-cities-at-futureeverything/&#34;&gt;‘New Games for New Cities’&lt;/a&gt; was the title of a presentation Kars gave some time ago to which I had contributed but had forgotten about.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berlin Inefficiences: 1/2 Cents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/berlin-inefficiences-12-cents/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 17:39:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3911</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just to start a series here about ways in which German society could be organized more sensibly ((Paraphrasing Harry Potter from the Methods of Rationality: “I don&amp;rsquo;t want to rule the universe. I just think it could be more sensibly organised.”)) ((Also I need to document this somewhere to get it out of my head.)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/paolomargari/5667162170/&#34; title=&#34;1 euro cent by Paolo Margari, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1 euro cent&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5069/5667162170_56ddf088ab.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we switched to the euro in the Netherlands I hardly ever remember seeing the one and two cent coins. I think they were there in the beginning, but popular consensus soon decided that those were too small money amounts to justify bothering with and dispensed with them. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1_cent_euro_coins#Usage&#34;&gt;They are still legal tender&lt;/a&gt; so occasionally you will be given change in those coins at some odd shop in the outback. Everybody knows though that people who do that are douchebags.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conquest of the Useless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/conquest-of-the-useless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2012 11:04:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3951</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday we went to see Werner Herzog read from his own work in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.volksbuehne-berlin.de/praxis/eroberung_des_nutzlosen/&#34;&gt;‘Erroberung des Nutzlosen’&lt;/a&gt; at the Volksbühne. While an impressive display of authorship my enjoyment of the performance was hampered by me having no knowledge of his movies and a recent aversion towards the theater.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With some heavy German, Herzog reads his diary notes from the production of Fitzcarraldo (trailer below), a massive undertaking to make a movie of a massive undertaking. The whole protracted shooting in the jungle sounds a lot like how &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apocalypse_Now#Principal_photography&#34;&gt;Apocalypse Now was made&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Selim Varol Collection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-selim-varol-collection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2012 17:05:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3943</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday I made it out to the penultimate day of the exhibition of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/www_toykio_com&#34;&gt;Selim Varol&lt;/a&gt; Collection in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.me-berlin.com/&#34;&gt;me collectors room&lt;/a&gt; here in Berlin. I&amp;rsquo;m glad I did. This was one of the most complete and stunning collections of contemporary toys and subversive art on display anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the fun is in the sheer completionism of certain walls and cabinets. Acquiring everything past the point of simple fun. Add to that trying to recognize what everything is about, what the references and twists in the various works are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PIVOT over Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/pivot-over-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Sep 2012 20:17:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3890</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I biked over tonight to see the installation &lt;a href=&#34;http://fonik.dk/works/pivot.html&#34;&gt;PIVOT by Jacob Kirkegaard&lt;/a&gt; at the leap in Berlin ((In the Berlin Carré, which is quite a bit different from the Amsterdam Carré. That I can assure you.)) before it finishes tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can read what the author wrote and see his or my pictures. It is a very nicely done curved projection from the Fernsehturm with recorded sound from the pivot mechanics of that same tower. Impressive and imposing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 287: kohi, praxis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-287-kohi-praxis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Sep 2012 16:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3872</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Work on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://playingwithpigs.nl/&#34;&gt;Pigs&lt;/a&gt; continues though my part is sort of finished now. The rest of the team is very busy getting the thing into the stable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7970465336/&#34; title=&#34;Toddy&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Toddy&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8318/7970465336_4f6ae5d87e.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday I dropped by &lt;a href=&#34;http://python.opentechschool.org/&#34;&gt;Open Tech School&lt;/a&gt; to do a bit of Python coaching. The entire week I spent a great many hours on &lt;em&gt;kohi&lt;/em&gt; getting both the iPhone client and the django server into usable shape. It has advanced to the point where I am using it regularly on the go and it works without too many hickups.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 282: back in Berlin, street games at Play Publik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-282-back-in-berlin-street-games-at-play-publik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3775</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7724995406/&#34; title=&#34;Wood paneled, 1-2 seated, ICE second class makes my TGV experience of a week ago look decidedly shabby by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Wood paneled, 1-2 seated, ICE second class makes my TGV experience of a week ago look decidedly shabby&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8423/7724995406_bc89014832.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Monday was the end of the holiday with a leisurely train ride from Munich to Berlin during which I managed to chew through a lot of e-mails and revise a bunch of maths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Het BMW Guggenheim Lab in Berlijn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/het-bmw-guggenheim-lab-in-berlijn/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2012 12:43:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3781</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Geconfronteerd met het feit dat de meeste dertigers die in de stad wonen geen auto meer willen hebben en veel twintigers niet eens meer hun rijbewijs halen, zetten automakers zichzelf opnieuw in de markt. Ze zijn niet meer verkopers van een statussymbool, maar aanbieders van vervoersoplossingen in een toekomstvisie waarin de auto een plek heeft naast de fiets, het openbaar vervoer en alle andere dingen die steden leuk maken. Audi komt in Londen binnenkort met haar &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.audi.co.uk/audi-innovation/audi-city.html&#34;&gt;Audicity&lt;/a&gt; en BMW toert &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bmwguggenheimlab.org/&#34;&gt;in samenwerking met het Guggenheim&lt;/a&gt; langs de wereld met haar lab. Eerst New York, nu Berlijn en straks in Mumbai. (Daimler is MIA.)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protests on Kotti against rent rises</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/protests-on-kotti-against-rent-rises/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 May 2012 17:18:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3573</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I wandered over to the rent increase protest camp on Kottbusser Tor. Some initial unformed thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7302092960/&#34; title=&#34;Wir fordern! by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Wir fordern!&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7099/7302092960_f1ea4a4425.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that the occupy style encampment has become quite a popular way of making a point. The crop of professional protesters and squatters that congregate around these camps are not very inviting towards deeper engagement. If you have no deep interest in the issues at hand, you might go over and read a couple of the pamphlets, but probably not much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 267: Hack and Tell, Thinkup, Gesellschaft im digitalen Wandel, Taobao and Gallery Weekend</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-267-hack-and-tell-thinkup-gesellschaft-im-digitalen-wandel-taobao-and-gallery-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 07:46:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3531</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a bunch of accessories for the office among which a bike stand:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6959822218/&#34; title=&#34;Parked my bike in its stand by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Parked my bike in its stand&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7062/6959822218_572e836bf8.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday I also finished the Thinkup hack I wanted to present at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.meetup.com/berlin-hack-and-tell&#34;&gt;the Berlin Hack &amp;rsquo;n Tell&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was another long sprint on saba and then off to the event. The presentation went quite well and I think I managed to hit both the technical rationale behind the hack as well as its longer term implications.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7109944621/&#34; title=&#34;Presenting at Hack and Tell by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Presenting at Hack and Tell&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7067/7109944621_0f3aefe753.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 265: Tatort debate, presentations, writing about theater, reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-265-tatort-debate-presentations-writing-about-theater-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 11:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3519</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before last (I&amp;rsquo;m running one week behind), was a good weak. Easter Monday was spent cleaning up the house which is now finally fully operational and fit to live in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6918807284/&#34; title=&#34;Return to normalcy (= bike + awesome coffee) by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Return to normalcy (= bike + awesome coffee)&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5235/6918807284_08959afbf4.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday was spent getting back on top of work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7064837317/&#34; title=&#34;Letting the poster hang out overnight by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Letting the poster hang out overnight&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7214/7064837317_100ac6a539.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blind Sequence Trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/blind-sequence-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 17:03:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3503</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De serie video&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dam-berlin.de/mlExhibitions-pa-showpage-pid-1-newlang-english.html&#34;&gt;Blind Sequence Trust&lt;/a&gt; van kunstenaar &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kubasik.biz/&#34;&gt;Joan Leandre&lt;/a&gt; speelt in DAM nog tot en met 5 mei.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6921825078/&#34; title=&#34;Joan Leandre - Blind Sequence Trust by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Joan Leandre - Blind Sequence Trust&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7090/6921825078_80558a6fc7.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leandre is een kunstenaar die al decennia lang bezig is met het gebruiken van computer 3D engines van allerlei vormen om verhalen te vertellen en emoties op te roepen. Het werk zoals dat in DAM te zien is, is lastig te plaatsen, maar zowel de beelden als de muziek zijn bijzonder goed uitgevoerd waardoor ((Het lijkt een beetje op &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.foam.org/foam-amsterdam/calendar/2010-exhibitions/fontcuberta,-joan-landscapes-without-memory&#34;&gt;Landscapes without Memory&lt;/a&gt; van Joan Fontcuberta dat in FOAM te zien was, maar dan beter.)) dingen die niets met elkaar te maken lijken te hebben, toch weten te boeien.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What the SchaubÃ¼hne is about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/what-the-schaubuhne-is-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2012 08:10:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3420</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday night I went to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/de_DE/program/detail/10489810&#34;&gt;Maß für Maß&lt;/a&gt; (Measure for Measure by Shakespeare) at die Schaubühne here in Berlin and it marked the first occasion where I saw a play directed by the intendant of that theater Thomas Ostermeier himself (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.guardian.co.uk/stage/2011/nov/13/thomas-ostermeier-hamlet-schaubuhne&#34;&gt;this Guardian piece&lt;/a&gt; for a bit of background).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mass-fur-mass.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/what-the-schaubuhne-is-about/mass-fur-mass.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Picture by Arno Declair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until that moment I had seen lots of pieces by other directors at the same house which were —I&amp;rsquo;m afraid to say— quite boring, almost all except for this one: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/de_DE/program/repertoire/577997&#34;&gt;Die Macht der Finsternis&lt;/a&gt; by Michael Thalheimer. The dance pieces that Falk Richter makes together with Anouk van Dijk are also very much worth watching, but not theater really.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Dutch theater debate in Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-dutch-theater-debate-in-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 17:45:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3424</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week or two ago I attended a discussion at the Deutsches Theater &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deutschestheater.de/spielplan/spielplan/holland_in_not/&#34;&gt;‘Holland in Not’&lt;/a&gt; that was organized because of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spiegel.de/spiegel/vorab/0,1518,820528,00.html&#34;&gt;a recently published book “Der Kulturinfarkt, vom Allem zu viel und überall das Gleiche”&lt;/a&gt; that proposed to close half of all theaters in Germany.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That prompted quite &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.spiegel.de/kultur/gesellschaft/0,1518,822606,00.html&#34;&gt;a bit of debate&lt;/a&gt; in the German cultural scene as well as the discussion at the DT. The event hosted by the Deutsches Theater brought together notables from the German theater scene and invited Alize Zandwijk (head of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.rotheater.nl/&#34;&gt;Ro Theater&lt;/a&gt;) and Johan Simons (intendant of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.muenchner-kammerspiele.de/&#34;&gt;Münchner Kammerspiele&lt;/a&gt;) to explain the Dutch situation to the gathered Germans.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 264: playable prototypes and Open State</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-264-playable-prototypes-and-open-state/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 08:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3476</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week was crazy hectic, notwithstanding the fact that I was ill at the same time. Sickness and deadlines are not fun, but thankfully both were survived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6904932768/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5348/6904932768_60bd9495d1.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had to be done was the prototype iPhone app for the first playtest of &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/?s=saba&amp;amp;searchsubmit=Search&#34;&gt;saba&lt;/a&gt;. Which was finished in the nick of time with programming sprints that ended later and later into the night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6906900510/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7063/6906900510_936e761963.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>[unnamed] is the best kept secret of Berlin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/unnamed-is-the-best-kept-secret-of-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2012 07:42:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3305</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We live in perhaps one of the nicest parts of Berlin I am finding out. It has every thinkable amenity: highly specialized stores, a diverse assortment of restaurants and cafés with some real gems. Our house is smack in the center of this in walking distance of three major U lines. If you talked to me recently you probably know where this is at, but for the purpose of this blogpost I&amp;rsquo;m going to play mum.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toneelgroep Amsterdam - Husbands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/toneelgroep-amsterdam-husbands/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2012 13:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3389</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tga.nl/default.asp?path=h8ql0lx8&#34;&gt;Husbands&lt;/a&gt; by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tga.nl/&#34;&gt;Toneelgroep Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; director Ivo van Hove in the Schaubühne in Berlin. I was not unequivocally enthusiastic about the play, though it has a boisterous quality that has stayed with me these past days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;husbands.jpeg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/toneelgroep-amsterdam-husbands/husbands-300x199.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Picture © &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tga.nl/default.asp?path=ql0lx8t48d&#34;&gt;Jan Versweyveld&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Germans on the other hand have not deigned to give the play five minutes before deciding it is trash, see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.freitag.de/community/blogs/juloeffl/find-4--husbands&#34;&gt;Jule Löffler for Freitag&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://stagescreen.wordpress.com/2012/03/10/manner-am-rande-des-nervenzusammenbruchs/&#34;&gt;Sascha Krieger&lt;/a&gt;. They stumble over each other and their poorly worded mischaracterizations to denounce the play, calling it boring, grotesque and poorly founded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Administrative No-ops</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/administrative-no-ops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2012 11:33:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3365</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week Peter Robinett sent me a link to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/2012/02/23/business/global/in-germany-a-limp-domestic-economy-stifled-by-regulation.html?_r=1&amp;amp;pagewanted=all&#34;&gt;this Times article&lt;/a&gt; that would seem a bit far fetched if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t mostly true. The headline (“a Limp Domestic Economy”) doesn&amp;rsquo;t really cover the article because it describes how massively things have improved in Germany. If I can believe stories, the situation here used to be far far worse. That however is no excuse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rule fucking (the Dutch ‘regelneuken’), protectionism and arcane laws still apply and add up to create:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A deeper simulation fever (at the Berliner GesprÃ¤che)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-deeper-simulation-fever-at-the-berliner-gesprache/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 16:07:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3318</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Wednesday I was at a gathering by the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hiig.de/&#34;&gt;Institue for Internet and Society&lt;/a&gt; here in Berlin in collaboration with Deutschlandfunk called &lt;a href=&#34;http://hiig.de/2012/02/10/%C2%BBberliner-gespr%C3%A4che%C2%AB-zu-internet-und-gesellschaft/&#34;&gt;“Berliner Gespräche”&lt;/a&gt; about how the internet influences society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6841740417/&#34; title=&#34;The internet is serious by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The internet is serious&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7148/6841740417_77b651b581.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What struck me mainly was that both a professor from the panel and a commenter from the audience held the position that the internet is in fact nothing new. That it is just another medium/channel for people to communicate through. Citing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/author/quotes/442126.Clay_Shirky&#34;&gt;Clay Shirky&lt;/a&gt;, I would say that more and faster information flows are in fact different. More fundamentally the internet is the manifestation of a vast new kind of object that interacts with other objects (such as us) in a myriad ways. That alone makes it something new and very significant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working theory regarding bureaucracy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/working-theory-regarding-bureaucracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 16:32:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3277</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6719904761/&#34; title=&#34;German form terror by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;German form terror&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7167/6719904761_3ba1c56336.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m revising my working theory for Germany based on experiences from last week and other things that have happened. My old one on &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2011/12/working-theory-for-germany/&#34;&gt;Germany&amp;rsquo;s attitude towards modernity&lt;/a&gt; still holds, but talking with open government activists and my experiences with government here, have prompted the following.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest mysteries for me is why Germany is so far behind when it comes to open government compared to the Netherlands. With &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hackdeoverheid.nl/&#34;&gt;Hack de Overheid&lt;/a&gt; we have been on a roll last year with nearly every institution coming forward and pushing towards more openness. We even got &lt;a href=&#34;http://nos.nl/op3/video/334610-minister-verhagen-over-open-data.html&#34;&gt;Minister Verhagen on television&lt;/a&gt; to pledge to our goal. All of this does not mean we have won yet, but it does show a momentum into the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early 2012 Events</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/early-2012-events/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 06:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3293</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The year has started nicely and the event line-up is already brimful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thursday a week ago saw &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ibestuurcongres.nl/&#34;&gt;the iBestuur Congress&lt;/a&gt; in the Netherlands where the winners of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appsvoornederland.nl/&#34;&gt;Apps voor Nederland&lt;/a&gt; competition were announced. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to see this last app competition to a succesful end and I look forward to what more we can bring. See &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hackdeoverheid.nl/2012/01/apps-for-the-netherlands-gold-silver-and-bronze/&#34;&gt;a write-up of them&lt;/a&gt; over at the Hack de Overheid site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I was joined here by fellow game makers from the Netherlands to participate in the Berlin Global Game Jam. We fought hard and managed to crank out the unparalleled &lt;a href=&#34;http://globalgamejam.org/2012/nakatomi-rider&#34;&gt;Nakatomi Rider&lt;/a&gt;. Niels wrote it up for the papers (available &lt;a href=&#34;http://bashers.nl/ggj12-nakatomi-rider&#34;&gt;over at Bashers&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting up self-employed in Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/starting-up-self-employed-in-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 14:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3257</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m reading up on German tax and trade rules because I&amp;rsquo;m going to incorporate here this month and most of the things I read do not make me very happy. They look like they are more suited to a 19th century gentry than to creative workers in the multipolar 21st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such thing ((I could go on and on but this is a bigger one.)) is being a &lt;em&gt;Freiberufler&lt;/em&gt;. The &lt;em&gt;Freiberuflich&lt;/em&gt; status, which means you work in a free profession, strikes me as an archaic oddity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whither the theater?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/whither-the-theater/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2012 07:27:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3131</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Talking to two young theater makers yesterday, I remarked that the majority of the Dutch plays I see don&amp;rsquo;t deliver the relevant and socially engaged experiences I would want them to. To which they asked why I still bothered going to the theater, a question I hear regularly from those in the more modern performing arts. They themselves hardly ever go and they make participatory theater, not the stage dramas that first come to mind. That is a response I get more often: that theater is boring, irrelevant and really &lt;strong&gt;‘Why would anybody want to go?’&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Criticism Without Borders</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/cultural-criticism-without-borders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2012 23:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3165</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I just got into Germany we managed to pin point something I had noticed before. It is striking how conservative people in Germany are when it comes to the internet and especially people who work in cultural positions. Compared to that, the Netherlands of the past five years has gone through a rather tumultuous revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was prompted a bit by responses are to the new play &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/en_EN/program/repertoire/754448&#34;&gt;“Edward II”&lt;/a&gt; directed by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/packages/html/arts/20070923_VANHOVE_FEATURE/?pagewanted=all&#34;&gt;Ivo van Hove&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/&#34;&gt;Schaubühne&lt;/a&gt; here. I am yet to see the play, but I hear it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. Judging from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://data.heimat.de/pics/4/4/5/2/8/ec_445289a317bd1147ad33244ee9ef8ac7.jpg&#34;&gt;set pictures&lt;/a&gt; and the trailer it is one of the more modern pieces at this particular theater ((Save perhaps Trust that I saw this week by Anouk van Dijk and Falk Richter. A bit long in the tooth, but still a very successful interdisciplinary collaboration.)). It seems to have been rather poorly received in the papers, which have treated it not really on merit, but with thinly veneered hatchet jobs where critics employed their position to jab at this or that enemy in the German cultural landscape. One particular critic even projected his own frustrations and personal perversions onto the play in a national daily. Germany still seems to be that place where personal gripes are written down and nailed to a door somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 251</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-251/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2012 07:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3236</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6619859985/&#34; title=&#34;Dropped in for a bit at the Wostel by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dropped in for a bit at the Wostel&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7171/6619859985_98b3085eda.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week was my first week in Berlin in earnest and I was more than a bit eager to get back on the horse. On Monday I visited four coworking spaces, on Tuesday I met Marguerite Joly from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hybrid-plattform.org/&#34;&gt;Hybrid Plattform&lt;/a&gt; and on Wednesday I visited a bunch more. Like &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/blog/2012/01/starting-up-in-berlin/&#34;&gt;I write over at Hubbub&lt;/a&gt;, I am looking for a studio space and much much more here in Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 249</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-249/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jan 2012 07:13:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3191</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the week I spotted an interesting dataset on Sargasso, requested to play with it and got the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://sargasso.nl/archief/2011/12/20/interrupties-tweede-kamer-mooi-verbeeld/&#34;&gt;visual published the next day&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://monsterswell.com/blog/2012/01/parliamentary-interruptions/&#34;&gt;our write-up&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then it was off to Berlin to finalize things with the appartment and prepare the move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My review of &lt;a href=&#34;http://gutefabrik.com/wimh.html&#34;&gt;“Where is my Heart?”&lt;/a&gt; was also published in the nrc.next that week ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/#!/nielsthooft/status/150113469012770816&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;):
&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;https://instagr.am/p/a3gSw/media/?size=l&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally my proposal to present on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.appsforamsterdam.nl/&#34;&gt;Apps for Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; project on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.socialcitiesoftomorrow.nl/&#34;&gt;Social Cities of Tomorrow&lt;/a&gt; conference was aspected and I will be attending and presenting at that conference in Amsterdam. Data commons are a topic that is very near to our practice and I look forward to exchanging ideas with those attending.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scepticism on the Filter Bubble</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/scepticism-on-the-filter-bubble/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2012 09:54:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3179</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I think most of the thinking around &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thefilterbubble.com/&#34;&gt;The Filter Bubble&lt;/a&gt; comes from people who are not very procedurally literate to begin with. That is to say they are not very adept at understanding the rules that govern interactive systems nor are they well equipped at reconfiguring them to suit their ends. I touch on this because the same tired argument was parroted in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zeit.de/campus/2012/01/sprechstunde-miriam-meckel/komplettansicht&#34;&gt;this Zeit interview with Miriam Meckel&lt;/a&gt;, a leading German communication scientist ((eine Koryphäe ihres Fachs)). It starts off with some very sensible sentiments but then it quickly derails on the topic of algorithms and concludes on several sidelines.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Working theory for Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/working-theory-for-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2011 14:46:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3167</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been in Berlin for a couple of hectic days now and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to come to terms with my surroundings. I have got a new working theory to use for the foreseeable future. Let&amp;rsquo;s see how well this holds up:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany has not quite recovered from their catastrophical experiment with modernism in the ’30s-’40s. This caused them to fall back and get stuck in a sort of classical romanticism. This stuckness has caused them to skip post-modernism and the developments that came after and is the main reason why its cultural velocity is slow. Some individuals have modernized to a greater or lesser extent and the developments of ’68 have had an effect, but the institutional parts of the country remain firmly entrenched in the past.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Michael LaFond - Berlin Co-Housing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/michael-lafond-berlin-co-housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 22:21:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3034</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arcam.nl/lezingen/programma_nl.html&#34;&gt;an event organized by ARCAM&lt;/a&gt; tonight concerning co-operative housing projects which are already very popular in Berlin but are rapidly expanding to other cities. Amsterdam is busy launching its own initiative and Michael LaFond from Berlin presented their experiences with this way of building.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was an interesting evening to attend. The slides were poorly visible from the back, but I managed to jot down a large part of the Q&amp;amp;A where most of the action was. It is interesting to see how eager for knowledge the Amsterdam crowd is. It strikes me as odd that building a house yourself would be novel, but given the market as it is, it is. Also: the Dutch with their capacity for trade and organization should be pretty good at this thing. If that will be so, remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A more messy city</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-more-messy-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2464</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We spent last weekend having &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/5496175719/&#34;&gt;a veritable blast&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cognitivecities.com/&#34;&gt;Cognitive Cities&lt;/a&gt; conference. It was a great spectacle of familiar faces, a nicely curated program and full frontal confrontations with the city of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot stress enough how much I enjoyed Cognitive Cities. It was crammed with beautifully designed views onto the city and a chance to catchup with old friends from all over Europe. The Copenhagen crew were present, &lt;a href=&#34;http://reboot.dk&#34;&gt;Rebooters&lt;/a&gt; came back from withdrawal and we could congratulate &lt;a href=&#34;http://yourneighbours.de/&#34;&gt;Your Neighbours&lt;/a&gt; and Third Wave with their tremendous success in organizing such a conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ein Berliner</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ein-berliner/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2008 16:38:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/ein-berliner/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Net een dag terug uit Berlijn na een weekend van straf rijden, drinken en &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.plazes.com/?p=222&#34;&gt;programmeren&lt;/a&gt; ((Klinkt redelijk ideaal, niet?)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elke keer weer in Berlijn, maakt me blij. De mensen lijken er redelijk onbevangen, de wijken zijn er ondertussen bekend en de taal gaat me elke keer weer makkelijker af.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Helaas geen tijd gehad om &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.arena-berlin.de/badeschiff.aspx&#34;&gt;sommige tips&lt;/a&gt; op te volgen of om sushi te eten, maar dat is dan weer voor een volgende keer, want die komt er zeker. In de tussentijd volgen hier in de komend dagen wat foto&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Berliner Existenz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/berliner-existenz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2007 01:57:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/11/berliner-existenz/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Na in Berlijn aangekomen te zijn, heb ik:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Turks gegeten (meermalen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heerlijke Libaneze &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kibbe&#34;&gt;kibbe&lt;/a&gt; gegeten (eindelijk weer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Currywurst gegeten (eerste van velen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Met bier over straat gelopen (vaak zat)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hardgelopen en geklommen (een beetje)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mafia_%28game%29&#34;&gt;Werewolf&lt;/a&gt; gespeeld (iets te weinig)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prenzlauerberg &amp;rsquo;s nachts verkend (meermalen)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In akelig hippe Wohnzimmer gelegen (eenmalig)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;€80 kwijtgeraakt (één keer teveel)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jeff_Wall&#34;&gt;Jeff Wall&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s foto&amp;rsquo;s gezien in het &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deutsche-guggenheim-berlin.de/&#34;&gt;Guggenheim&lt;/a&gt; (smaakt naar meer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/1879797520/&#34; title=&#34;Photo Sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2269/1879797520_9a19cb7d78.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wat ik nog wil doen voor zaterdag:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vandaar die hoed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/vandaar-die-hoed/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2007 01:03:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/11/vandaar-die-hoed/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Als jullie je afvroegen waarom ik die hoed op had, het komt door &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.blogpiloten.de/2007/11/04/barcamp-berlin-blogger-interviewen-blogger/&#34;&gt;het estafette-interview voor Blogpiloten.de&lt;/a&gt; dat ik gegeven heb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/1845955464/&#34; title=&#34;Photo Sharing&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Blogpiloten.de&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2127/1845955464_d150e34f4f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ZurÃ¼ck aus Deutschland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/zuruck-aus-deutschland/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2007 15:08:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/10/zuruck-aus-deutschland/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even twee dagen weg zijn en aan niks anders dan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.expressaopaulista.com/DE/&#34;&gt;capoeira&lt;/a&gt; en andere Brazilianischen Sachen hoeven te denken is fijn. Nu nog even 1500 foto&amp;rsquo;s verwerken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veel te doen voor ik op &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/place/de/berlin&#34;&gt;2 november naar Berlijn&lt;/a&gt; ga:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nieuwe huis klussen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Verhuizen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feest geven&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BTW-aangifte doen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Een paar sites afmaken en lanceren&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik zou er bijna moe van worden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NS Internationaal</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ns-internationaal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 04:33:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/10/ns-internationaal/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik ga eind deze maand naar Berlijn om &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eelkedekker.nl/&#34;&gt;Eelke&lt;/a&gt; te bezoeken en acte de présence te geven op de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.web2expo.com/&#34;&gt;Web 2.0 Expo&lt;/a&gt; en Barcamp Berlin. Nu dacht ik dat het wel leuk zou zijn om met de trein te gaan. Ik heb pas ook een Railplus Kaart bij mijn kortingskaart gekocht. Daar zou ik iets aan moeten hebben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Voor Berlijn staan overal advertenties van de NS dat retourkaartjes €58 kosten. Als je op de site zo&amp;rsquo;n kaartje probeert te boeken, lijkt het erop dat ze beschikbaar zijn. Ga je alleen een stap verder dan krijg je &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/1479158734/&#34;&gt;een ontzettend vage foutmelding&lt;/a&gt;. Het lijkt erop dat alle kaartjes van €29 via de site niet te boeken te zijn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
