<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on alper.nl</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on alper.nl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:38:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/travel/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iseji - Day 0 - Getting to Ise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/11/iseji-day-0-getting-to-ise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:38:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18528</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I still need to write up how I got to Ise in the first place and why that was so terrible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After landing on Narita at around 11:00 JST, I fumbled around a bit and managed to buy myself a sandwich and a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.keisei.co.jp/keisei/tetudou/skyliner/us/skyliner/index.php&#34;&gt;Skyliner&lt;/a&gt; ticket. So far so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then getting into town, I quickly found out I couldn’t get any money from the ATMs. Not from any ATM, not with any card.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iseji - Day 3 - Kiinagashima to Owase</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/11/iseji-day-3-kiinagashima-to-owase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 11:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18500</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another day, another broken night because of jetlag. Getting up at all was not easy, let alone getting up early.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hostess kindly offered to refund me the money (a trifle) for dinner because of the misunderstanding. Which I of course did not accept. The food was tasty, plentiful and home cooked and she might have saved my legs. She made me the light breakfast with fish and rice that we know and love.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iseji - Day 2 - Misedani to Kiinagashima</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/11/iseji-day-2-misedani-to-kiinagashima/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 21:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18496</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well before 7am I grabbed a quick breakfast at the local FamilyMart and supplies for the day ahead. I&amp;rsquo;m glad that these things are open 24 hours, but how is this possible? Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s better to not ask any questions (S. &lt;a href=&#34;https://mainichi.jp/english/articles/20251114/p2a/00m/0bu/032000c&#34;&gt;Store owner regrets &amp;lsquo;slave contracts&amp;rsquo; with major Japanese convenience store chain Ministop&lt;/a&gt;). I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to be able to get any kind of coffee at a time like this, but the hotel machine brewed something that wasn&amp;rsquo;t entirely undrinkable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iseji - Day 1 - Tamura to Misedani</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/11/iseji-day-1-tamura-to-misedani/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 13:16:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18480</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The day started late after jetlag kept me up between 2-5am. Then when I finally got to sleep, it was time to get up and leave. The Fitbit clocks me at 3h47m of sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly walked over from the lovely &lt;a href=&#34;https://maps.app.goo.gl/jPwVTpBdEucQciL5A&#34;&gt;Mizuhokan&lt;/a&gt; to the Ise Outer Shrine. The site is beautiful and I just learned that the empty lot next to the shrine is where they&amp;rsquo;ll build the building anew every 20 years. A tradition, &lt;em&gt;shikinen sengu&lt;/em&gt;, I had heard about before but hadn&amp;rsquo;t connected to this place. They started the 63rd rebuilding this year &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.iseshima-kanko.jp/en/highlights/sengu_eg&#34;&gt;apparently&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/11/18451/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 21:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18451</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This spring when I was in London, I stayed there with Sonder and even when they were still in business the entire process was somewhat sketchy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/sonder-bankruptcy-9.6976737&#34;&gt;https://www.cbc.ca/news/business/sonder-bankruptcy-9.6976737&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/01/17911/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 10:34:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17911</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tenpages.github.io/us-level/us.html&#34;&gt;Maps for where you&amp;rsquo;ve been&lt;/a&gt; in Europe and the US ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.iamcal.com/2025-01/10229/&#34;&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;). Stayed means having spent a night there which means the only places I&amp;rsquo;ve visited and not spent the night are Slovenia (went over the border to hike a mountain there) and the Vatican.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should probably upgrade Turkey to lived depending on your definition: stayed in your own house or registered as a resident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;CleanShot-2025-01-12-at-11.30.08@2x.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My score for the US is negligible and I don&amp;rsquo;t see this changing any time soon (maybe ever).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/01/17904/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 14:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17904</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Germany for many transactions you need a proof of address which a &lt;em&gt;Personalausweis&lt;/em&gt; provides for German citizens. Us foreigners don&amp;rsquo;t get one however often we ask for it. In the Netherlands moving through the country without a battery of chip cards (OV chipkaart, Bonuskaart, OV-fiets etc.), apps and associated services is costly and annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The signs have been there for a while but China seems to be pushing this much further along. The question is whether it&amp;rsquo;s a deliberate move or that the number of people affected is so small that they&amp;rsquo;re a negligible edge case for the policy makers over there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year in Review 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/01/year-in-review-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17872</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a grab bag year but overall not as bad as 2023 and a bunch of things seem to be on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;health&#34;&gt;Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got on the neurodiversity bandwagon this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I got myself a self-paid diagnosis for ADHD. This result should not surprise anybody who knows me. I&amp;rsquo;ve forced myself to be very high functioning throughout my life but it can&amp;rsquo;t be denied that there were always some underlying issues. I&amp;rsquo;m on medication from the end of the year and have gone off caffeine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2025/01/17862/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 17:23:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17862</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There was a brief period where Foursquare based recommendations were good and drawn from your wider social graph. Now we&amp;rsquo;ve gone back to Yelp and Google Maps where reviews and ratings don&amp;rsquo;t mean anything. A lower than 4 star review on GMaps has netted me a cease-and-desist e-mail for defamation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That puts personally curated travel docs and word of mouth back in play as Thrillist describes here. Every Dutch person has or knows somebody who has a Berlin Google Doc with all the &lt;em&gt;Geheimtipps&lt;/em&gt;. Dutch people&amp;rsquo;s tastes are fairly predictable and pedestrian, so these&amp;rsquo;ll mostly be cheap Asian eateries in Prenzlauerberg but that&amp;rsquo;s also fine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>December Adventure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2024/12/december-adventure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 23:44:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17749</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I felt I couldn&amp;rsquo;t really bring myself to do &lt;a href=&#34;https://adventofcode.com&#34;&gt;Advent of Code&lt;/a&gt; this year since I have more than enough other things to do (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcane_(TV_series)&#34;&gt;watch&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://store.steampowered.com/app/333640/Caves_of_Qud/&#34;&gt;play&lt;/a&gt;) and with work and the kids, it&amp;rsquo;s always pretty miserable to keep up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw this thing called &lt;a href=&#34;https://eli.li/december-adventure&#34;&gt;December Adventure&lt;/a&gt; though and that fits in nicely with my current push to release a major update for &lt;a href=&#34;https://cuppin.gs&#34;&gt;Cuppings&lt;/a&gt;. If I&amp;rsquo;m going to be programming until late this month, then I&amp;rsquo;d prefer it to be on something that I can release.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2024/11/17718/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 08:28:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17718</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I painstakingly built a bespoke Rust web application to host the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cuppin.gs&#34;&gt;Cuppings&lt;/a&gt; venue data and to add Google place_ids to almost 2000 Foursquare location. That&amp;rsquo;s been done for a while now but now we have the announcement of Foursquare open sourcing their location dataset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That has two direct consequences for me:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was going to scrub the Foursquare data out of the database as a clean-up but that&amp;rsquo;s something I won&amp;rsquo;t do for now. In fact, I may recode the venues so I have ids in both worlds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was toying around with the idea of building a next generation Foursquare/Dopplr on top of &lt;a href=&#34;https://atproto.com&#34;&gt;atproto&lt;/a&gt; which is something that I think is a lot more feasible now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Nov/20/foursquare-open-source-places/#atom-everything&#34;&gt;https://simonwillison.net/2024/Nov/20/foursquare-open-source-places/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2024/11/17686/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:10:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17686</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A beautiful elegy for photographer Matthieu Chazal by Paul Salopek on the epic Out of Eden Walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On those bitter days afoot in the Caucasus, Murat and I would sometimes send Matthieu ahead to search for shelter in the snowy wastes. He was very good at it. Often, we found him at a tumbledown farmhouse or roadside inn, regaling a crowd with outlandish stories, and sipping from a jar of homemade Georgian wine. Last month our nomad friend left us, at 49, a casualty of aggressive cancer. Once more he scouts the road ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2024/11/17676/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 19:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17676</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe I have to say this, but let&amp;rsquo;s do it anyway: Going to Mars is—just like the hyperloop—a distraction from the actual problems and solutions in front of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://defector.com/neither-elon-musk-nor-anybody-else-will-ever-colonize-mars&#34;&gt;https://defector.com/neither-elon-musk-nor-anybody-else-will-ever-colonize-mars&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2024/01/2023-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17382</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back on 2023 I can say that we made lemonade out of an overall pretty shit year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not to worry. This is probably just one shit year in a sequence of many more shit years to come. No sign of anything getting better in our near future and lots of trends pointing downward. Does it have to be like this? Not in any way but the majority of people are stupid and we all suffer together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2023/11/17312/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 15:24:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17312</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding time for side projects and putting out new versions of Cuppings is difficult as always, but I&amp;rsquo;m glad we have a new version out this week again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The list of things still to do is long as ever but for now enjoy the newest most up to date version of your favourite coffee drinking guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/de/app/cuppings/id652901707?l=en-GB&#34;&gt;https://apps.apple.com/de/app/cuppings/id652901707?l=en-GB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2023/03/17125/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 10:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17125</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But these subjects of the Islamic Emirate could not be kept from watching &lt;em&gt;Stranger Things&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/em&gt; or Japanese anime; they had a better knowledge of &lt;em&gt;Breaking Bad&lt;/em&gt; than I did. On Twitter—they, like so many Afghans, were avid users—shared soyjack memes and called themselves “sigma males.”They talked about feminism, “LGBTQ,”and pronouns—strange things to complain about in a country where women can’t go to school. They were becoming Westerners: culture war, America’s most successful soft-power export, was their induction. The younger members of the Taliban, online enough to follow &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newsweek.com/taliban-worried-about-andrew-tate-they-ask-his-freedom-1770693&#34;&gt;Andrew Tate&lt;/a&gt;, were not immune.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2023/01/16946/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jan 2023 19:45:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16946</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Everything we continue to learn about the very earliest people is completely fascinating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next time I go to Turkey, a visit to the Taş Tepeler is definitely in order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/does-an-unknown-extraordinarily-ancient-civilisation-lie-buried-under-eastern-turkey-/&#34;&gt;https://www.spectator.co.uk/article/does-an-unknown-extraordinarily-ancient-civilisation-lie-buried-under-eastern-turkey-/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2022/04/16771/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2022 22:59:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16771</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh Beirut, it seems nothing has changed since the last time I was there. Things have pretty much only gotten predictably worse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://palladiummag.com/2021/12/09/the-long-fall-of-beirut/&#34;&gt;https://palladiummag.com/2021/12/09/the-long-fall-of-beirut/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2021/10/16599/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2021 22:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16599</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of amazing and unforgettable experiences with Couchsurfing mostly staying in Berlin way back in the day. This history of the site&amp;rsquo;s rise and fall fills in what happened after I lost track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.inputmag.com/features/rise-and-ruin-of-couchsurfing&#34;&gt;https://www.inputmag.com/features/rise-and-ruin-of-couchsurfing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/12/16369/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 20:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16369</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lovely interview about the magic bus and the hippie period in Istanbul revolving around the Lale Pudding Shop which is still in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kenan&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/kenan&lt;/a&gt;_sharpe/status/1333719308585857024&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/10/16353/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 09:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.alper.nl/dingen/?p=16353</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Als ik het verhaal over witwassen in de Amsterdamse binnenstad hier lees, denk ik dat het hier in Berlijn zonder overdrijven tien keer zo erg is (decennia armoede, corruptie en geen enkele prioriteit bij de lokale overheid).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.groene.nl/artikel/ze-zijn-hier-zo-lekker-aan-het-witwassen&#34;&gt;https://www.groene.nl/artikel/ze-zijn-hier-zo-lekker-aan-het-witwassen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/09/16273/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 19:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16273</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting story about the interaction between loving the outdoors and Instagram culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.outsideonline.com/2415324/instagram-social-media-geotagging-outdoors-oversharing&#34;&gt;https://www.outsideonline.com/2415324/instagram-social-media-geotagging-outdoors-oversharing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/06/16117/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 22:44:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16117</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We have to build these ultra rapid trains anyway, so let&amp;rsquo;s start on it tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/heimbergecon/status/1273531610932170752&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/heimbergecon/status/1273531610932170752&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/05/16087/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:57:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16087</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lovely set of easter eggs hidden in Switzerland&amp;rsquo;s official maps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eyeondesign.aiga.org/for-decades-cartographers-have-been-hiding-covert-illustrations-inside-of-switzerlands-official-maps/&#34;&gt;https://eyeondesign.aiga.org/for-decades-cartographers-have-been-hiding-covert-illustrations-inside-of-switzerlands-official-maps/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chaos at the Top of the World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2020/01/15933/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 13:55:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15933</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A breathtaking background story of how the top of Mount Everest turned into a tourist destination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.gq.com/story/mount-everest-chaos-at-the-top-of-the-world&#34;&gt;https://www.gq.com/story/mount-everest-chaos-at-the-top-of-the-world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Languages spoken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/10/languages-spoken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 21:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15798</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Found this on Reddit and made my own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Picked the countries where 50% of the people speak a language where I have at least B level of skill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;5e3bc816-e99f-46b4-92a5-4adc3b911d5d.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/09/15737/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2019 21:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15737</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I remember seeing at IST airport advertisements for connecting flights to Erbil (Ø£Ø±Ø¨ÙŠÙ„â€Ž). The city seems to have continued growing and by now developed a vibrant nightlife.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.playboy.com/read/nightlife-erbil-kurdistan&#34;&gt;https://www.playboy.com/read/nightlife-erbil-kurdistan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/09/15701/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 20:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15701</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An interesting bit of news did the rounds last week but I&amp;rsquo;ve personally heard of multiple cases where people leaving online reviews have been faced with legal action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany has a lot of lawyers and judges and the system finds work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/sep/06/german-tourist-sued-complaints-hotel-nazi-portraits-austria?CMP=share_btn_tw&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2019/sep/06/german-tourist-sued-complaints-hotel-nazi-portraits-austria?CMP=share_btn_tw&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/08/15639/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 21:12:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15639</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not enough popcorn in the world to read this exposé on Booking.com.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s just say that if almost everybody tells you not to write your website in Perl and you still insist on it, then you deserve all of the consequences of that decision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they seem to be making so much money than most of the dysfunctionality in the article does not really affect the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.volkskrant.nl/kijkverder/v/2019/oud-werknemers-over-booking.com-het-is-een-grote-chaos/?referer=https%3A%2F%2Fpinboard.in%2Fu%3Aalper%2Funread%2F&#34;&gt;https://www.volkskrant.nl/kijkverder/v/2019/oud-werknemers-over-booking.com-het-is-een-grote-chaos/?referer=https%3A%2F%2Fpinboard.in%2Fu%3Aalper%2Funread%2F&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/06/15508/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 19:58:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15508</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the blisters develop and his feet start to bleed, Walton asks the right questions. What are the human and environmental costs of Singapore’s success, and are they sustainable?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His conclusions are more nuanced than either Singapore’s detractors or its cheerleaders would like. The island’s vaunted meritocracy is imperfect, especially seen from the perspective of its Malay and Indian minorities; and the pressures on citizens to perform and conform are so intense that those who do not fit in sometimes opt for voluntary exile.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/05/15466/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 22:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15466</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cities like Barcelona are starting to fight back against AirBnB and tourism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/04/29/the-airbnb-invasion-of-barcelona&#34;&gt;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/04/29/the-airbnb-invasion-of-barcelona&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently refused to help some local tourists to call the bike share hotline in German. We were legitimately in a hurry but my flat out refusal was not appreciated. Next time I&amp;rsquo;ll tell them I won&amp;rsquo;t be helping them because I do not support tourism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2019/04/15363/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 14:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15363</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“The economic costs Airbnb imposes likely outweigh the benefits.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think anybody will be surprised by this study whose conclusions are that AirBnB is a drain on society and should be taxed and regulated mercilessly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.epi.org/publication/the-economic-costs-and-benefits-of-airbnb-no-reason-for-local-policymakers-to-let-airbnb-bypass-tax-or-regulatory-obligations/&#34;&gt;https://www.epi.org/publication/the-economic-costs-and-benefits-of-airbnb-no-reason-for-local-policymakers-to-let-airbnb-bypass-tax-or-regulatory-obligations/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Presenting at the Good School</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2018/05/presenting-at-the-good-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 May 2018 08:04:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6001</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weeks ago I took the train to Hamburg and back to present at the Good School. Here&amp;rsquo;s a picture of me in action courtesy of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.good-school.de/&#34;&gt;The Good School&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2018/05/presenting-at-the-good-school/dtc_t_3-tag_alper/&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2018/05/presenting-at-the-good-school/DTC_T_3.-Tag_Alper.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Packing List</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2016/04/packing-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 14:32:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5547</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I used to travel between the Netherlands and Germany at least once a month and pretty quickly I grew tired of forgetting things. That&amp;rsquo;s why I made a list (in &lt;strong&gt;bold&lt;/strong&gt;, comments added) with the things that I should take or at least consider taking. Whenever I pack my bag, I quickly scan the list and make sure I&amp;rsquo;ve covered the bases. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;ll be helpful to you as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tokyo Coffee Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/10/tokyo-coffee-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2013 16:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4774</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are my notes from a couple of weeks of drinking coffee in Tokyo on a fact finding mission for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cuppin.gs/&#34;&gt;Cuppings&lt;/a&gt;. With Cuppings we try to give you a guide of the best coffee places around the world based on our personal tastings. Some notable locales are still not as well represented as they should be. London and New York have their own excellent guides for coffee with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nytimes.com/interactive/2010/03/09/dining/20100309-new-york-coffee-map.html&#34;&gt;Oliver Strand&amp;rsquo;s Coffee App&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelondoncoffeemap.com/&#34;&gt;the London Coffee Map&lt;/a&gt;. Tokyo is one place that I thought we should fill in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 336</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/10/week-336/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Oct 2013 12:16:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4792</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9588195849/&#34; title=&#34;Beautiful new coffee place by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Beautiful new coffee place&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7295/9588195849_232cf26b33_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was the week of getting a lot of things done and a minor John Boyd obsession. I read &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/38840.Boyd&#34;&gt;the biography by Coram&lt;/a&gt; and queued the PhD thesis by Osinga to read as soon as I finish Latour&amp;rsquo;s Aramis ((This is all a move towards reading more foundational works (I &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/08/apply-your-philosophy/&#34;&gt;wrote about that here&lt;/a&gt;) instead of the pop-sci that permeates everything.)). &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.defensie.nl/nlda/onderzoek_en_onderwijs/wetenschappelijk_medewerkers/krijgswetenschappen/extra_informatie_osinga&#34;&gt;Frans Osinga&lt;/a&gt; is a rather impressive fellow if you look at his Ministry of Defense webpage. We were joking around that having a design event with him would be brilliant mind-expand. Unfortunately events take too much time to organize so that won&amp;rsquo;t be happening anytime soon.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 332</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/08/week-332/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 07:15:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4719</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oh, this week. This week was how to put it rather intense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got visits again from &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ruk&#34;&gt;Peter Rukavina&lt;/a&gt; and this time &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mygdal&#34;&gt;Thomas&lt;/a&gt; dropped in as well to make it a proper Reboot reunion. I decided to join Peter (Bihr) to go to London in October to attend Playful and Mozilla Festival and potentially &lt;a href=&#34;http://gamecity.co.uk/&#34;&gt;Gamecity&lt;/a&gt; too which is supposed to be an awesome conference in Nottingham. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been outside of London so that alone may be worth the trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 330</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/08/week-330/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2013 10:36:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4701</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new coffee place had reportedly opened up in the area and I went out searching for it. &lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/concierge-coffee/51d3f1e2498e15ad7aa4c00e&#34;&gt;Concierge&lt;/a&gt; is tucked into a gate on Paul-Lincke-Ufer and they are really nice guys pulling quality shots. It is amazing both that this part of Berlin which was quite barren when it comes to coffee is shaping up so nicely and also that&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9255591138/&#34; title=&#34;Concierge Coffee, opening party tonight. Namy, Dutch guy, making a flat white for me. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Concierge Coffee, opening party tonight. Namy, Dutch guy, making a flat white for me.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2841/9255591138_6344c79ff3_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 328</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/07/week-328/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 09:14:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4695</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Travel is making it hard to keep up writing these notes weekly (or write anything for that matter). So this blog is &lt;a href=&#34;http://ironbloggerberlin.com/&#34;&gt;turning into an expensive affair&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/9124420933/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office. Off to Munich in a bit. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office. Off to Munich in a bit.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2893/9124420933_ef3d604145_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Way back when this happened I was in the Netherlands for an appointment that was cancelled and because of that I had to fly to Munich from Amsterdam for a day of workshopping. The next night I flew back to Amsterdam to spend the rest of the week at &lt;a href=&#34;http://hubbub.eu/&#34;&gt;Hubbub&lt;/a&gt; HQ in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 324</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/06/week-324/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2013 07:36:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4652</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8864206696/&#34; title=&#34;Bicycle madness by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Bicycle madness&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.staticflickr.com/2881/8864206696_05077e9c83_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two weeks ago I headed towards Amsterdam where I&amp;rsquo;ll be the week after next again. I did a massive sprint on Cuppings and prepared my presentation for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dezwijger.nl/page/72146/nl&#34;&gt;Sign of Times&lt;/a&gt; in Pakhuis de Zwijger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I worked on a bunch of projects over at Hubbub on Tuesday and on Wednesday I was there again but then to prepare my presentation. That talk went really well despite the torrential rains of the day and I had a great time catching up with the people who had showed up.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 320</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/05/week-320/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2013 12:32:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4540</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before last started out with me still in Paris sampling the local coffee scene which has been improving massively over the past year or so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/t%C3%A9lescope/4f684076e4b0b4f791ce4f7f&#34;&gt;Télescope&lt;/a&gt; already was nice:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8692196038/&#34; title=&#34;Proper coffee by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Proper coffee&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8123/8692196038_00c28a0115_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with the addition of &lt;a href=&#34;https://foursquare.com/v/loustic/5149c2738aca0ead6a573ce5&#34;&gt;Loustic&lt;/a&gt;, French coffee can finally be taken seriously again:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8691848065/&#34; title=&#34;Very nice place and only open for six weeks now. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Very nice place and only open for six weeks now.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8405/8691848065_45c31a4b45_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 319</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/05/week-319/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2013 22:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4528</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week was the week where we were in full sprint for the pilot launch of KAIGARA. Besides that we had a dinner off &lt;a href=&#34;http://nextberlin.eu/&#34;&gt;NEXT&lt;/a&gt; with some people involved and some speakers. What I managed to catch from NEXT&amp;rsquo;s program while working was nothing short of splendid. &lt;a href=&#34;http://nextberlin.eu/2013/04/bruce-sterling-fantasy-prototypes-and-real-disruption/&#34;&gt;Bruce Sterling&amp;rsquo;s talk&lt;/a&gt; has been shared widely and I&amp;rsquo;m eagerly awaiting Anab Jain&amp;rsquo;s to be published as a video ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.superflux.in/blog/newnormal-revisited&#34;&gt;the slides are already there&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday I managed to set aside a bit of time to go to the local multiplayer picknick at Amaze. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amaze-indieconnect.de/&#34;&gt;Amaze Indie Connect&lt;/a&gt; is the most fun event of the Berlin game scene and it always gets lots of very cool people to come out. Just sitting at the same table as &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/terrycavanagh&#34;&gt;Terry Cavanagh&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/smestorp&#34;&gt;Michael Brough&lt;/a&gt; left me a bit star-struck:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8681546562/&#34; title=&#34;@smestorp and @TerryCavanagh playing a game in the beer garden! Amaze Indie Connect is awesome. by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;@smestorp and @TerryCavanagh playing a game in the beer garden! Amaze Indie Connect is awesome.&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8258/8681546562_4f5d4edf82_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 318</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/05/week-318/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2013 13:26:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4524</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Unbelievable how many weeks behind I am on these. That&amp;rsquo;s not wholly intended, but the last couple of weeks have been a bit busier than usual. This was the week of April 15th which I spent mostly in Amsterdam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a full day with the team on Tuesday working on &lt;a href=&#34;http://whatsthehubbub.nl/?s=kaigara&amp;amp;searchsubmit=Search&#34;&gt;KAIGARA&lt;/a&gt;:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8654049797/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8118/8654049797_ebe61f6e3e_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I drank very awesome coffee that &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevillagecoffee.nl/&#34;&gt;Angelo had brought back&lt;/a&gt; from his road trip along the west coast of the USA:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8656916145/&#34; title=&#34;Angelo got that fresh package from the states by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Angelo got that fresh package from the states&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8113/8656916145_4181687733_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 317</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/04/week-317/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2013 19:25:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4508</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before this on Monday (almost two weeks ago), I went to a lecture by Graham Harman. &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/04/graham-harman-at-the-universitat-der-kunste/&#34;&gt;Notes on that&lt;/a&gt; were blogged in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That week also involved a one-day trip to Munich to present on the work we did for a client there. More on that on the Hubbub blog in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8638417758/&#34; title=&#34;My desk optically flipped (not an Instagram filter) by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;My desk optically flipped (not an Instagram filter)&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8110/8638417758_05037692c5_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeks 313-4</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/03/weeks-313-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2013 12:27:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4463</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two week notes in one because last week seems to have been too busy to write any.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8552432673/&#34; title=&#34;Rushing through the snow towards Amsterdam by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Rushing through the snow towards Amsterdam&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8233/8552432673_d375951613_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week 313 was spent in the Netherlands with a somewhat hectic visit. I spent a lot of time at the Hubbub studio and at the Open Coop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8557842180/&#34; title=&#34;Today&#39;s office by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Today&amp;rsquo;s office&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8086/8557842180_b73b4d0c07_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And of course the inevitable five (!) visits to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thevillagecoffee.nl/&#34;&gt;the Village&lt;/a&gt; who were serving only &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.coffeecollective.dk/&#34;&gt;Coffee Collective&lt;/a&gt; coffees when I was there:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 312</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2013/03/week-312/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 12:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4401</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8527131955/&#34; title=&#34;The German police state is up and about by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;The German police state is up and about&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8371/8527131955_97673a982f_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I booked my &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/trip/alper/3428356&#34;&gt;trip and accommodation in Paris&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m quite looking forward to see that city again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday we had a big office lunch along with the people from &lt;a href=&#34;http://schnellebuntebilder.de/?lang=en&#34;&gt;Schnelle Bunte Bilder&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wednesday we had our weekly German language class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8533006375/&#34; title=&#34;Language class by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Language class&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8511/8533006375_9453255f48_z.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that night I worked late to finish TORREON. A small project that took up way too much time as all small projects do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Capitals I didn&#39;t visit until 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/12/capitals-i-didnt-visit-until-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3963</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One recap of 2012 which was an odd year what with the international move and all. Still in the second half I managed to get &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of travel in leaving aside the almost monthly trips to Amsterdam by train. Dopplr unfortunately does not give me &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/traveller/alper/public&#34;&gt;a total amount of kilometers&lt;/a&gt; travelled for 2012 anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The funny thing is that I visited a lot of capitals of countries that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t visited before even though I may have visited the country.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 301: a flurry of appointments in Amsterdam</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/12/week-301-a-flurry-of-appointments-in-amsterdam/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Dec 2012 07:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4108</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last Monday was the last day in Berlin before the holidays so something of a push here and there to get things to go through. That night we had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://vvvv.org/&#34;&gt;vvvv&lt;/a&gt; workshop at the studio hosted by Joreg to teach somewhere around eight people the basics of node based graphical environments (the only other one I had used extensively before was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opendx.org/&#34;&gt;Open DX&lt;/a&gt; and of course there&amp;rsquo;s Quartz Composer and &lt;a href=&#34;http://impure.com/&#34;&gt;Impure Quadrigram&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/8282160298/&#34; title=&#34;VVVV workshop. I&#39;m psyched! by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;VVVV workshop. I&amp;rsquo;m psyched!&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8071/8282160298_55a1122f0a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Monocle-isms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/11/monocle-isms/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2012 14:52:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3982</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I picked up a &lt;a href=&#34;http://monocle.com/&#34;&gt;Monocle&lt;/a&gt; at Sydney airport for a long flight without laptop (along with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/7141642-the-thousand-autumns-of-jacob-de-zoet&#34;&gt;a book&lt;/a&gt;) and I was a bit disappointed ((In retrospect I should have bought a New Yorker if they had them, but this was an impulse purchase and yes I too do aspire in a modest way.)) in finding that the magazine hadn&amp;rsquo;t progressed much since I first read it years ago. It still is that strangely a-political collection of fluff pieces for the spendy class and because of the current realities of print publishing now also brimful of advertorials.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 296: Back in Europe/business</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/11/week-296-back-in-europebusiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 17:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3989</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After some weeks traveling to Beijing and Australia, last week I was back in Europe, touching down in Amsterdam Tuesday morning early. I had a very nice flight in from Sydney with the only annoyance being that my laptop had broken upon arrival there. This made me spend half a day of the two I had there in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.apple.com/au/retail/bondi/&#34;&gt;Bondi Apple Store&lt;/a&gt; trying to figure out what the problem was.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Genius there was less than helpful. Determining that it was my hard drive, he tried without avail to erase it and then load up a new version of the OS. I am more or less pleased that he wasn&amp;rsquo;t successful in doing that. In Amsterdam I tried another couple of things but finally handed it in at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.maccare.nl/&#34;&gt;Maccare.nl&lt;/a&gt; who without touching it said ‘it was probably the cable’ and the very same day had replaced it for me. Since the Genius hadn&amp;rsquo;t even managed to erase my disk, I could incredulously resume working from where I was a week ago.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 292: Ignite, GSL, pre-trip prep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/10/week-292-ignite-gsl-pre-trip-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2012 03:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3971</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sitting here at &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.bcia.com.cn/&#34;&gt;Beijing Airport&lt;/a&gt; writing these too late weeknotes on their free WiFi ((Also: it is nice to still have a blog in a country where most social services are effectively a SPOF.)) which is an oddly implemented but still excellent service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week was mostly spent with a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/10/games-on-ignite-berlin-3/#footnote_0_3965&#34;&gt;scattered brain&lt;/a&gt; working on my ignite an various proposals. We had a studio meeting at &lt;a href=&#34;http://praxisberlin.net/&#34;&gt;Praxis&lt;/a&gt; to discuss recent developments and issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 282: back in Berlin, street games at Play Publik</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/08/week-282-back-in-berlin-street-games-at-play-publik/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2012 08:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3775</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7724995406/&#34; title=&#34;Wood paneled, 1-2 seated, ICE second class makes my TGV experience of a week ago look decidedly shabby by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Wood paneled, 1-2 seated, ICE second class makes my TGV experience of a week ago look decidedly shabby&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8423/7724995406_bc89014832.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last Monday was the end of the holiday with a leisurely train ride from Munich to Berlin during which I managed to chew through a lot of e-mails and revise a bunch of maths.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weeks 280-281: Traveling and vacation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/08/weeks-280-281-traveling-and-vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2012 16:38:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3768</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7636181826/&#34; title=&#34;Having my mind catch up with me in the garden by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Having my mind catch up with me in the garden&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8161/7636181826_6899cf7e92.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last two weeks, after the brief trip to present in Helsinki were mostly spent on holiday in Avignon and the Alps (with some short stops in La Ciotat and Finale Ligure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7650678210/&#34; title=&#34;Die Kontrakte des Kaufmanns by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Die Kontrakte des Kaufmanns&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7246/7650678210_8541ab27ce.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fun was had. Relaxation not so much, but nevertheless, normal service has continued here again this week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gentse Feesten: a fantastic city festival</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/08/gentse-feesten-a-fantastic-city-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 11:55:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3697</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent two days in Ghent a Belgian city that is lovely in its own right, but really shines for a long week every summer when it has its own festival: the Gentse Feesten. I&amp;rsquo;d been there once before some ten years ago and had a lot of fun there. So &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.visitflanders.com/&#34;&gt;Tourism Flanders&lt;/a&gt; gave me the chance to revisit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7576118578/&#34; title=&#34;Long time since I was here. #fiaf12 by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Long time since I was here. #fiaf12&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8155/7576118578_91cd59173a.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 279: Paris, Numerical Revolutions, Helsinki, Dutch eCulture Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/07/week-279-paris-numerical-revolutions-helsinki-dutch-eculture-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jul 2012 07:35:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3712</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7590724728/&#34; title=&#34;Oh La La Gare du Nord by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Oh La La Gare du Nord&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8157/7590724728_5e79e6275f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7592389114/&#34; title=&#34;Pyramids by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Pyramids&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7135/7592389114_89d1af3f5c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my stay in Ghent there was so much rain, I managed to do some work on &lt;em&gt;kohi&lt;/em&gt; in the hotel room. This being a self-commissioned project, it can hardly be named work in any of the regular meanings of the word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7591535476/&#34; title=&#34;Arrived by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Arrived&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8427/7591535476_af29802b99.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tuesday I travelled onwards to my AirBnB in Paris in the area of Porte de Saint Ouen. A neighborhood far away enough from the city center to be cheap and colorful (a bit like Delfshaven), but just inside the Péripherique boundary so not too threatening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 275: Athens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/07/week-275-athens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jul 2012 15:51:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3682</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The week before last I spent in Athens mostly hanging out, going to the beach and getting some work done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was also the week that I upgraded my Things client to to &lt;a href=&#34;http://culturedcode.com/beta/thingscloud/download/&#34;&gt;the Things Cloud Beta&lt;/a&gt;. I think I&amp;rsquo;m not supposed to say anything about it, but let me just say: ++. I have started moving large parts of my workload to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.asana.com/&#34;&gt;Asana&lt;/a&gt;, so it remains to be seen if native apps like these continue to be a good fit for what is an inherently collaborative effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Greece, a society undergoing Stockholm syndrome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/06/greece-a-society-undergoing-stockholm-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2012 12:57:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3641</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spent last week in Athens because &lt;a href=&#34;http://fraulea.tumblr.com/&#34;&gt;Lea&lt;/a&gt; was at work at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.greekfestival.gr/en/&#34;&gt;Athens &amp;amp; Epidaurus festival&lt;/a&gt; where &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/&#34;&gt;the Schaubühne&lt;/a&gt; staged two plays. I spent the week relaxing, working and taking in the Athens air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/7433234262/&#34; title=&#34;Rooftop drink watching the Acropolis by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Rooftop drink watching the Acropolis&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm6.staticflickr.com/5453/7433234262_bf50680e5f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;athens-terrace-life&#34;&gt;Athens Terrace Life&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The temperature of 32-36C during the entire week was a good reason to spend all my time outdoors in the shade. Athens, being accustomed to this weather, has ample options to choose from to spend your time, from garden patios, terraces all over the place, drink and food stands and lots and lots of iced cappucini and espressi.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Copenhagen Bikes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/06/copenhagen-bikes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jun 2012 11:39:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3602</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During my visit to Copenhagen I tried to make use of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bycyklen.dk/&#34;&gt;Copenhagen City Bike&lt;/a&gt; system. Although eventually successful, it turns out bicycle sharing systems without a digital component can lead to frustrations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/09/boris-bikes-are-made-of-epic-win/&#34;&gt;London&amp;rsquo;s Boris Bikes&lt;/a&gt; provide a digital readout of station occupancy in Copenhagen you need to walk around and see which (if any) station still has a bike in it. Late afternoon this turns up empty most of the time because it seems many tourists get one and then camp on their bike for the rest of the day or their stay.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Racism at the border, or not so Schengen after all</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/03/racism-at-the-border-or-not-so-schengen-after-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2012 15:22:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3450</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The train just had its stop in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bad_Bentheim&#34;&gt;Bad Bentheim&lt;/a&gt; entering Germany. At that stop we usually get a short break, a new locomotive and the German border police checking the train. Border police? Didn&amp;rsquo;t the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schengen_Agreement&#34;&gt;Schengen Agreement&lt;/a&gt; abolish checks at the signing countries&amp;rsquo; borders?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It did, but these informal spot checks are still being held by some countries. Even worse, they are not random by any degree. The German Bundespolizei deliberately checks those with a dark skin and hardly any others. Normally such an observation could be attributed to me being cynical. Here it unfortunately cannot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dutch Train Times are open</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2011/04/dutch-train-times-are-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 14:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2548</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years after &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/op-radio-online-tegen-de-ns/&#34;&gt;I harrangued the Dutch national railways&lt;/a&gt; on radio about their closed data policy and &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/04/een-soort-van-antwoord-van-de-ns/&#34;&gt;debunked all their arguments&lt;/a&gt; why they would not open up this data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ns.nl&#34;&gt;NS&lt;/a&gt; opened up their data via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ns.nl/cs/Satellite/reizigers/api&#34;&gt;an official API&lt;/a&gt;. And one of the first applications is &lt;a href=&#34;http://kubus.mailspool.nl/spoorkaart/&#34;&gt;this live train map of the Netherlands&lt;/a&gt; which is just wonderful. It simply exposes something that we knew implicitly and displays it very fluently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just one of the many open data dominoes falling this year, but a very nice one and yes it looks like victory is within our grasp.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A more messy city</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2011/03/a-more-messy-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 16:07:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2464</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We spent last weekend having &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/5496175719/&#34;&gt;a veritable blast&lt;/a&gt; at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://cognitivecities.com/&#34;&gt;Cognitive Cities&lt;/a&gt; conference. It was a great spectacle of familiar faces, a nicely curated program and full frontal confrontations with the city of Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cannot stress enough how much I enjoyed Cognitive Cities. It was crammed with beautifully designed views onto the city and a chance to catchup with old friends from all over Europe. The Copenhagen crew were present, &lt;a href=&#34;http://reboot.dk&#34;&gt;Rebooters&lt;/a&gt; came back from withdrawal and we could congratulate &lt;a href=&#34;http://yourneighbours.de/&#34;&gt;Your Neighbours&lt;/a&gt; and Third Wave with their tremendous success in organizing such a conference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tekst NRC.next-artikel openbaar vervoersgegevens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/10/tekst-nrc-next-artikel-openbaar-vervoersgegevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2010 05:16:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2253</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stukjes schrijven zonder hyperlinks erin is gek, maar dat komt erbij kijken als het op krantenpapier gedrukt moet worden. In ieder geval is vandaag een stuk van mij gepubliceerd op de opinie-pagina van de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nrcnext.nl/&#34;&gt;nrc.next: “Dat moet toch beter kunnen? — Geef vervoersinformatie vrij&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In dat stuk betoog ik dat de gegevens van het openbaar vervoer vrij beschikbaar moeten zijn voor reizigers. Dit is onderdeel van een langer &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/index.php?s=openbaar+vervoer&#34;&gt;thema op dit blog&lt;/a&gt; en van een recente ontwikkeling voor &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/index.php?s=open+data&#34;&gt;open data in de breedste zin&lt;/a&gt; van het woord.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gone fishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/10/gone-fishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2010 15:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2206</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time you&amp;rsquo;re reading this I will have flown off to the Levant to spend three weeks mainly in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Damascus&#34;&gt;Damascus&lt;/a&gt;, Syria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Update frequency here and work/weeknotes will be very sparse depending on the weather and the network over there. Keep calm and carry on Get excited and start making things without me, I will be rejoining you on the 6th of November.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boris Bikes are made of epic win</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/09/boris-bikes-are-made-of-epic-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Sep 2010 15:56:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2069</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I had my yearly trip to the UK to attend the dConstruct conference in Brighton. Usually I add some time to visit London too and explore the things that need exploring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year (like last) I stayed at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cristianobetta.com/&#34;&gt;Cristiano&lt;/a&gt; ((Cristiano&amp;rsquo;s project &lt;a href=&#34;https://minutebox.com/&#34;&gt;Minutebox&lt;/a&gt; won an award while I was staying there. Check it out!)) and &lt;a href=&#34;http://missgeeky.com/&#34;&gt;Melinda&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; place near Canada Water but contrary to last year, Cristiano equipped me with all the material necessary for a roving &lt;a href=&#34;http://speedbird.wordpress.com/?s=networked+urbanism&#34;&gt;networked urbanist&lt;/a&gt;. I got to borrow his MiFi and his &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tfl.gov.uk/roadusers/cycling/14808.aspx&#34;&gt;Barclays Cycle Hire&lt;/a&gt; key and it made a ridiculous amount of difference. So much so that I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;ll want to travel any other way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Design Mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/08/design-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2010 15:18:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2030</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From slide 47 on is the core of &lt;a href=&#34;http://janchipchase.com/2010/08/design-mind-shanghai/&#34;&gt;this presentation by Jan Chipchase&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;challenge assumptions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;generate concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;evaluate concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;segmentation and brand strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/janchip/design-mind-speaker-series-shanghai&#34; title=&#34;Design Mind Speaker Series, Shanghai&#34;&gt;Design Mind Speaker Series, Shanghai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View more &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/&#34;&gt;presentations&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/janchip&#34;&gt;Jan Chipchase&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking forward to when either the Design Mind or Mr. Chipchase make their way to the low countries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GVB clusterfuck</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/07/gvb-clusterfuck/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2010 11:20:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1993</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Terwijl we aan de andere kant een strijd voeren voor vrij beschikbare openbaar vervoersinformatie is het openbaar vervoer zelf in een ‘wereldstad’ als Amsterdam nog een zooitje.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Op dit moment is de hele metrolijn van Amstel naar Centraal dicht vanwege onderhoud aan de roltrappen (!). Dat is op zich al WTF. Nog erger is dat er ruzie is tussen een aannemer en de gemeente en dat daardoor de metro volgende zomer weer dicht moet (( &lt;em&gt;If you fuck us, we will fuck you fifty times over&lt;/em&gt; lijkt mij het devies.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turks-Syrische herontdekking</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/07/turks-syrische-herontdekking/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2010 09:22:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1982</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De grens tussen Turkije en Syrië is tegenwoordig compleet open en Turkije ‘groeit uit zijn voegen’ ((Wat nou Eurozone…)):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aleppo is maar een half uurtje rijden over de grens en een totaal andere wereld. Samen met de bouw en handel die toenemen zal nu het toerisme waarschijnlijk ook groeien. Voorbij is het ongerepte Syrië waar ik &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/index.php?s=syri%C3%AB&#34;&gt;drie jaar geleden&lt;/a&gt; met wat kunst en vliegwerk in kon reizen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goed wel, maar toch een beetje jammer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hangjongeren</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/06/1917/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2010 17:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1917</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jelle Brandt Corstius &lt;em&gt;nailt&lt;/em&gt; het:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik had een Russische vriendin op bezoek, en we waren beland in een visrestaurant in een pittoresk Noord-Hollands kustplaatsje waar ik vaak kom. Nouja, pittoresk, op het centrale plein van het kustplaatsje komen regelmatig hangjongeren samen die bier zuipen en heel hard Heil Hitler! roepen. Maar het zijn geen Marokkanen, dus ze kunnen kun gang gaan. Ik ben helemaal voor het harder aanpakken van hangjongeren, maar dan wel alle hangjongeren. Maar dat terzijde. ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://mightymoscow.blogspot.com/2010/06/jelle-krijgt-een-telefoontje-van-de.html&#34;&gt;Mighty Moscow&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Toename in veiligheid door de ov-chipkaart</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/03/toename-in-veiligheid-door-de-ov-chipkaart/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2010 15:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1606</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De OV-chipkaart is een groot succes in de Amsterdamse metro. Het aantal zwartrijders is afgenomen en navenant ook het aantal geweldsincidenten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mooi en nog meer onbegrip voor de mensen die tegen de ov-chipkaart zijn. Hij mag nog wel verbeterd worden, maar de waarde van de chipkaart is nu duidelijk bewezen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De GVB zegt in de pers dat het niet mogelijk is om de harde kern van zwartrijders aan te pakken. Ik denk meer dat het een kwestie is van niet willen of dat de kosten niet opwegen tegen de baten. Het is de vraag in hoeverre je de kieren dicht van een veiligheidssysteem.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year in Cities 2009</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/01/year-in-cities-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2010 14:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1471</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://novemberborn.net/2009/12/my-year-in-cities-2009-347&#34;&gt;that time&lt;/a&gt; of the year again, a modest list this time compared to &lt;a href=&#34;http://annevankesteren.nl/&#34;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;London, and again in September for &lt;a href=&#34;http://dConstruct.org&#34;&gt;dConstruct&lt;/a&gt;, crashing at &lt;a href=&#34;http://cristianobetta.com/&#34;&gt;Cristiano&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://missgeeky.com/&#34;&gt;Melinda&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Austin, first visit to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sxsw.com/&#34;&gt;SxSWi&lt;/a&gt;, definitely not the last&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copenhagen, yearly &lt;a href=&#34;http://reboot.dk&#34;&gt;Reboot&lt;/a&gt;, this time crashing at &lt;a href=&#34;http://novemberborn.net&#34;&gt;Mark&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s awesome place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amsterdam&lt;/strong&gt;, moving house over from Delft finally!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casablanca, flying in and out with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.airarabia.com/&#34;&gt;Air Arabia&lt;/a&gt; on this Morrocan holiday&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rabat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marrakech&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Agadir&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essaouira&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope to travel more in this coming year. Austin, Copenhagen and Brighton are definitely in again. A new visit to the Middle East is in order and a big trip.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Het gebrek aan kaizen in het openbaar vervoer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/12/het-gebrek-aan-kaizen-in-het-openbaar-vervoer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 11:29:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1451</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik schreef hier al eerder dat &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/12/ov-chipkaart-ellende/&#34;&gt;de ov-chipkaart kut&lt;/a&gt; ((Excusez le mot, maar er is geen ander wat de lading zo goed dekt.)) is. Het is nog steeds kut.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trage-poortjes&#34;&gt;Trage poortjes&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hier moet ik even een filmpje van schieten om het voelbaar te maken. Er staan tijdens de spits rijen voor de poortjes. Op station Amstel blokkeren groepen mensen de roltrappen boven op de perrons omdat ze daar in- en uitchecken (wat niet de bedoeling is). En de poortjes zijn gewoonweg niet snel genoeg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NextMuni â€” Wanneer komt de volgende tram?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/12/nextmuni-%E2%80%94-wanneer-komt-de-volgende-tram/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 11:24:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1428</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De vervoersmaatschappij van San Francisco geeft &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sfmta.com/cms/asite/nextmunidata.htm&#34;&gt;de voorspelde aankomsttijd&lt;/a&gt; van het volgende voertuig op een willekeurige halte vrij in een handig XML-formaat. Daarmee kun je leuke dingen bouwen, zoals bijvoorbeeld &lt;a href=&#34;http://headwayblog.com/2009/12/14/telling-time-with-openrealtime-data/&#34;&gt;een horloge wat de volgende tram&lt;/a&gt; aangeeft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gvb.nl/reizigers/Pages/vertrektijden.aspx&#34;&gt;In Amsterdam leven we&lt;/a&gt; in vergelijking nog in de Middeleeuwen. Daar zit ik buiten de Coffee Company in de vrieskou mijn espresso te drinken om de lijn 4 aan te kunnen zien komen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In gerelateerd nieuws: gegeven goede data, kun je ook hele vette displays maken. Zoals &lt;a href=&#34;http://alexbogusky.posterous.com/deep-in-the-bowels-of-cpb-0&#34;&gt;dit live project-overzicht bij een bureau&lt;/a&gt; op een muur geprojecteerd.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OV-chipkaart: kansen voor verbetering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/12/ov-chipkaart-ellende/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2009 18:21:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1396</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik ben eenduidig voor de ov-chipkaart. De cognitieve moeite die het bespaart bij het reizen in het openbaar vervoer (temminste als je simpele routes gebruikt en niet overstapt op de trein) is geweldig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maar er zijn toch nog wel genoeg irritaties. Dus ik ben voor de ov-chipkaart maar ik ben zeker ook voor een &lt;strong&gt;betere&lt;/strong&gt; ov-chipkaart dan dat we nu hebben. In de implementatie hebben de ontwerpers van het systeem de bal grof laten vallen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reisadvies ov moet beter</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/11/reisadvies-ov-moet-beter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2009 22:25:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1372</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik zou zeggen “duh!”, maar je kunt net zo goed zeggen dat dit een revolutie inluidt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;105-01.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Reisadvies ov moet beter&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/11/reisadvies-ov-moet-beter/105-01.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Heel vet. Laten we zien wat er gebeurt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gone surfing, come back later</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/10/gone-surfing-come-back-later/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2009 17:04:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1367</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time you&amp;rsquo;re reading this I&amp;rsquo;ll be on a brief &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/trip/alper/923013&#34;&gt;holiday to Morocco&lt;/a&gt; to surf and eat local cuisine. It&amp;rsquo;s been too long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/grace_land/3252307148/&#34; title=&#34;Untitled by Graceź, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3528/3252307148_434b038930.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-nd/2.0/deed.en_GB&#34;&gt;CC&lt;/a&gt; picture by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/grace_land/&#34;&gt;Grace Oda&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>City Hopping</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/10/city-hopping/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2009 05:58:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1321</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Jumping all over the randstad these past weeks. Some gems to be found:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/4031842083/&#34; title=&#34;Neude by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Neude&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3544/4031842083_97c4dd5838_b.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shared bicycle transit systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/09/shared-bicycle-transit-systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 22:16:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1245</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recently used my first &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ov-fiets.nl/&#34;&gt;OV-fiets&lt;/a&gt; and it was a fantastic experience ((The fact that I used it to bike out to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3919129087/&#34;&gt;a theater festival&lt;/a&gt; in a nature reserve may have contributed to that.)). It&amp;rsquo;s a great way to bridge the last couple of miles on your transit experience and I think an important addition to the public transportation system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/silvertje/3033788593/&#34; title=&#34;half uur eerder dan de planning by Anne Helmond, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;half uur eerder dan de planning&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3064/3033788593_235a4b6c3f.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
CC picture by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.annehelmond.nl/&#34;&gt;Anne Helmond&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nooit meer met de trein naar Londen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/09/nooit-meer-met-de-trein-naar-londen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2009 11:00:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1206</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik denk niet dat ik binnenkort nog met de trein naar Londen ga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het is al niet de meest aantrekkelijke propositie. Van Amsterdam naar London St. Pancras kost je toch een uur of zes en een half ((Tijdsverschil niet meegerekend.)). De treinen hebben geen stroomaansluitingen, dus je kunt niet voluit laptoppen. Verder moet je uiterlijk een half uur van tevoren op Brussel inchecken, anders mag je niet mee.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waarom doen we het dan? Treinreizen heeft iets fijns, het is continu met minder wachten en veiligheidsmaatregelen dan je hebt als je vliegt én je komt middenin Londen uit in plaats van op een vliegveld ergens in een buitenwijk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nationale Databank Wegverkeersgegevens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/07/nationaal-databank-wegverkeersgegevens/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2009 11:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1112</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Via &lt;a href=&#34;http://gvenkdaily.nl&#34;&gt;Gerard&lt;/a&gt; het nieuws over het &lt;a href=&#34;http://tweakers.net/nieuws/61095/nationale-databank-wegverkeersgegevens-moet-fileleed-verminderen.html&#34;&gt;NDW dat geopend is door Minister Eurlings&lt;/a&gt;. Het eerste resultaat is een warrige site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nationaaldatawarehouse.nl/&#34;&gt;Nationaaldatawarehouse.nl&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het lijkt me boeiend om de intensiteit van het wegverkeer in Nederland globaal te visualiseren, en het lijkt erop dat het NDW die gegevens beheert en aanbiedt. Nergens op de site is te vinden hoe je dan als potentiele afnemer aan die gegevens komt. Wellicht zijn hier marktpartijen hier —zoals wel vaker— nauw gedefinieerd als een soort ons-kent-ons clubje waar men elkaar wél weet te vinden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebooted</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/07/rebooted/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2009 09:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1090</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I got Rebooted in Copenhagen again. Drove up with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3676235876/in/set-72157620636875097/&#34;&gt;Peter&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3676238350/in/set-72157620636875097/&#34;&gt;Iskander&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3676261680/&#34; title=&#34;Mark by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Mark&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2561/3676261680_01525482aa_m.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After your fourth time attending such a great and small conference as Reboot, it becomes familiar like a reunion. This year&amp;rsquo;s action theme meaned the two days were completely packed. There was so much to do and so much going on that the first day was over already before you knew it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing that struck me as being odd was the fact that many speakers on the large stage weren&amp;rsquo;t asked any questions (I had one or two for Richard Falkvinge). If anything, Reboot does not strike me as an event where one person can rain down the gospel unquestioned. So for a next time more interactive maybe even adversarial formats may be nice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ramen open in het openbaar vervoer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/05/ramen-open-in-het-openbaar-vervoer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2009 15:35:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=989</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dennis &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/naquah/status/1837494417&#34;&gt;tipte&lt;/a&gt; me net deze video:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het is een beetje warrig maar wat &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/vincente&#34;&gt;Vincent Everts&lt;/a&gt; zegt is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik denk dat als eerste stap om de ramen open te doen en te zeggen laten we samenwerken aan producten, hier heb je mijn basis-API maak er iets moois van. Ik denk dat dat veel verder doorgegaan moet worden en dat die API die jullie nu hebben waarmee iedereen dus een basisvervoersadvies kan krijgen en dat kun je dan zelf verrijken, dat dat een hele goede weg is en ik denk dat 9292 ook verder moet doorzetten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Een soort van antwoord van de NS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/04/een-soort-van-antwoord-van-de-ns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 22:11:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=899</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik vernam al dat de NS op de afgelopen Mobile Monday probeerde hun nieuwe reisplanner te pitchen. Dat was afgaand op &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.twitter.com/search?q=momo+ns&#34;&gt;de reacties via Twitter&lt;/a&gt; geen doorslaand succes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zojuist op de &lt;a href=&#34;http://gvenkdaily.nl/&#34;&gt;gvenkdaily&lt;/a&gt; ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gvenkdaily/status/1430051480&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gvenkdaily/status/1430057131&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gvenkdaily/status/1430062685&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/gvenkdaily/status/1430067592&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;) wat referenties naar verslaggeving over dit onderwerp en fragmentarisch de argumenten waarom de NS weigert hun gegevens open te gooien.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/op-radio-online-tegen-de-ns/&#34;&gt;schreef hier eerder al over&lt;/a&gt; en mensen vragen steeds aan mÃ­j waarom de NS de gegevens niet zou willen vrijgeven. Niemand snapt het en de meeste mensen vinden het onvoorstelbaar dat de NS puur uit eigenbelang de gegevens voor zich zou willen houden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Op Radio Online tegen de NS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/op-radio-online-tegen-de-ns/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2009 16:54:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=865</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.radio-online.nl/pivot/entry.php?id=1836&#34;&gt;gisteren dus op Radio Online&lt;/a&gt; ((Ik mocht het van tevoren niet echt Twitteren wat ik toch een beetje gek vind.)) ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://cgi.omroep.nl/cgi-bin/streams?/radio1/tros/radioonline/20090321-17.wma?start=25:21&#34;&gt;audio&lt;/a&gt;) waar ik &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/de-ns-spant-het-paard-achter-de-trein/&#34;&gt;een kritiek&lt;/a&gt; mocht uiten tegen de strategie van de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ns.nl&#34;&gt;NS&lt;/a&gt; van het niet vrijgeven van de vervoersgegevens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corine van Drunen van de NS laat het na om in te gaan op de vragen die gesteld werden en maak zich er daarna van af door te verwijzen naar het feit dat de NS haar planmatige gegevens ter beschikking stelt aan 9292ov. 9292 is een gezamenlijke site van de vervoerders waar de gegevens in een bepaalde vorm worden ontsloten maar die niet een herbruikbare toegang tot vervoersgegevens biedt. Daarnaast zou het handig zijn om de dynamische reisgegevens (de actuele posities van vervoersmiddelen) te hebben maar in eerste instantie zouden we al blij zijn met de planmatige gegevens.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SxSWi Conference Highlights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/sxswi-conference-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 20:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=843</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a list of some of my favorite things from SxSW:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kicking it with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://wakoopa.com&#34;&gt;Wakoopa&lt;/a&gt; guys who I shared a room with. Nice to hang around with a Dutch crew and some crazy stuff happening in the nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very interesting to see how people would behave in an environment ((The convention center was big enough to be an environment unto itself.)) with adequate bandwidth and Twitter saturation. As noted &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/alper/status/1332041897&#34;&gt;in&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/alper/status/1332156377&#34;&gt;tweets&lt;/a&gt; the immediacy of social interaction with your social subset, the people aimlessly wandering the corridors absorbed by their mobile displays and the HUGE backchannel were just symptoms of more to come.
For us Europeans attending an event such as this without a data plan is somewhat annoying ((Wasn&amp;rsquo;t there a cheap international data roaming plan somewhere?)). After leaving the convention center, &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wardriving&#34;&gt;war walking&lt;/a&gt; will only get you so far.
Also the realization that you don&amp;rsquo;t need a laptop or a DSLR (thanks &lt;a href=&#34;http://powazek.com/posts/1846&#34;&gt;Derek&lt;/a&gt;!) to enjoy a conference was a golden one. An iPhone, a charger and a small notebook will do just fine and won&amp;rsquo;t wear you down as much. Most of the time you&amp;rsquo;ll be busy talking to people at parties, walking around or eating, which does not require you to lug a complete digital office with you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De NS spant het paard achter de trein</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/de-ns-spant-het-paard-achter-de-trein/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2009 16:08:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=835</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Een &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketingfacts.nl/berichten/20090318_ns_reisinformatie_nieuwe_stijl_met_videoreview/&#34;&gt;redelijk zachte review&lt;/a&gt; van de nieuwe NS-applicatie op Marketingfacts (ook &lt;a href=&#34;http://tweakers.net/nieuws/59093/ns-wil-iphone-en-blackberry-reisplanner-maken-update.html&#34;&gt;Tweakers&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reisinformatie ‘nieuwe stijl’ is ook maar een woord om te verhullen dat de manier van informatie aanbieden die de NS hanteert jaren achterloopt en dat ze zelfs actief mensen die zelf dit niveau proberen op te schroeven &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.marketingfacts.nl/berichten/20081014_ns_moet_niet_zeuren_om_trein_app/&#34;&gt;zoals Trein.app het verhinderen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De reis app die door de NS uitgebracht is werkt op Java wat mobiel niet het handigste platform is en waar ook niet de interessantste gebruikers zich bevinden. Versies voor iPhone en anderen schijnen nog te komen, maar deze versie heeft al een jaar op zich laten wachten, dus wanneer is erg onduidelijk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Away from office</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/03/away-from-office/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2009 08:00:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=830</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik ben even een weekje naar &lt;a href=&#34;http://sxsw.com/interactive/&#34;&gt;Austin&lt;/a&gt; voor een woestijn-retraite met vakgenoten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; SxSW is met gemak één van de beste algemene events waar ik geweest ben. De hoeveelheid en in sommige gevallen kwaliteit van de sessies dragen daaraan bij, maar nog veel belangrijker is de concentratie van mensen die hier aanwezig is.
Er is een absurde hoge concentratie hier van mensen die werken in ons vakgebied, dit maakt spontane en geplande ontmoetingen erg waarschijnlijk en is de voornaamste reden om hierheen te komen (het is toch niet mogelijk om alle sessies te zien en ze worden ook opgenomen en binnenkort online gezet).
Absolute aanrader dus als je Engels kunt en zelfredzaam bent. We zijn nu al met een recordaantal Nederlanders hier maar ik denk dat dat aantal nog een paar keer moet verdubbelen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My year in cities, 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/01/my-year-in-cities-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 13:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=722</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kottke.org/08/12/my-year-in-cities-2008&#34;&gt;per Kottke&lt;/a&gt; fished out of my iCal and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/traveller/alper/public&#34;&gt;my Dopplr&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://novemberborn.net/life/year-in-cities-2008&#34;&gt;hat tip Mark&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Berlinâˆ—&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amsterdamâˆ—&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;London&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copenhagen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nantes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meppel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;San Franciscoâˆ—&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oakland&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It could be debated whether &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Meppel&#34;&gt;Meppel&lt;/a&gt; is a city or not, but I&amp;rsquo;ll let it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Light formations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/12/light-formations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2008 00:05:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=714</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Occasionally some very beautiful things here in Berlin between the grey and cold (( &lt;em&gt;Beirut — In the Mausoleum:&lt;/em&gt;[…] And Berlin // is so ugly in the morning light)):&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Twin Peaks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/10/twin-peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2008 23:10:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=564</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last day in San Francisco we went up to Twin Peaks for this absolutely stunning view over the city:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2983607115/&#34; title=&#34;Night Time View by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Night Time View&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3032/2983607115_e3bb48dc00.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great way to end a first visit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adjustments</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/10/adjustments/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2008 09:26:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=559</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Freshly one day back in from San Francisco some adjustments need to be made. The time difference has been reduced from 9 hours to 8 thanks to our splendidly &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Daylight_Savings_Time#Origin&#34;&gt;European invention&lt;/a&gt;: DST. Along with the time difference there is also a slight difference in daylight and a large difference in temperature (15ź centigrade) and precipitation (nearly non-stop rain the past day).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2980038537/&#34; title=&#34;Last view by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Last view&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3269/2980038537_f802bb9483.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adjusting to the superficials will be easy enough, but as after every big trip and after having seem some truly splendid natural and metropolitan vistas, adjusting the mind to a realignment of the world brought about by new experience will be somewhat more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Current affairs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/10/current-affairs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 06:29:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=557</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My days in Berkeley/Oakland ((About which more later.)) used to be filled with:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2963055773/&#34; title=&#34;Mestre Acordeon by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Mestre Acordeon&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3230/2963055773_0d5ce18c78.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And now my days are filled with:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2962972519/&#34; title=&#34;Shore by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Shore&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3029/2962972519_4c7e1ca90c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2962951457/&#34; title=&#34;Golden Gate Bridge by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Golden Gate Bridge&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3236/2962951457_4eb978e44c.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2962994359/&#34; title=&#34;Fog by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Fog&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3142/2962994359_3fc4958eed.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2963001557/&#34; title=&#34;Sunset by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Sunset&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3213/2963001557_9dfb9a2f32.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow it&amp;rsquo;s back to the city and doing some last things before flying back early Sunday morning.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>San Francisco</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/10/san-francisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 00:37:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=544</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to go there and tomorrow I&amp;rsquo;m finally going. Some vague plans, tads of serendipity and friends pushing me over the edge were enough to have me book the ticket, I think, only three weeks ago. Tomorrow Lufthansa will take me over an ocean for the first time of my life ((Pretty lame for somebody who likes to travel.)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halfway during the trip there&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.capoeiraarts.com/batizado/index.html&#34;&gt;four day capoeira event&lt;/a&gt; celebrating &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mestre_Acordeon&#34;&gt;Mestre Acordeon&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s fiftieth year of teaching capoeira with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.capoeiraarts.com/brazilfest/index.html&#34;&gt;a Brazilian festival in Berkeley&lt;/a&gt; on Saturday. I&amp;rsquo;ll also try to get some surfing in and see if I can visit the local tech hubs and meet some people, so it&amp;rsquo;s not purely a holiday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily life in Ð¡Ð¾Ñ„Ð¸Ñ</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/08/daily-life-in-%D1%81%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2008 21:19:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=365</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to have friends who are pushing their bounds photographically to try and improve their skill and to see them improve leaps and bounds as a result of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One such friend is Mony and &lt;a href=&#34;http://straboh.uber.com/blogs/Release_a_set_of_photographs_of_Sofia_on_Flickr.html&#34;&gt;during his yearly holiday&lt;/a&gt; ((Or should I say pilgrimage.)) to Bulgaria he has produced a very nice set of street photography out of Sofia:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/straboh/2717457190/in/set-72157606560417919&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3256/2717457190_71ae8027c4_d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Picture by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/people/straboh/&#34;&gt;Mony Nedkov&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/straboh/sets/72157606560417919/&#34;&gt;the set Sofia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me it&amp;rsquo;s of particular interest to see pictures of a city neighboring my love Istanbul. I have just &lt;a href=&#34;http://bighugelabs.com/flickr/onblack.php?id=1356161009&#34;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; picture I would call a good street photography shot. The effort it takes to get even halfway decent shots is staggering.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Socio-locational disconnection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/07/socio-locational-disconnection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 11:26:42 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=323</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been tremendously enjoying &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.janchipchase.com/&#34;&gt;the stuff Jan Chipchase writes&lt;/a&gt; on his blog both current and digging deep into his archives ((Back to a time when comments were still allowed on his blog.)). A dream job if ever there was one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.janchipchase.com/shared-location-awareness&#34;&gt;current piece&lt;/a&gt; is especially pertinent as the iPhone 3G release with builtin GPS and accompanied unlimited data plans will herald the location based revolution. Many of my friends say that they do not want to broadcast where they are and know where their friends are most of the time. That they would rather get together using premediated consensual communication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Normal service</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/07/normal-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jul 2008 11:15:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=322</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back from holiday, the surf was mostly flat but a good time was had, judging from the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/&#34;&gt;pictures on Flickr&lt;/a&gt; ((Still sorting through the bunch from Apremont and Nantes.)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2704482088/&#34; title=&#34;Distant by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Distant&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3018/2704482088_0e4210e1ac.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal service will resume here at least until half of August when I will break shortly for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dopplr.com/trip/alper/236146&#34;&gt;Wapsen&lt;/a&gt; and maybe thereafter a bit longer for the former Yugoslavia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10th Reboot - day 2 and on</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/07/10th-reboot-day-2-and-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2008 14:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=319</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2627216575/&#34; title=&#34;Jerry by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Jerry&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3063/2627216575_d14945bbc7.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second day started off with a talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reboot.dk/artefact-5420-en.html&#34;&gt;Free by Jerry Michalski&lt;/a&gt; which reminded me a lot of the topics that I had covered the previous day in my talk. Jerry&amp;rsquo;s talk being in the main hall made this turn out a lot differently than my talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2627217363/&#34; title=&#34;David by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;David&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3020/2627217363_dcde3d1340.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Recordon followed with a talk &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reboot.dk/artefact-5417-en.html&#34;&gt;about the open web&lt;/a&gt; and reminded us that not that much has changed in the last six months since I saw him on the same topic in Berlin. The big social conglomerates that have each other in a chokehold make for glacial progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10th Reboot - day 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/06/10th-reboot-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 22:54:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=317</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://reboot.dk&#34;&gt;Reboot 10&lt;/a&gt; is over and in my experience they simply get better every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d signed up for a session and got slotted on Thursday morning so I spent a good part of Wednesday preparing and running through the story. Of course after having gotten over &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/06/off-to-copenhagen/&#34;&gt;my early flight&lt;/a&gt; and having eaten something at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thelaundromatcafe.com/&#34;&gt;Laundromat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My session on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reboot.dk/artefact-5148-en.html&#34;&gt;Free Economics&lt;/a&gt; was filled over capacity while it was meant to be a cosy conversational session. Fortunately that also meant more than enough people willing to participate and add information, so I think it went well and it proved a good starting point for the rest of the conference. My stress relieved could follow the rest of the sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Off to Copenhagen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/06/off-to-copenhagen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jun 2008 00:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=316</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the time this post has been published I will be on a train on my way to Schiphol to fly to Copenhagen to attend the 10th edition of &lt;a href=&#34;http://reboot.dk&#34;&gt;Reboot&lt;/a&gt; ((my third)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copenhagen has become familiar territory and I&amp;rsquo;ll be there for only four days. Acclimatizing on Wednesday which kicks off with a boat trip. Thursday and Friday will be conference days during which I hope to see a lot of people and I have been alotted a small session where we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reboot.dk/artefact-5148-en.html&#34;&gt;Free Economies&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De wereld is kapot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/05/de-wereld-is-kapot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2008 20:14:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=296</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maar ik heb er grondige vertrouwen in dat we hem kunnen repareren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik zit nu in Londen ((De Eurostar is een leuk vervoersmiddel.)) bij &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mseckington&#34;&gt;@mseckington&lt;/a&gt; en &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/cbetta&#34;&gt;@cbetta&lt;/a&gt; op de bank na een dagje conferentie bij &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.geekyoto.com/&#34;&gt;geekyoto&lt;/a&gt; waar een hele serie mensen hun visie hebben gegeven de toestand van de wereld en hoe die te repareren. Erg inspirerend en er zijn veel mensen met goede dingen bezig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik ga nog meer schrijven maar feit is dat veel van de oplossingen geen extra techniek nodig hebben en ook niet meer kosten. Het enige wat de boel tegenhoudt is menselijke inertie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
