<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Reading on alper.nl</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reading on alper.nl</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:47:05 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/reading/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Acemoglu &amp; Robinson Critique on Piketty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-acemoglu-robinson-critique-on-piketty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Dec 2025 23:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5029</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this paper right after I read the book by Piketty thinking that there would be some interesting economic debate. Unfortunately I was proved wrong and this seems to be exemplary of the stagnation of the economic field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of my thinking on the paper has been confirmed by this post: &lt;a href=&#34;http://glineq.blogspot.nl/2014/08/my-take-on-acemoglu-robinson-critique.html&#34;&gt;http://glineq.blogspot.nl/2014/08/my-take-on-acemoglu-robinson-critique.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18085/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:40:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18085</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a Marxist who understands the importance of money and markets; without Marx, you cannot understand the movement of history, but without money, you can’t do anything about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all, times are changing, and we have to change with them, and if we don’t we’ll die, which is completely normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are companies and organizations that are very interested in ideas and culture and are very willing to support projects related to these themes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/18172/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2025 08:51:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=18172</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wasn&amp;rsquo;t it the CEO of META going around telling everybody that free speech was the most important thing at the moment?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/legal/meta-wins-halt-promotion-careless-people-tell-all-book-by-former-employee-2025-03-13&#34;&gt;https://www.reuters.com/legal/meta-wins-halt-promotion-careless-people-tell-all-book-by-former-employee-2025-03-13&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17917/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 08:44:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17917</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Agents chapter from Chip Huyen&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;AI Engineering&amp;rdquo; is clear and enjoyable to read. She&amp;rsquo;s right that &amp;ldquo;the concept of an agent is fairly simple&amp;rdquo; but building something functional still looks like a massive lift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://huyenchip.com/2025/01/07/agents.html&#34;&gt;https://huyenchip.com/2025/01/07/agents.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17899/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 13:57:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17899</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s rare to find writing in German as lithe and delightful as what Christoph Rauscher puts out. The monthly lists are &lt;a href=&#34;https://christowski.de/blog/2024/12/dezember-liste-2024/&#34;&gt;one particularly good example&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m learning new and interesting words still in most of his pieces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I totally agree that &amp;ldquo;Writing = Design&amp;rdquo; and you should hire him for Design/Writing/Illustration: &lt;a href=&#34;https://christophrauscher.de/writing/&#34;&gt;https://christophrauscher.de/writing/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://christowski.de/blog/2024/12/dezember-liste-2024/&#34;&gt;https://christowski.de/blog/2024/12/dezember-liste-2024/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17879/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 06:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17879</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.02830&#34;&gt;RARE: Retrieval-Augmented Reasoning Enhancement for Large Language Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical QA depends heavily on domain-specific knowledge that is not always available within pre-trained models, necessitating knowledge-based retrieval from external sources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition medical knowledge evolves rapidly, and new treatments or updated guidelines may not be included in the model&amp;rsquo;s pertained corpus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question example for the reasoning process in Figure 1 is on a multiple-choice question. That seems overly simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In parallel, Commonsense Question Answering shares similar complexities with Medical QA, particularly in its reliance on structured multi-step reasoning and iterative evidence retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year in Review 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/year-in-review-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 17:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17872</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a bit of a grab bag year but overall not as bad as 2023 and a bunch of things seem to be on track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;health&#34;&gt;Health&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got on the neurodiversity bandwagon this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First I got myself a self-paid diagnosis for ADHD. This result should not surprise anybody who knows me. I&amp;rsquo;ve forced myself to be very high functioning throughout my life but it can&amp;rsquo;t be denied that there were always some underlying issues. I&amp;rsquo;m on medication from the end of the year and have gone off caffeine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17854/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:10:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17854</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hans de Zwart&amp;rsquo;s end of the year media overviews are one of the highlights of what still happens on personal blogs for me. He&amp;rsquo;s a voracious reader and one of the rare people who acts on his moral clarity. Also, Hans is a great guy and I had the chance to briefly catch-up with him last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll see if I can pull something together, but definitely go through his list. I always pick up more than a couple of interesting things to explore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17833/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 07:17:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17833</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.00412&#34;&gt;Adapting While Learning: Grounding LLMs for Scientific Problems with Intelligent Tool Usage Adaptation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A paper where they fine tune an LLM to be able to answer some questions itself and figure out for which questions it needs to use a specialized tool. Intelligent tool usage seems like it would expand the use cases for LLM driven systems much more than any kind of scaling (real or imagined).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, scholars note that their abilities are capped at approximately high-school levels&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17831/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 14:23:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17831</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2209.07663&#34;&gt;Monolith: Real Time Recommendation System With Collisionless Embedding Table&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t get that much from this paper, probably because it&amp;rsquo;s pretty high level and I don&amp;rsquo;t have a strong background in recommendation systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approach is their Cuckoo Hashmap for embedding from which they can update parameters on the fly using existing data engineering pipeline technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of reading mini-batch examples from the storage, a training worker consumes realtime data on-the-fly and updates the training PS. The training PS periodically syn- chronizes its parameters to the serving PS, which will take effect on the user side immediately. This enables our model to interactively adapt itself according to a user’s feedback in realtime.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17829/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:17:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17829</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/abs/2304.00612&#34;&gt;Eight Things to Know about Large Language Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A bunch of stuff that maybe was somewhat surprising a year ago but by now should be common knowledge for anybody even half following the developments in this field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting bits in there but for the rest it&amp;rsquo;s a bit rah-rah because the author works at Anthropic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In particular, models can misinterpret ambiguous prompts or incentives in unreason- able ways, including in situations that appear unambiguous to humans, leading them to behave unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Witches Kitchen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/witchs-kitchen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Dec 2024 20:22:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17819</guid> 
      <description>&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;CleanShot-2024-12-27-at-21.16.15@2x.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ams.org/notices/200410/fea-grothendieck-part2.pdf&#34;&gt;the Grothendieck biography&lt;/a&gt;, funny to see that the legend would express himself in German.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riemann-Roch&amp;rsquo;scher Satz: der letzte Schrei: der Diagramm […] ist kommutatif!&lt;br&gt;
Um dieser Aussage über f:X-&amp;gt;Y einen approximativen Sinn zu geben, musste ich nahezu zwei Stunden lang die Geduld der Zuhörer missbrauchen. Schwartz auf weiss (in Springer Lecture Notes) nimmt&amp;rsquo;s wohl an die 400,500 Seiten.&lt;br&gt;
Ein packendes Beispiel dafür, wie unser Wissens und Entdeckungsdrang sich immer mehr in einem lebensentrückten logischen Delirium auslebt, während das Lebens selbst auf Tausendfache Art zum Teufel geht – und mit endgültiger Vernichtung bedroht ist. Höchste Zeit unsern Kurs zu ändern!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17809/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17809</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1706.03762&#34;&gt;Attention Is All You Need&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;rsquo;d dive back into history and read the original paper that started it all. It&amp;rsquo;s somewhat technical about encode/decoder layouts and matrix multiplications. None of the components are super exciting for somebody who&amp;rsquo;s been looking at neural networks for the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s exciting is that such a simplification generates results that are &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; much better and how they came up with it. Unfortunately, they don&amp;rsquo;t write how they found this out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17805/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:12:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17805</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2305.10601&#34;&gt;Tree of Thoughts: Deliberate Problem Solving with Large Language Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I came across this paper after the recent &lt;a href=&#34;https://arcprize.org/blog/oai-o3-pub-breakthrough&#34;&gt;o3 high score&lt;/a&gt; on the ARC-AGI-PUB test. It&amp;rsquo;s a quick read and details how to scale LLMs at inference stage by generating new states at every node and so create a tree on which to perform DFS/BFS search algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A specific instantiation of ToT involves answering four questions: 1. How to decompose the intermediate process into thought steps; 2. How to generate potential thoughts from each state; 3. How to heuristically evaluate states; 4. What search algorithm to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Discipline and Punish: The Birth of the Prison</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-discipline-and-punish-the-birth-of-the-prison/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17697</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In modern justice and on the part of those who dispense it there is a shame in punishing, which does not always preclude zeal. This sense of shame is constantly growing: the psychologists and the minor civil servants of moral orthopaedics proliferate on the wound it leaves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of insanity eliminating the crime according to the original meaning of article 64, every crime and even every offence now carries within it, as a legitimate suspicion, but also as a right that may be claimed, the hypothesis of insanity, in any case of anomaly. And the sentence that condemns or acquits is not simply a judgement of guilt, a legal decision that lays down punishment; it bears within it an assessment of normality and a technical prescription for a possible normalization. Today the judge – magistrate or juror – certainly does more than ‘judge’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Conversational Capacity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-conversational-capacity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 22:41:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17694</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll say nothing when we should speak up. We’ll quarrel when we should inquire. We’ll remain reticent when we should be resolved. We’ll be closed-minded and critical when we should be open-minded and curious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, a “little voice” in the back of his brain urged him to raise his concern; on the other hand, he didn’t want to be labeled a troublemaker, a non–team player, or a “high-maintenance” flight operations officer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>So long Ribbonfarm!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/so-long-ribbonfarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 22:06:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17683</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ribbonfarm retiring is another such ending in a time rife with them. I can&amp;rsquo;t overstate how influential it has been on my (our) thinking and practice. Tremendously impressive to think all of that was thought up by one person (who I still haven&amp;rsquo;t met).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;d be impossible to summarise all the themes, intersections and other tidbits that &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/?s=ribbonfarm&#34;&gt;I got out of Ribbonfarm&lt;/a&gt;. I can say how it begun: I was lying on the river-shore in Avignon in 2012 and I had a large part of the blog&amp;rsquo;s back catalog in my Instapaper and there I read the entire thing while listening to the crickets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17681/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 19:36:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17681</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alan Moore definitely is not wrong:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, I’m sure that fandom is sometimes a grotesque blight that poisons the society surrounding it with its mean-spirited obsessions and ridiculous, unearned sense of entitlement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/oct/26/fandom-has-toxified-the-world-watchmen-author-alan-moore-on-superheroes-comicsgate-and-trump&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2024/oct/26/fandom-has-toxified-the-world-watchmen-author-alan-moore-on-superheroes-comicsgate-and-trump&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17671/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 17:39:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17671</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for an updated edition of “Designing Data-Intensive Applications” and now I see that Kleppmann is working on it. Reading the first edition has given me such an outsized advantage when architecting and building systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://nondeterministic.computer/@martin/113039967645896991&#34;&gt;https://nondeterministic.computer/@martin/113039967645896991&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/designing-data-intensive-applications/9781098119058&#34;&gt;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/designing-data-intensive-applications/9781098119058&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17639/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:03:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17639</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wer täglich, manchmal mehrmals die Stunde, die Verdammten belächelt, ist wohl zu Recht in der Hölle. Twitter, so mussten wir uns eingestehen, war der Ort, den wir bewohnten, weil wir sehr schlechte Menschen waren.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Utterly utterly savage feuilleton about Twitter as a medium for poetry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zeit.de/2024/45/clemens-setz-twitter-gedichtband-poesie-social-media/komplettansicht&#34;&gt;https://www.zeit.de/2024/45/clemens-setz-twitter-gedichtband-poesie-social-media/komplettansicht&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17616/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17616</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Of course it takes a Dutch guy, an outsider, to blow the lid off Germany&amp;rsquo;s Nazi Bilionaires. David de Jong is doing great work and the German establishment tries to bury that as much as possible (because they know which side their bread is buttered on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/richest-german-nazi-billions&#34;&gt;https://www.vanityfair.com/news/story/richest-german-nazi-billions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17610/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17610</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A damning but also entirely correct assessment of Elon Musk:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How degrading it must be: a 53-year-old man, notionally responsible for five companies, endlessly jostling for empty, phatic interactions with strangers. A clown forced to play for an audience he despises, an audience he cannot be sure even exists, and which gains with every tasteless joke a clearer understanding of what he is really worth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newstatesman.com/culture/books/2024/09/how-elon-musk-killed-twitter&#34;&gt;https://www.newstatesman.com/culture/books/2024/09/how-elon-musk-killed-twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17527/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 17:58:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17527</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third truth is that we have a generation in crisis and in desperate need of the best of what science and evidence-based solutions can offer. Unfortunately, our time is being spent telling stories that are unsupported by research and that do little to support young people who need, and deserve, more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The experts agree that kids need to be cared for better. The experts also agree that people like Haidt are grifters who do not contribute anything into that direction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17525/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 17:54:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17525</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Herbert believed that progress was an illusion because he was an ideologically motivated reactionary who hated the New Deal, the welfare state, the Civil Rights Movement, and any political leader who promised to help the oppressed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally a piece about Dune 2 that doesn&amp;rsquo;t pull any punches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://slate.com/culture/2024/03/dune-2-movies-frank-herbert-books-meaning-differences.html&#34;&gt;https://slate.com/culture/2024/03/dune-2-movies-frank-herbert-books-meaning-differences.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17450/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 17:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17450</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Once, men turned their thinking over to machines in the hope that this would set them free. But that only permitted other men with machines to enslave them.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—Reverend Mother Gaius Helen Mohiam, Dune&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De Correspondent over de Wooncrisis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-correspondent-over-de-wooncrisis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 11:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17427</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grappig om te zien dat De Correspondent een serie maakt over de wooncrisis in Nederland:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://decorrespondent.nl/14143/waarom-ik-geen-huis-wil-kopen/b196ee1f-4ff7-00f6-1463-37df41d85bb5&#34;&gt;https://decorrespondent.nl/14143/waarom-ik-geen-huis-wil-kopen/b196ee1f-4ff7-00f6-1463-37df41d85bb5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://decorrespondent.nl/14572/het-kan-de-bouw-van-betaalbare-woningen-overlaten-aan-beleggers/fd05f4ad-ee26-07be-3b42-1576e194f55d&#34;&gt;https://decorrespondent.nl/14572/het-kan-de-bouw-van-betaalbare-woningen-overlaten-aan-beleggers/fd05f4ad-ee26-07be-3b42-1576e194f55d&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://decorrespondent.nl/14844/wonen-is-een-publieke-taak-nu-nog-beleid-waar-je-dat-in-terugziet/073e6ebb-bbe3-0615-1ab0-e485bb65a016&#34;&gt;https://decorrespondent.nl/14844/wonen-is-een-publieke-taak-nu-nog-beleid-waar-je-dat-in-terugziet/073e6ebb-bbe3-0615-1ab0-e485bb65a016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://decorrespondent.nl/14996/niet-minder-asielzoekers-maar-meer-betaalbare-huizen-is-de-oplossing-voor-de-woningnood/11729058-1943-0564-307b-9b18240a1482&#34;&gt;https://decorrespondent.nl/14996/niet-minder-asielzoekers-maar-meer-betaalbare-huizen-is-de-oplossing-voor-de-woningnood/11729058-1943-0564-307b-9b18240a1482&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het is ook typisch De Correspondent om een series historische analyses en stukjes over alternative woon-/bouw-projecten neer te zetten. Allemaal dingen waar je je als lezer over goed kunt voelen zonder dat je iets aan het probleem moet doen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ze hadden wel een keer &lt;a href=&#34;https://decorrespondent.nl/13454/deze-belasting-maakt-alle-andere-belastingen-overbodig/e2c4da7e-1935-0abb-284d-1cee32b8f6ba&#34;&gt;een artikel over de LVT&lt;/a&gt; maar de samenhang komt niet echt naar voren.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17412/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 14:48:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17412</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From this massive list of science-fiction books by Noah Smith I&amp;rsquo;ve read and liked half or so which means that I probably should read the other half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.noahpinion.blog/p/my-sci-fi-novel-recommendations-888/&#34;&gt;https://www.noahpinion.blog/p/my-sci-fi-novel-recommendations-888/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023 Year in Review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2023-year-in-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17382</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking back on 2023 I can say that we made lemonade out of an overall pretty shit year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But not to worry. This is probably just one shit year in a sequence of many more shit years to come. No sign of anything getting better in our near future and lots of trends pointing downward. Does it have to be like this? Not in any way but the majority of people are stupid and we all suffer together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17338/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2023 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17338</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Listening to the Trash Future team describe CulturePulse.ai and the digital twin profile created for entire populations seems very very reminiscent of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/en/book/show/2263657&#34;&gt;“The Red Men”&lt;/a&gt; by Matthew de Abaitua which didn&amp;rsquo;t get the attention it deserved but was quite prescient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://trashfuturepodcast.podbean.com/e/waltz-with-the-sims/&#34;&gt;https://trashfuturepodcast.podbean.com/e/waltz-with-the-sims/&lt;/a&gt; (minute 23 and on)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elements from the book such as the corporation known as “Monad”(!) and robotic public service utilities called “Dr. Easy”are looking back from our current hellscape period a bit too on the nose.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17323/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 18:54:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17323</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think about the Roman Empire that much, but when I do it&amp;rsquo;s great to have it be because of Mary Beard who in this podcast (from the 18:48) talks about Zuckerberg&amp;rsquo;s fascination with August and how leadership then and now has not changed that much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://pca.st/6q8p6uok#t=1128.0&#34;&gt;https://pca.st/6q8p6uok#t=1128.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17306/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 08:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17306</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; stop thinking about the Roman Empire, but this piece that draws an analogy between the Fall of the Romans and the End of Twitter is long overdue to be shared and still really good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over at twitter this dance was happening but with weirdo right wingers. They were always mad because no one likes them because they are hateful, stupid, and have absolutely no rizz. Because they only know other weirdo right wingers IRL, however, they were convinced that there was some sort of nefarious plot to dunk on them online and they wanted to know when Twitter would acknowledge them, the biggest victims known to man. At the head of this was, of course, your man there Elon who is mad that he isn’t funny. He became convinced that there was an army of bots or something making fun of him and he demanded to know why twitter was letting people be mean to him. “You say that you want weirdo right wingers to be on this site and yet! You allow people to be very mildly mean to them!!!!! Even when they are the richest man on the planet! So much for free speech, etc.”Anyway, he accidentally got forced to buy twitter for too much money because he is quite stupid, and now here we are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17123/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 17:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17123</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally got around to reading Elizabeth Sandifer&amp;rsquo;s essay and if there was any doubt, this makes it clear how much of an unserious and malicious person Scott Alexander/Siskind is. Siskind&amp;rsquo;s writing deliberately pretends to be respectable to provide ideological cover to some real evil.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eruditorumpress.com/blog/the-beigeness-or-how-to-kill-people-with-bad-writing-the-scott-alexander-method&#34;&gt;https://www.eruditorumpress.com/blog/the-beigeness-or-how-to-kill-people-with-bad-writing-the-scott-alexander-method&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17118/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 11:22:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17118</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An amazing read about the first solo unsupported around the world sailing event and the maintenance that goes into doing something like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-maintenance-race&#34;&gt;https://worksinprogress.co/issue/the-maintenance-race&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Amp It Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-amp-it-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 09:42:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17112</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you need on day one is to ratchet up expectations, energy, urgency, and intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can engulf your organization with energy, step up the tempo, and start executing the basic blocking and tackling with a lot more focus and higher expectations. It will feel like busting a log jam. All of a sudden, everything is moving and shaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let malaise set in. Bust it up. Raising the bar is energizing by itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2023 08:34:40 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17101</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A useful distinction between &amp;ldquo;code proofreading&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;code editing&amp;rdquo; by Hillel Wayne both of which are part of a standard PR process but neither is really a good fit there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://buttondown.email/hillelwayne/archive/code-review-vs-code-proofreading/&#34;&gt;https://buttondown.email/hillelwayne/archive/code-review-vs-code-proofreading/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Rise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 21:59:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17090</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You need to use your time differently. You need to rise above the work. You need to figure out how to make yourself less busy with your current workload to make room to do higher-value work. No one will do this for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was trying to teach her team this lesson: you can’t work yourself to death and succeed over the long term. It was a hard cultural challenge, because her team believed that this overwork was not only highly valued by the company, but demanded.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Thinking in Bets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-thinking-in-bets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 17:35:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17085</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The punch line of the John Hennigan—Des Moines story—“after two days, he begged to get out of it”—made it part of gambling folklore.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everything is a bet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Most people aren’t like poker players, around whom there is always the potential that someone might propose a bet and they will mean it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Such interactions are reminders that not all situations are appropriate for truthseeking, nor are all people interested in the pursuit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Out with Bungacast and their tankie/nutter agenda</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/17035/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 21:48:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=17035</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Several online situations today where I think I&amp;rsquo;m going insane so I might as well document them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I listened to the last episode of Bungacast with the authors of the new book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/57791691-the-covid-consensus?ac=1&amp;amp;from_search=true&amp;amp;qid=BinLxtnEKr&amp;amp;rank=1&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Covid Consensus&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BungaCast/status/1625430144897671168&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/BungaCast/status/1625430144897671168&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the book and the episode are highly questionable. There is little more there than pandering to the COVID sceptic horseshoe left ((Those on the far left who would be far right if only the wind would blow from a different direction that day.)) by fishing in the murky pond of anti-authoritarianism, pseudo-science and neoreaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Domain Driven Design</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-domain-driven-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 22:17:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16850</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good programmers will naturally start to abstract and develop a model that can do more work. But when this happens only in a technical setting, without collaboration with domain experts, the concepts are naive. That shallowness of knowledge produces software that does a basic job but lacks a deep connection to the domain expert&amp;rsquo;s way of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And with typical design approaches, the code and documents don&amp;rsquo;t express this hard-earned knowledge in a usable form, so when the oral tradition is interrupted for any reason, the knowledge is lost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Bizim BÃ¼yÃ¼k Ã‡aresizliÄŸimiz</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-bizim-buyuk-caresizligimiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 22:16:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16848</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beş el vardı direksiyonda, babanın iki eli, Nevzat Amca&amp;rsquo;nın iki eli ve gören görür, ölümün eli&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Azrail&amp;rsquo;in piyangosu annenle babana vurdu Nihal!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daha doğrusu ikimiz de birbirimizin &amp;ldquo;âşık&amp;rdquo; halinden pek hoşlanmamıştık.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sonra sustum. Çok konuşunca olan şey: Konuşmak, anlatmak, anlamsız gelmişti birdenbire. Belki de, katlanıp kaldırılması gereken şeyleri buruşturmuştum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nihal&amp;rsquo;i karnının üzerinde pençelerini ne zaman etine geçireceği belli olmayan yırtıcı bir hayvanla dolaşıyor gibi düşünmüştüm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Görüyorsun değil mi Çetin, üç buçuk yaşındaki çocuk bile kendi deneyiminden bir yasa çıkarıyor! Başka türlü nefes alınmaz. Başka türlü yaşanmaz. Başka türlü aşk olmaz. Yaptıklarımızı olumlayan yasalar buluyoruz; sanırım aklımız böyle işliyor: Buyurgan iç huzurumuzun boynu bükük kölesi olarak.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Ministry for the Future</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-ministry-for-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 22:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16846</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In dealing with the poverty that still plagued so much of the Indian populace, the Indian government had had to create electricity as fast as they could, and also, since they existed in a world run by the market, as cheaply as they could. Otherwise outside investors would not invest, because the rate of return would not be high enough. So they had burned coal, yes. Like everyone else had up until just a few years before. Now India was being told not to burn coal, when everyone else had finished burning enough of it to build up the capital to afford to shift to cleaner sources of power. India had been told to get better without any financial help to do so whatsoever. Told to tighten the belt and embrace austerity, and be the working class for the bourgeoisie of the developed world, and suffer in silence until better times came— but the better times could never come, that plan was shot. The deck had been stacked, the game was over. And now twenty million people were dead.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Executive Presence</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-executive-presence/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 21:50:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16827</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But in the finals what distinguished one from another was all of the nonmusic stuff. The way they walked onto the stage, the cut of their clothes, the set of their shoulders, the spark in their eyes, and the emotion that played on their faces. All of these things established a mood either of tedium and awkwardness or of excited anticipation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned that EP rests on three pillars:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How you act (gravitas)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Cosmopolitanism</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-cosmopolitanism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 21:49:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16825</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to insist, however, that to say that Muslims should go to Mecca for this reason isn’t to agree with Muslims. It is to give our reason for them to do something that they do for a different reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We go astray, similarly, when we think of a moral vocabulary as the possession of a solitary individual. If meanings ain’t in the head, neither are morals. The concept of kindness, or cruelty, enshrines a kind of social consensus.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16819/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 09:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16819</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currentaffairs.org/2022/07/the-dangerous-populist-science-of-yuval-noah-harari&#34;&gt;https://www.currentaffairs.org/2022/07/the-dangerous-populist-science-of-yuval-noah-harari&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For how popular and questionable Yuval Noah Harari&amp;rsquo;s writing has been, it has barely seen any scrutiny. This critique by Darshana Narayanan is on point and most of the things in it were—I hate to say it—glaringly obvious from the get-go.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Rust for Rustaceans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-rust-for-rustaceans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 21:40:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16749</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, there cannot be two parallel flows with mutable access to a value. Nor can there be a flow that borrows a value while there is no flow that owns the value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeing the memory twice could have catastrophic consequences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you just want to leave some valid value behind, std::mem::take 2 is a good candidate. It is equivalent to std::mem::replace(&amp;amp;mut value, Default::default()); it moves value out from behind the mutable reference but leaves a new, default value for the type in its place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for It&#39;s Not About the Burqa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-its-not-about-the-burqa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 21:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16746</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not have heard the word ‘feminism’ yet, but I knew that the way women and girls were treated in Saudi Arabia was wrong and that this was not the Islam I was taught, nor did it represent the home I was raised in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am Indian. Yoga runs through my blood, it’s as natural to me as my vitamin D deficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet I was surrounded by a community that disapproved of this sort of independence. Any attempt to challenge the traditional roles was met with disapproval that quickly spread through gossip and manifested as social control.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Becoming Trader Joe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-becoming-trader-joe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 21:36:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16742</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We witnessed something very interesting: the United States had a quota for imported tuna. Once Peru’s quota had been filled, a biological miracle occurred right there on the canning line. What had been tuna was now pilchard, a member of the herring family, on which there was no quota.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Adamsons were land-rich but cash-poor; they lacked the funds to develop the magnificent property. They were having to sell off pieces for far less than they potentially were worth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16715/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 11:45:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16715</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wat is geweld? vroeg hij haar. Is het besmeuren van gebouwen gewelddadiger dan het blijven verbranden van kolen, terwijl we weten dat de broeikasgassen die daardoor in de atmosfeer terechtkomen een hoop leed veroorzaken, niet alleen voor toekomstige generaties, maar ook voor de minder gefortuneerde mensen die vandaag leven?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good article about Malm. The answer to the question above should be: &amp;ldquo;All climate action is self-defense.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s possible to draw a straight line from Malm&amp;rsquo;s book to the climate protests happening right now in Berlin where people block the city ring road, which makes him quite effective.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16713/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 10:00:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16713</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why recent developments in fields such as Afrofuturism and Black horror are so crucial. They provide a critical alternative to the alt-right’s exterminationist fantasy of an all-white future. Just as importantly, they offer readers other ways of thinking about time that do not fall in line with the fascist dream of a history that unfolds step-by-step along the lines of the Aryan dictator’s master plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/race-consciousness-fascism-and-frank-herberts-dune/&#34;&gt;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/race-consciousness-fascism-and-frank-herberts-dune/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year Note 2021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/year-note-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 09:14:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16685</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The days are long but the years are short.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more year over and these are starting to look like a blur, so here&amp;rsquo;s what changed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;work&#34;&gt;Work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I gave notice between Christmas and New Year 2020 and spent the first three months of the year in a weird in-between state mostly done with the old job, waiting for the new one to start, in between daycare closures and being sick.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn You a Haskell is Problematic</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/learn-you-a-haskell-is-problematic/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 12:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16661</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago I learned Haskell and to do that I read a book that is universally recommended for beginners and used to be available free online called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6593810-learn-you-a-haskell-for-great-good&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Learn you a Haskell for Great Good&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website seems to be gone at the moment: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.learnyouahaskell.com/&#34;&gt;https://www.learnyouahaskell.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t think too much about it when I read it but after some other people were asking what they should use to learn Haskell I remembered these weird &amp;lsquo;jokes&amp;rsquo; that are in the book to make the code a bit livelier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16617/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 07:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16617</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is a lot of truth to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.economist.com/1843/2016/07/04/let-me-explain-the-problem-with-german-humour&#34;&gt;this Economist article about German humour&lt;/a&gt; and I refer back to it a lot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shortly after moving&lt;/strong&gt; back to Germany in 2012 after decades of absence, mainly in Anglo-Saxon countries, I took my kids to the Berlin zoo. The children were two, four and seven at the time, and had already developed a keen sense of irony — or at least they understood that dad doesn’t always mean things literally, because, you know, it’s funny. So we queued for our tickets, trading silly jokes. Like me, the kids are dual citizens of America and Germany, though at that time, fresh from California, we still felt more American and more at ease in English. But we deliberately spoke German, to help us acclimatise to our new home. In a mood of levity, we approached the ticket window.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leveled up in Turkish</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/leveled-up-in-turkish/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 20:43:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16586</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hanging out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joinclubhouse.com/&#34;&gt;Clubhouse&lt;/a&gt; from the beginning made me realize how lacking my Turkish was. I got on the app when Germany came online and I think Turkey launched shortly after that and only then did it kick off in the Netherlands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That particular sequencing gave me an interesting perspective on how different cultures adopted the service. Germans went into panel hell. Most of the sessions were dominated by journalists and politicos and therefore were extremely boring. Turkey got online in no time and was dominated by influencers who launched all kinds of funky &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/lkoltuksohbetleri/&#34;&gt;repeating formats&lt;/a&gt; and casual chatrooms where people were going until deep into the night (I would listen until 1-2 at night which in Turkey would be 2 hours later still). The Netherlands went into a marketing fervor with a strong showing of douchebags.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Site Reliability Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-site-reliability-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 22:06:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16581</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Traditional operations teams and their counterparts in product development thus often end up in conflict, most visibly over how quickly software can be released to production. At their core, the development teams want to launch new features and see them adopted by users. At their core, the ops teams want to make sure the service doesn’t break while they are holding the pager. Because most outages are caused by some kind of change—a new configuration, a new feature launch, or a new type of user traffic—the two teams’ goals are fundamentally in tension.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Radical Markets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-radical-markets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 22:05:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16579</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private property would become public to a significant extent and the possessions of those around you would, in a sense, become partly yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although at first blush you might assume that the auction would allow the rich to buy up everything of value, reflect for a moment. What do you mean by “the rich”? People who own lots of businesses, land, and so forth. But, if everything were up for auction all the time, no person would own such assets.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16540/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jul 2021 16:00:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16540</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Helicopter Story&amp;rdquo; was one of the best pieces of sci-fi I&amp;rsquo;ve read in a while. All the more galling that it was ripped apart in a culture war free-for-all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a special amount of hate especially for those people who feel like they&amp;rsquo;re on the good side but have an understanding of literature that is too shallow to contain something like this. I blame MCU, games and Disney for letting these people believe that what happens there is what&amp;rsquo;s possible and allowed in fiction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Provos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-provos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:27:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16433</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He believed that the ‘blood sacrifice’ of a few would regenerate the national consciousness and lead, by force of Irish arms, to the eventual withdrawal of Britain from Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MacSwiney took his place in history not just because of his sacrifice but because of his portentous words. ‘It is not those who can inflict the most,’ he warned, ‘but those who can suffer the most who will conquer.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight months earlier, Lloyd George had likened the prospect of meeting Collins to that of meeting a murderer and had described the IRA as ‘a small body of assassins, a real murder gang, dominating the country and terrorizing it’. Now he described its commander as ‘one of the most courageous leaders ever produced by a valiant race’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Nine Lies About Work</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-nine-lies-about-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 15:26:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16431</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And from that point on she micromanaged me, and I realized that she was fear-based, both in how she thought of her bosses and in terms of how she ran her team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good news in all this for you, the team leader, is that what people care most about at work is within your control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big thing is that only on a team can we express our individuality at work and put it to highest use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16377/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 20:54:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16377</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am immensely happy to see two friends launch Branch, a magazine about creating a sustainable internet. The way they put the magazine together mirrors the best practices of the future we should live in right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://branch.climateaction.tech/2020/10/21/letter-from-the-editors/&#34;&gt;https://branch.climateaction.tech/2020/10/21/letter-from-the-editors/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16369/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 20:39:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">https://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16369</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lovely interview about the magic bus and the hippie period in Istanbul revolving around the Lale Pudding Shop which is still in business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kenan&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/kenan&lt;/a&gt;_sharpe/status/1333719308585857024&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16344/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Oct 2020 21:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.alper.nl/dingen/?p=16344</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hpdetijd.nl/2020-10-14/twee-eeuwen-oranjebitter/&#34;&gt;https://www.hpdetijd.nl/2020-10-14/twee-eeuwen-oranjebitter/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Een heerlijk artikel over het reilen en zeilen van de Oranjes en hoe het instituut niet veel meer dan een vehikel is voor zelfverrijking en slecht gedrag.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16286/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 22:04:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16286</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The technology is not the hard part. It’s already invented, but we have to pay ourselves to install it fast. So, again, that’s an economic question, and it doesn’t work in capitalism. We have the means right now to arrange for everybody alive today to have adequate food, water, shelter, clothing, education, and healthcare, within the biosphere’s carrying capacity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A market of some sort may always exist, because we need to trade, but it could be so sharply regulated that it could exist on what economists call the margin, suitable for the toys, but not for the necessities of life, which should all be public utilities and part of a job guarantee and a living wage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Progress and Poverty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-progress-and-poverty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 19:51:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16265</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foul things fled, fierce things tame; discord turned to harmony! For how could there be greed where all had enough? How could the vice, the crime, the ignorance, the brutality, that spring from poverty and the fear of poverty, exist where poverty had vanished? Who should crouch where all were freemen; who oppress where all were peers?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where the conditions to which material progress everywhere tends are most fully realized—that is to say, where population is densest, wealth greatest, and the machinery of production and exchange most highly developed—we find the deepest poverty, the sharpest struggle for existence, and the most of enforced idleness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16210/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 10:52:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16210</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought this was a great interview with Kim Stanley Robinson but it turns out the Corona virus has not rewritten our imaginations enough, not enough at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-coronavirus-and-our-future&#34;&gt;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/the-coronavirus-and-our-future&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slate Star Codex and Silicon Valleyâ€™s War Against the Media</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/slate-star-codex-and-silicon-valleys-war-against-the-media/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2020 23:05:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16153</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An excellent overview of the issues around Slate Star Codex without having to read a single word of the blog yourself. That&amp;rsquo;s an excellent service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/slate-star-codex-and-silicon-valleys-war-against-the-media&#34;&gt;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-inquiry/slate-star-codex-and-silicon-valleys-war-against-the-media&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16141/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 10:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16141</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t say I&amp;rsquo;ve read a lot of Beyond the Beyond nor been much of a happy Wired consumer in any case, but it&amp;rsquo;s passing still marks the end of an era. I remember Bruce Sterling&amp;rsquo;s closing speeches at SxSWi as one of the highlights of the conference (me being  too late an arrival to attend his house parties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/beyond-the-beyond/2020/05/farewell-beyond-beyond/&#34;&gt;https://www.wired.com/beyond-the-beyond/2020/05/farewell-beyond-beyond/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Peaceful Parent Happy Kids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-peaceful-parent-happy-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 22:32:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16139</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the popular idea that we need to “express”our anger so that it doesn’t eat away at us, research shows that expressing anger while we are angry actually makes us more angry. This in turn makes the other person hurt, afraid, or angry, and causes a rift in the relationship. Rehashing the situation in our mind always proves to us that we’re right and the other person is wrong, which again makes us more angry as we stew. What works is to calm down, and then find a constructive way to address whatever is making us angry so that the situation is resolved, and our anger stops being triggered.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16093/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:19:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16093</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very thorough overview of William Gibson&amp;rsquo;s life and work which touches on a lot of familiar points. It reminds me that I should read Agency and makes me want to dive back and read the previous trilogies again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/12/16/how-william-gibson-keeps-his-science-fiction-real&#34;&gt;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/12/16/how-william-gibson-keeps-his-science-fiction-real&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16091/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 09:07:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16091</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tell them the contours of patriarchy closed in, but haven’t crushed me. I’m the same person I’ve always been, broke but stronger.&lt;br&gt;
Tell whoever asks, that I’m still right here, and I — by which I mean we, us, women voices, mine and others — we’re not going away. We’re speaking up, erasing patriarchal privilege by calling it out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A striking story of a woman who writes against all odds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/16089/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 08:59:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16089</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had put the Ray Dalio book on my do-not-read pile even before knowing exactly how evil it is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.currentaffairs.org/2018/06/how-to-make-everyone-in-your-vicinity-secretly-fear-and-despise-you&#34;&gt;https://www.currentaffairs.org/2018/06/how-to-make-everyone-in-your-vicinity-secretly-fear-and-despise-you&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>(kom eens langs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kom-eens-langs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 20:46:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16077</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Eerst praten we over van alles en niets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan schenk ik thee. Doe er nog wat koekjes bij.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik had geld geleend van mijn moeder waarmee ik een goed gevulde tafel dek.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je zegt ‘ik ben op dieet’ en eet niet, ik eet, dat geeft niet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan praten we over ditjes en datjes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dan hebben we het over mij.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ook al wil ik dat helemaal niet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Je neemt me mijn fouten kwalijk.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Escapology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-escapology/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 19:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16045</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first lesson Amiga learnt when she started to kill was how easy it is, and how utterly horrifying that can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the homes here are assembled from huge 3D-printed parts and brightly coloured, though it’s hard to see in the meagre lighting. The brainchild of a design genie called Liberty, printed homes have become ubiquitous amongst under-mono communities, transforming them from shantytowns to neat, albeit crowded plastic villages. Everything modernizes eventually.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Dead Souls</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-dead-souls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 21:42:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16040</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The newcomer was somehow never at a loss and showed himself to be an experienced man of the world. Whatever the conversation, he always knew how to keep up his end: if the talk was of horse breeding, he spoke about horse breeding; if they were speaking of fine dogs, here, too, he made very sensible observations; if the discussion touched upon an investigation conducted by the treasury—he showed that he was not uninformed about legal wiles; if there were some argument about the game of billiards—in the game of billiards, too, he would not go amiss; if they spoke of virtue, on virtue, too, he reasoned very well, tears even came to his eyes; if on the distilling of spirits, then on the distilling of spirits he also knew his stuff; if on customs supervisors and officials, of them, too, he could judge as if he himself had been both an official and a supervisor.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Crucial Conversations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-crucial-conversations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 21:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=16035</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, you don’t have to choose between being honest and being effective. You don’t have to choose between candor and your career. People who routinely hold crucial conversations and hold them well are able to express controversial and even risky opinions in a way that gets heard. Their bosses, peers, and direct reports listen without becoming defensive or angry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When two or more of us enter crucial conversations, by definition we don’t share the same pool. Our opinions differ. I believe one thing; you another. I have one history; you another.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15958/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 22:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15958</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An incredibly sad and beautiful story of a father&amp;rsquo;s last days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2019/dec/14/saying-goodbye-to-family-motor-neurone-disease-reflecting-on-end-of-life&#34;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/lifeandstyle/2019/dec/14/saying-goodbye-to-family-motor-neurone-disease-reflecting-on-end-of-life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15956/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 22:02:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15956</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A bit of near-future fiction about crypto as a subsistence work enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://logicmag.io/bodies/the-crypto-family-farm/&#34;&gt;https://logicmag.io/bodies/the-crypto-family-farm/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15940/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2020 14:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15940</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this science-fiction short story which is reminiscent of Ann Leckie&amp;rsquo;s books in how it plays with gender and militarism, but I think this is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/atomicthumbs/status/1215170599045103617&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/atomicthumbs/status/1215170599045103617&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Winners Take All</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-winners-take-all/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 12:17:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15889</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, the system—in America and around the world—has been organized to siphon the gains from innovation upward, such that the fortunes of the world’s billionaires now grow at more than double the pace of everyone else’s, and the top 10 percent of humanity have come to hold 90 percent of the planet’s wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How can there be anything wrong with trying to do good? The answer may be: when the good is an accomplice to even greater, if more invisible, harm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>German history reading list</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/german-history-reading-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 11:55:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15886</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been meaning to finish reading up on German history. If I read the five books below, I should be in a great place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heart of Europe: A History of the Holy Roman Empire&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iron Kingdom, the Rise and Downfall of Prussia, 1600-1947&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;History of Germany 1780-1918: The Long Nineteenth Century&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weimar Germany: Promise and Tragedy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hitler: Ascent 1889-1939&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15761/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 20:01:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15761</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Will Larson (whose new book is lying on my desk at work) writes a welcome long view on the technology career, something we will increasingly need to think about and come to terms with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lethain.com/forty-year-career/&#34;&gt;https://lethain.com/forty-year-career/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for My Struggle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-my-struggle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 21:18:31 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15733</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your perspective of the world increases not only is the pain it inflicts on you less but also its meaning. Understanding the world requires you to take a certain distance from it. Things that are too small to see with the naked eye, such as molecules and atoms, we magnify. Things that are too large, such as cloud formations, river deltas, constellations, we reduce. At length we bring it within the scope of our senses and we stabilize it with fixer. When it has been fixed we call it knowledge. Throughout our childhood and teenage years, we strive to attain the correct distance to objects and phenomena. We read, we learn, we experience, we make adjustments. Then one day we reach the point where all the necessary distances have been set, all the necessary systems have been put in place. That is when time begins to pick up speed. It no longer meets any obstacles, everything is set, time races through our lives, the days pass by in a flash and before we know what is happening we are forty, fifty, sixty . . .&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15726/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 21:00:23 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15726</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is true that Goodreads is a deeply broken website but right now it is the only place that we have that has a critical mass of readers on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://onezero.medium.com/almost-everything-about-goodreads-is-broken-662e424244d5&#34;&gt;https://onezero.medium.com/almost-everything-about-goodreads-is-broken-662e424244d5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for How not to hate your husband after kids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-how-not-to-hate-your-husband-after-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 18:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15651</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fisher says there is brain evidence that when women are under stress (say, a new baby has colic), they are inclined to “tend and befriend”(become more empathetic and social), while men under stress are apt to withdraw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study of heterosexual couples led by Shiri Cohen, a couples therapist and psychology instructor at Harvard Medical School, revealed that women reported feeling much happier when their male partners understood that they were angry or upset. “This research bore out what I see every day with couples,”Cohen tells me. “When the man can register his wife’s negative feelings, and communicate that on some level, the wife feels better, because she knows that ‘Oh, he gets how I’m feeling.’”She points out that, conversely, men do not derive the same satisfaction in knowing that their wives are upset. “Research shows that men tend to retreat from what feels like conflict to them, because they tend to physiologically get much more negatively aroused,”she said, “so conflict feels way more intense for them.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15649/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 12:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15649</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of these literary exposés, this one about how Benjamin Moser treats female collaborators and appropriates their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/benjamin-moser-and-the-smallest-woman-in-the-world/&#34;&gt;https://lareviewofbooks.org/article/benjamin-moser-and-the-smallest-woman-in-the-world/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Agile Application Security</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-agile-application-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 20:54:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15635</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t wait for the perfect time, tool or training course to get started. Just do something.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lean as a methodology prioritises the principle cycle of “Build”â†’ “Measure”â†’ “Learn”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many security professionals have a hard time adapting their existing practices to a world where requirements can change every few weeks, or where they are never written down at all. Where design and risk management decisions are made by the team just in time, instead of being planned out and directed from top down. And where manual testing and compliance checking cannot possibly keep up with the speed of delivery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15627/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2019 21:31:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15627</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I offer this: literature can save a life. Just one life at a time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teju Cole is a treasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2019/07/05/carrying-a-single-life-on-literature-translation/&#34;&gt;https://www.nybooks.com/daily/2019/07/05/carrying-a-single-life-on-literature-translation/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15610/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 10:58:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15610</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We do our own flavor of attachment parenting and this is still one of my favorite pieces about motherhood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2018/01/31/baby-book-bathwater/&#34;&gt;https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2018/01/31/baby-book-bathwater/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Temperamentvolle Kinderen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-temperamentvolle-kinderen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 18:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15586</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opvallend is dat ze vaak een groot gevoel voor uiterlijke schoonheid hebben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intens: enthousiast, uitbundig, gepassioneerd, diepzinnig, levendig, hartstochtelijk, innig, fanatiek&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in plaats van hysterisch, overdreven, driftig, wild, luidruchtig, ongeremd)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gevoelig: inlevend, empathisch, openstaand, zachtaardig, teder, toegankelijk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in plaats van sentimenteel, kwetsbaar, prikkelbaar, overgevoelig, slap)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opmerkzaam: oog voor detail, scherpzinnig, oplettend, alert, aandachtig, waakzaam, kritisch, geconcentreerd, oplettend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(in plaats van pietluttig, lastig, kieskeurig, snel afgeleid)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sterke wil: vastberaden, doelgericht, eigenzinnig, onverstoorbaar, krachtig, aanhoudend, standvastig&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15544/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 16:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15544</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are people paying the Medium article ransom?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A poor man&#39;s instapaper</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/a-poor-mans-instapaper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 11:29:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15516</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instapaper.com/&#34;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; for a long time now, but I&amp;rsquo;m still reading longreads. Let me explain how.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I go through my links in Chrome on my desktop. I close and read whatever I can and anything that&amp;rsquo;s too long stays in an open tab and floats slowly to the left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;IMG_CAACFBBBB194-1-1.jpeg&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Chrome on my phone whenever I&amp;rsquo;m in transit or when I want to read something longer that isn&amp;rsquo;t a book, I go to the “Recent tabs”screen. Besides those you can also find synced open tabs from all your other Chrome browsers. I then pick something that I want to read.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Designing Data-Intensive Applications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-designing-data-intensive-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2019 21:19:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15514</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon RedShift is a hosted version of ParAccel. More recently, a plethora of open source SQL-on-Hadoop projects have emerged; they are young but aiming to compete with commercial data warehouse systems. These include Apache Hive, Spark SQL, Cloudera Impala, Facebook Presto, Apache Tajo, and Apache Drill [52, 53].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these situations, as long as people agree on what the format is, it often doesn’t matter how pretty or efficient the format is. The difficulty of getting different organizations to agree on anything outweighs most other concerns.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Society</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-theory-of-society/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 21:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15487</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was arguing against Systems Theory today (a necessary evil when you live in Germany) which prompted the thought of searching for the conjunction of Bruno Latour and Niklas Luhmann. That led me to &lt;a href=&#34;https://wittenbrink.net/lostandfound/clash-of-culturesbruno-latour-trifft-niklas-luhmann/&#34;&gt;this gem&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that they met each other for a debate in 1996 in Bielefeld and Latour &lt;strong&gt;DESTROYED&lt;/strong&gt; his opponent ( &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.leydesdorff.net/luhmannreconsidered/luhmann_and_latour.pdf&#34;&gt;full article&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luhmann, as expected, failed to engage with the theme of the conference, Science and Technology Studies and didn&amp;rsquo;t come out of his bubble. The same bubble that he has managed to trap most of the German humanities in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15464/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 21:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15464</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik dacht dat Arjen van Veelen één van de beste schrijvers op de Correspondent was. Dat is hij misschien nog steeds, maar dan shrijft hij wel dit soort onzin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GijsbertPols/status/1133034973437599744&#34;&gt;https://twitter.com/GijsbertPols/status/1133034973437599744&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Interpreter of Maladies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-interpreter-of-maladies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 12:56:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15441</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her estimation, I knew, I was assured a safe life, an easy life, a fine education, every opportunity. I would never have to eat rationed food, or obey curfews, or watch riots from my rooftop, or hide neighbors in water tanks to prevent them from being shot, as she and my father had.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my son&amp;rsquo;s eyes I see the ambition that had first hurled me across the world. In a few years he will graduate and pave his way, alone and unprotected. But I remind myself that he has a father who is still living, a mother who is happy and strong. Whenever he is discouraged I tell him that if I can survive on three continents than there is no obstacle he cannot conquer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for How to Measure Anything in Cybersecurity Risk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-how-to-measure-anything-in-cybersecurity-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 12:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15439</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What risks are acceptable is often not documented, and when they are, they are stated in soft, unquantified terms that cannot be used clearly in a calculation to determine if a given expenditure is justified or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Measurement: A quantitatively expressed reduction of uncertainty based on one or more observations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a decision maker or analyst engages in what they believe to be measurement activities, but their estimates and decisions actually get worse or don’t at least improve, then they are not actually reducing their error and are not conducting a measurement according to the stated definition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15431/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2019 07:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15431</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of very salient thinking on books, metacognition, double-loop learning and the deliberate design of new forms by Andy Matuschak in &lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/books/&#34;&gt;“Why Books Don&amp;rsquo;t Work”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I acknowledged earlier that of course, some people &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; absorb knowledge from books. Indeed, those are the people who really do think about what they’re reading. The process is often invisible. These readers’ inner monologues have sounds like: “This idea reminds me of…,”“This point conflicts with…,”“I don’t really understand how…,”etc. If they take some notes, they’re not simply transcribing the author’s words: they’re summarizing, synthesizing, analyzing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15382/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 21:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15382</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.niemanlab.org/2019/05/what-will-the-correspondent-publish-in-english-a-look-at-the-dutch-site-offers-some-clues/&#34;&gt;https://www.niemanlab.org/2019/05/what-will-the-correspondent-publish-in-english-a-look-at-the-dutch-site-offers-some-clues/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Americans feel ripped off by the Corres&amp;rsquo;s bait and switch and it seems now we&amp;rsquo;re going to seeing a free for all where they will mercilessly rip the site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was disappointing to realize — to actually &lt;em&gt;see&lt;/em&gt; in the numbers — that while The Correspondent raised $2.6 million in part by stressing diversity and inclusivity, tapping ambassadors like DeRay Mckesson and Baratunde Thurston, the Dutch site is not a model of that diversity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15358/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 13:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15358</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you’ll see, everything is slightly approximate, slightly exaggerated — so that each step in the argument takes you further from what you’re prepared to agree to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out Harari&amp;rsquo;s books only go downhill after Sapiens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thewhitereview.org/reviews/yuval-noah-harari/&#34;&gt;http://www.thewhitereview.org/reviews/yuval-noah-harari/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15332/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 20:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15332</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t really get enough of Haidt takedowns like this one in the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core irony of &lt;em&gt;The Coddling of the American&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;Mind&lt;/em&gt; is that, by opposing identity politics, its authors try to consolidate an identity that does not have to see itself as such. Enjoying the luxury of living free from discrimination and domination, they therefore insist that the crises moving young people to action are all in their heads.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15304/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2019 22:16:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15304</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An elaboration on High Output Management split into “Running yourself”and “Running your team”by Keith Rabois.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://delian.io/lessons-3&#34;&gt;http://delian.io/lessons-3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Pnin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-pnin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 22:15:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15289</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;by a huge, active, buoyantly thriving German Department which its Head, Dr. Hagen, smugly called (pronouncing every syllable very distinctly) “a university within a university.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pnin, despite his many shortcomings, had about him a disarming, old-fashioned charm which Dr. Hagen, his staunch protector, insisted before morose trustees was a delicate imported article worth paying for in domestic cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;desuetude&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;lozenges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was the world that was absent-minded and it was Pnin whose business it was to set it straight. His life was a constant war with insensate objects that fell apart, or attacked him, or refused to function, or viciously got themselves lost as soon as they entered the sphere of his existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Street of Thieves</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-street-of-thieves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 22:14:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15249</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I choked and turned tail, fled once again, fled faced with myself; I left at a run; there are things that can’t be fixed. Actually, nothing can be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Men are dogs who rub against each other in solitude&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we sense the situation is escaping us, that things are getting out of hand; we become afraid and instead of calmly looking, trying to understand, we react like a dog caught in barbed wire, thrashing about madly until it slices open its throat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Sacred Book of the Werewolf</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-sacred-book-of-the-werewolf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 22:13:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15247</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But other foxes say that in that brief second the man realizes that physical life is a stupid and shameful mistake. And the first thing he tries to do is to thank the fox who has opened his eyes. And after that he corrects the error of his own existence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this boom doesn’t have much to do with the economy. It’s just that the money from all over Russia flows into Moscow and moistens life here a bit before it departs for off-shore hyperspace.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Changing my media diet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/15195/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 22:25:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=15195</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve changed my monthly contribution from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.theguardian.com/international&#34;&gt;Guardian&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://taz.de/&#34;&gt;Taz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guardian is a bit weird and was not doing that much for me anymore. It&amp;rsquo;s not clear what they&amp;rsquo;re about and I&amp;rsquo;m mostly disappointed in their roster of writers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taz, I only read occasionally but they&amp;rsquo;re local (with an office that is practically next to my house) and they&amp;rsquo;re a lot more left-wing than the Guardian is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t found many good alternative newspapers other than the FT which is ridiculously expensive.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Red Moon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-red-moon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 13:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6104</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analogies always deceive more than they reveal; I am no fan of analogies, I do not use them. Even metaphor, that mental operation we use with almost every word we speak, is slippery and deceptive. I always speak as plainly as I can.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Oh, nothing. I wish I knew what was going on.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She shook her head, stared at the wall. “It’s China,”she said. “Give up on that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He watched his mom fondly. How many times he had heard this story. Even inside the device, the weight of the world was still crushing him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Tribal Leadership</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-tribal-leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 21:50:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6101</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, they spent most of their efforts building strong relationships between Griffin’s tribal members—its employees, volunteers, and patients. Second, instead of telling people what to do, they engineered experiences (such as the retreats) in which staff members would look at the same issues they were dealing with, so that strategy became everyone’s problem. Third, they got out of the way and let people contribute in their own way to the emerging tribal goals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading 2018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reading-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jan 2019 20:58:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6091</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I grabbed &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/alper/goodreadsgraph&#34;&gt;the code&lt;/a&gt; I had lying around for &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2017/12/reading-2017/&#34;&gt;last year&lt;/a&gt; and without too much trouble ran the same analysis for the books. The graph is not that dramatic this time though for some reason I did not read much during summer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;download.png&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Page-wise this year with 13398 pages was a bit weaker than last year (15049 pages).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By some miracle, I managed to post my top ten recommendations to twitter on the 31st.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Shambhala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-shambhala/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 13:17:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6087</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope only that we have not obstructed or weakened the power of these teachings. May they help to liberate all beings from the warring evils of the setting sun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shambhala vision teaches that, in the face of the world’s great problems, we can be heroic and kind at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is lacking is a sense of humor. Humor here does not mean telling jokes or being comical or criticizing others and laughing at them. A genuine sense of humor is having a light touch: not beating reality into the ground but appreciating reality with a light touch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Oh Crap</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-oh-crap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6085</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One year of one child using disposable diapers uses two full grown trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s worse is very few people dispose of the poop in the toilet before throwing away the diaper—did you even know you’re supposed to do that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most moms, probably including you, are reading this book because you know deep in your heart that your child is ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There will be a power struggle and for the first time ever, your child will literally be holding all the power, in the form of pee and poop. You will not win.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for No Bad Kids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-no-bad-kids/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 12:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6083</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting limits, the emotional state of the parent almost always dictates the child’s reaction. If we lack clarity and confidence, lose our temper or are unsure, tense, frazzled, or frustrated — this will unsettle our kids and very likely lead to more undesirable behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why would our sweet darling throw her toy at us when we’ve just asked her not to, and then add insult to injury by smirking? Is she evil? Does she have a pressing need to practice throwing skills? Maybe she just hates us…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The First 90 Days</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-first-90-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 20:04:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6078</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To transition effectively, first identify the risks you face as you move into your new role using the Transition Risk Assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter where you land, the keys to effective delegation remain much the same: you build a team of competent people whom you trust, you establish goals and metrics to monitor their progress, you translate higher-level goals into specific responsibilities for your direct reports, and you reinforce them through process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for How Democracy Ends</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-how-democracy-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 21:27:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6075</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When democracy ends, we are likely to be surprised by the form it takes. We may not even notice that it is happening because we are looking in the wrong places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All can continue to function as they ought while failing to deliver what they should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future will be different from the past. The past is longer than we think. America is not the whole world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The resemblance to a scene in a Batman movie — the Joker addressing the cowed citizens of Gotham — was so strong it seemed like a cliché.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Surveillance Valley</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-surveillance-valley/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Nov 2018 11:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6072</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people gathered at city hall that night saw Oakland’s DAC as an extension of the tech-fueled gentrification that was pushing poorer longtime residents out of the city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Internet was developed as a weapon and remains a weapon today. American military interests continue to dominate all parts of the network, even those that supposedly stand in opposition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An even more disturbing dimension of the AIR’s pacification work in Thailand was that it was supposed to serve as a model for counterinsurgency operations elsewhere in the world—including against black people living in American inner cities, where race riots were breaking out at the time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blitzkrieg Tactics Translated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/blitzkrieg-tactics-translated/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 09:41:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6069</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The tactics employed during the Blitzkrieg are those of highly agile manoeuvre warfare. They are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Einheit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fingerspitzengefühl&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auftragstaktik&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Schwerpunkt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For an English audience or one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a stomach for this bit of history you can use:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Feeling Trust&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Idiot</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-idiot/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 07:30:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6065</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Were Germans supposed to be particularly ordered and machinelike? Was it possible that Germans really were ordered and machinelike?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was no way to go through life, in Turkish or any other language, making only factual statements about direct observations. You were forced to use -miş, just by the human condition—just by existing in relation to other people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Spanish—I liked how the donkey had a place in the national literature&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Hall of Uselessness</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-hall-of-uselessness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 07:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6063</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One has the feeling that these critics do not really like literature—they do not enjoy reading. Worse even, if they were actually to enjoy a book, they would suspect it to be frivolous. In their eyes, something that is amusing cannot be important or serious.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though, as a wise doctor once remarked, between two doctors whose medical qualifications are otherwise equal, we should trust the one who reads Chekhov.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The closer a book comes to being a genuine work of art, a true creation with a life of its own, the less likely it is that the author had full control over and a clear understanding of what he wrote.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Chapo Guide to Revolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-chapo-guide-to-revolution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2018 20:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6059</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You find yourself in the dumbest of all possible worlds, clowns to the left of you, Re-thug-licans to the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Official state religion is Shia Scientology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’ll focus entirely on liquidating the “legitimate news”part of the media, along with its revolting acolytes, known as “journalists.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our rival Nazi Germany had collapsed after it overleveraged risky investments in Eastern European “living space,”while Japan—once an aggressive competitor to America—was defeated due to a certain killer app developed in a cutting-edge incubator in Los Alamos, New Mexico.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Parent&#39;s Tao Te Ching</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-parents-tao-te-ching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 21:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6056</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Call birth, “birth,”and death, “death,”without seeing one as good and the other as evil and your children will be at home with life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you teach them to achieve they will never be content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you teach them contentment, they will naturally achieve everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do not live your life through your children.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore they are free to find their own true fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you overly protect your children they will fear failure and avoid pain.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Ghachar Ghochar</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-ghachar-ghochar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 21:26:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6052</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The woman had not abused us. She had not come here to pick a fight. We were thrown off balance by her love for one of us, and so we tore into her with such vengeance that she collapsed to the ground, sobbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s true what they say — it’s not we who control money, it’s the money that controls us. When there’s only a little, it behaves meekly; when it grows, it becomes brash and has its way with us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Cracking the Tech Career</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-cracking-the-tech-career/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 12:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6028</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best product managers, the best marketers, and the best developers have something in common: they each understand the others&amp;rsquo; roles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you founded a club that accomplished some concrete goals and led your school&amp;rsquo;s shift to electronic course review, you might make this a Leadership Experience section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you must always include education on your resume, this section should get shorter with more work experience. Many candidates with even two or three years of experience list just their major and degree.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Woken Furies</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-woken-furies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 20:39:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6047</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That, of course, doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to Envoys. We just used to go silently, crush the odd planetary uprising, topple the odd regime, and then plug in something UN-compliant that worked. Slaughter and suppression across the stars, for the greater good — naturally — of a unified Protectorate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Envoys came and they tore your world apart. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that simple, of course; the truth was far more complex, and ultimately far more scary. But who in this universe wants the truth?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Why We Sleep</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-why-we-sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2018 12:03:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6031</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short sleeping increases the likelihood of your coronary arteries becoming blocked and brittle, setting you on a path toward cardiovascular disease, stroke, and congestive heart failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists such as myself have even started lobbying doctors to start “prescribing”sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society’s apathy toward sleep has, in part, been caused by the historic failure of science to explain why we need it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;suprachiasmatic (pronounced soo-pra-kai-as-MAT-ik)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We require more supple work schedules that better adapt to all chronotypes, and not just one in its extreme.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Be Like the Fox</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-be-like-the-fox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jul 2018 21:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6035</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His design ‘was to write for a tyrant those things that are pleasing to tyrants, bringing about in this way, if he could, the tyrant’s self-willed and swift downfall’.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pole warned; beware of this two-faced writer. ‘For it is the aim of his doctrine to act like a drug that causes princes to go mad,’ making them attack their own people with ‘the savagery of the lion and the wiles of the fox’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Radical Candor</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-radical-candor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 07:45:49 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6024</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you probably know, for every piece of subpar work you accept, for every missed deadline you let slip, you begin to feel resentment and then anger. You no longer just think the work is bad: you think the person is bad. This makes it harder to have an even-keeled conversation. You start to avoid talking to the person at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only reason it was OK for me to talk to Jared that way was because of the relationship we’d formed over the years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for No Name in the Street</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-no-name-in-the-street/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 18:55:27 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6017</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Incontestably, alas, most people are not, in action, worth very much; and yet, every human being is an unprecedented miracle. One tries to treat them as the miracles they are, while trying to protect oneself against the disasters they’ve become.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was not the same, but they were, as though they had been trapped, preserved, in that moment in time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They should have known me better, or at least enough, to have known that I meant what I said. But the general reaction to famous people who hold difficult opinions is that they can’t really mean it. It’s considered, generally, to be merely an astute way of attracting public attention, a way of making oneself interesting: one marches in Montgomery, for example, merely (in my own case) to sell one’s books.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Neoreaction a Basilisk</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-neoreaction-a-basilisk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 19:35:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=6013</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Angela Nagle’s appalling Kill All Normies, which takes the jaw-droppingly foolish methodology of simply reporting all of the alt-right’s self-justifications as self-evident truths so as to conclude that the real reason neo-nazis have been sweeping into power is because we’re too tolerant of trans people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This brings us to our second relatively uninteresting question, which is what to do about the alt-right. In this case the answer is even easier and more obvious than the first: you smash their bases of power, with violent resistance if necessary. If you want a more general solution that also takes care of the factors that led to a bunch of idiot racists being emboldened in the first place you drag all the billionaires out of their houses and put their heads on spikes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Bluets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-bluets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 20:02:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5995</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a simple story, but it spooks me, insofar as it reminds me that the eye is simply a recorder, with or without our will. Perhaps the same could be said of the heart. But whether there is a violence at work here remains undecided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last night I wept in a way I haven’t wept for some time. I wept until I aged myself. I watched it happen in the mirror. I watched the lines arrive around my eyes like engraved sunbursts; it was like watching flowers open in time-lapse on a windowsill.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for A Contest of Ideas</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-a-contest-of-ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 14:35:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5993</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One cannot chart a course of social action without understanding the world in which one lives, works, and struggles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of a system of global supply chains, with their multilayered set of factories, vendors, and transport links, has created a world system in which legal ownership of the forces of production have been divorced from operational control. This shift has generated a system in which accountability for labor conditions is legally diffused and knowledge of the actual producers is far from transparent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Ecology Without Nature</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-ecology-without-nature/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 May 2018 20:37:52 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5989</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To speak thus is to use the aesthetic as an anesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would be unable to cope with modernity unless we had a few pockets of place in which to store our hope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rendering is technically what visual- and sonic-effects artists do to a film to generate a more or less consistent sense of atmosphere or world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;elcphrasis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Texts also exploit negative rhythm to generate tone. The absence of sound or graphic marks can be as potent as their presence. Gaps between stanzas, and other kinds of broken lineation, create tone out of sheer blankness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Broken Angels</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-broken-angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Apr 2018 20:03:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5974</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the very least, you habitually find yourself in unfamiliar bodies on unfamiliar worlds where people are shooting at you. Even on a good day, no amount of briefing can prepare you for a total change of environment like that, and in the invariably unstable to lethally dangerous sets of circumstances the Envoys have been created to deal with, there just isn&amp;rsquo;t any point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is logistically impossible to expect everything, she told us evenly, we will teach you not to expect anything. That way, you will be ready for it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Exit West</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-exit-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 19:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5968</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;but that is the way of things, with cities as with life, for one moment we are pottering about our errands as usual and the next we are dying, and our eternally impending ending does not put a stop to our transient beginnings and middles until the instant when it does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Location, location, location, the realtors say. Geography is destiny, respond the historians.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had begun, each of them, to be penetrated, but they had not yet kissed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Sapiens</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-sapiens/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 22:02:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5964</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humankind paid for its lofty vision and industrious hands with backaches and stiff necks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if the Interbreeding Theory is right, there might well be genetic differences between Africans, Europeans and Asians that go back hundreds of thousands of years. This is political dynamite, which could provide material for explosive racial theories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The foragers may have had their all-conquering Napoleons, who ruled empires half the size of Luxembourg; gifted Beethovens who lacked symphony orchestras but brought people to tears with the sound of their bamboo flutes; and charismatic prophets who revealed the words of a local oak tree rather than those of a universal creator god. But these are all mere guesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Stone Sky</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-stone-sky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2018 20:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5962</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, some worlds are built on a fault line of pain, held up by nightmares. Don’t lament when those worlds fall. Rage that they were built doomed in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He has given up some of who he was, but what remains is still an artist of terror. If he has seen fit to share the secrets of his artistry with them, they’re lucky. She hopes they appreciate it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Obelisk Gate</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-obelisk-gate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 20:11:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5959</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s when you no longer need an answer to the question. There is such a thing as too much loss. Too much has been taken from you both—taken and taken and taken, until there’s nothing left but hope, and you’ve given that up because it hurts too much. Until you would rather die, or kill, or avoid attachments altogether, than lose one more thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not the thought. The thought was simple and predictable: Better to die than live a slave. But what you felt in that moment was a kind of cold, monstrous love. A determination to make sure your son’s life remained the beautiful, wholesome thing that it had been up to that day, even if it meant you had to end his life early.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Fifth Season</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-fifth-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2018 14:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5956</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accepted members of a comm are those who have been accorded rights of cache-share and protection, and who in turn support the comm through taxes or other contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then you stop. Because, oh uncaring Earth. Look what you’ve done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obey the lore, make the hard choices, and maybe when the Season ends there will be people who remember how civilization should work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Likewise, no one speaks of celestial objects, though the skies are as crowded and busy here as anywhere else in the universe. This is largely because so much of the people’s attention is directed toward the ground, not the sky.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Turn the Ship Around</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-turn-the-ship-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:28:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5952</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our world’s bright future will be built by people who have discovered that leadership is the enabling art. It is the art of releasing human talent and potential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leadership is communicating to people their worth and potential so clearly that they are inspired to see it in themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You know, sure, maybe over time things would have improved, but who wants to gamble their career—no, their life energy—on the hope of a sea change at an established, ‘successful’ company. I went on to pursue my dreams, and I’ve done so.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Journey to the End of the Night</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-journey-to-the-end-of-the-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 21:25:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5951</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe our colonel knew why they were shooting, maybe the Germans knew, but I, so help me, hadn&amp;rsquo;t the vaguest idea. As far back as I could search my memory, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t done a thing to the Germans, I&amp;rsquo;d always treated them friendly and polite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that tangled meat was bleeding profusely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The one thing any of us really cared about was living for one more hour, one more hour is a big deal in a world where everything has reduced itself to murder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Good Strategy Bad Strategy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-good-strategy-bad-strategy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 21:22:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5947</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of strategy work is always the same: discovering the critical factors in a situation and designing a way of coordinating and focusing actions to deal with those factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad strategy tends to skip over pesky details such as problems. It ignores the power of choice and focus, trying instead to accommodate a multitude of conflicting demands and interests. Like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To make matters worse, for many people in business, education, and government, the word “strategy”has become a verbal tic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Altered Carbon</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-altered-carbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 20:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5941</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rich people do this. They have the power and they see no reason not to use it. Men and women are just merchandise, like everything else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were no protests — you can&amp;rsquo;t argue with a robot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What had possessed Bancroft to outfit me for summer with the scrambled weather systems that Bay City had so far exhibited was beyond me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shopping is physical interaction, exercise of decision-making capacity, sating of the desire to acquire, and an impulse to more acquisition, a scouting urge. It&amp;rsquo;s so basically flicking human when you think about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for From the Ruins of Empire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-from-the-ruins-of-empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 21:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5936</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It mattered little to which class or race they belonged; the subordinate peoples of the world keenly absorbed the deeper implications — moral and psychological — of Japan’s triumph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They had failed to notice the intense desire for equality and dignity among peoples whom Europe’s most influential thinkers, from Hegel and Marx to John Stuart Mill, had deemed unfit for self-rule — thinkers whose ideas, ironically, would in fact prove highly potent among these ‘subject peoples’.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Kintu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-kintu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 20:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5933</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indeed, this is the challenge of the historical novel: whether or not the stories are true might be the least important thing about them. History as it’s written down in books is one thing, but history as it’s lived is another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Europeans left, educated Ugandans climbed out of the swamps, slaked off the mud, and took to the hills and raw Ugandans flooded the swamps. Up in the hills, educated Ugandans assumed the same contempt as Europeans had for them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for the Art of Not Being Governed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-art-of-not-being-governed/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 08:20:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5838</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the history of those who got away&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the power of the state to deploy distance-demolishing technologies—railroads, all-weather roads, telephone, telegraph, airpower, helicopters, and now information technology—so changed the strategic balance of power between self-governing peoples and nation-states, so diminished the friction of terrain, that my analysis largely ceases to be useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, living in the absence of state structures has been the standard human condition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That frontier operated as a rough and ready homeostatic device; the more a state pressed its subjects, the fewer subjects it had.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for The Coaching Habit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-coaching-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 21:44:46 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5927</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you use “And what else?”you’ll get more options and often better options. Better options lead to better decisions. Better decisions lead to greater success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a place for giving advice, of course. This book isn’t suggesting that you never give anyone an answer ever again. But it’s an overused and often ineffective response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Which is why people in organizations like yours around the world are working very hard and coming up with decent solutions to problems that just don’t matter, and why the real challenges often go unaddressed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Pedagogy of the Oppressed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-pedagogy-of-the-oppressed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 21:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5926</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Critical consciousness, they say, is anarchic. Others add that critical consciousness may lead to disorder.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This, then, is the great humanistic and historical task of the oppressed: to liberate themselves and their oppressors as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The oppressed, having internalized the image of the oppressor and adopted his guidelines, are fearful of freedom. Freedom would require them to eject this image and replace it with autonomy and responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solidarity requires that one enter into the situation of those with whom one is solidary; it is a radical posture.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading 2017</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reading-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2017 20:38:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5917</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most unexpectedly I read 52 books in 2017. These last couple of months I’d been gunning for it but nothing about the first half of this year indicated that I would even hit my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user_challenges/6889434&#34;&gt;challenge of 26 books&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first half of the year was marked by some decidedly slow reading as well as becoming a twin dad. The long and regular naps of young babies along with my parental leave made that a period where I caught up on watching a lot of movies (see the 50 movies in &lt;a href=&#34;https://letterboxd.com/alper/films/diary/&#34;&gt;my Letterboxd diary&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Metaphors We Live By</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-metaphors-we-live-by/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 21:22:29 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5908</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madness and journeys give us handles on the concept of love, and food gives us a handle on the concept of an idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are proposing that the concepts that occur in metaphorical definitions are those that correspond to natural kinds of experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Examples are PHYSICAL ORIENTATIONS, OBJECTS, SUBSTANCES, SEEING, JOURNEYS, WAR, MADNESS, FOOD, BUILDINGS, etc. These concepts for natural kinds of experience and objects are structured clearly enough and with enough of the right kind of internal structure to do the job of defining other concepts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Blindsight and Echopraxia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-blindsight-and-echopraxia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 21:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5896</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world in which Humanity had become redundant in unprecedented numbers, we&amp;rsquo;d both retained the status of another age: working professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Unknown was technologically advanced—and there were some who claimed that that made them hostile by definition. Technology Implies Belligerence, they said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humans didn&amp;rsquo;t really fight over skin tone or ideology; those were just handy cues for kin-selection purposes. Ultimately it always came down to bloodlines and limited resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Never Split the Difference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-never-split-the-difference/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 21:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5898</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every negotiation, in every agreement, the result comes from someone else’s decision. And sadly, if we believe that we can control or manage others’ decisions with compromise and logic, we’re leaving millions on the table. But while we can’t control others’ decisions, we can influence them by inhabiting their world and seeing and hearing exactly what they want.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So don’t settle and—here’s a simple rule—never split the difference. Creative solutions are almost always preceded by some degree of risk, annoyance, confusion, and conflict. Accommodation and compromise produce none of that. You’ve got to embrace the hard stuff. That’s where the great deals are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Financial Strategy for Public Managers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-financial-strategy-for-public-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 21:48:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5894</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing’s executives expect their managers to know this information, in real time, if the company is to remain profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managers need good information about costs to set prices, determine how much of a good or service to deliver, and to manage costs in ways that make their organization more likely to achieve its mission.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public financial resources are finite, scarce, and becoming scarcer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CVP is a powerful tool that can directly illuminate many important management decisions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Blood Meridian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-blood-meridian/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2017 17:51:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5891</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We are dealing with a people manifestly incapable of governing themselves. And do you know what happens with people who cannot govern themselves? That’s right. Others come in to govern for them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no such joy in the tavern as upon the road thereto, said the Mennonite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sproule sat without moving. The kid looked at him but he would look away. He was wounded in an enemy country far from home and although his eyes took in the alien stones about yet the greater void beyond seemed to swallow up his soul.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for the Argonauts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-the-argonauts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 14:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5878</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I was so happy renting in New York City for so long because renting—or at least the way I rented, which involved never lifting a finger to better my surroundings—allows you to let things literally fall apart all around you. Then, when it gets to be too much, you just move on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But any fixed claim on realness, especially when it is tied to an identity, also has a finger in psychosis. If a man who thinks he is a king is mad, a king who thinks he is a king is no less so.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for UX for Lean Startups</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-ux-for-lean-startups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 14:47:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5879</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing will bias a session faster than you trying to sell him on your ideas. You’re not there to talk. You are there to listen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody in the world can possibly tell you whether some abstract concept you just explained will solve a problem that they have. Even if they could somehow understand the wild abstractions you’re presenting them with, they couldn’t honestly tell you whether they would pay money for your solution.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Alibaba: The House That Jack Ma Built</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-alibaba-the-house-that-jack-ma-built/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 14:41:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5880</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that by sharing orders, delivery status, and customer feedback each member company can improve efficiency and service quality, while remaining separately owned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba encourages a sense of informality at work. Every employee is asked to adopt a nickname.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With its constant emphasis on culture and ideology, people at Alibaba refer to HR informally as the “Political Commissar”(zheng wei).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;reducing “time to market,”launching products that they can perfect later, an approach some refer to as “running with short steps.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Dispossessed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-dispossessed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 10:11:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5866</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were walls around all his thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know how it is, what women call thinking is done with the uterus! Of course, there’s always a few exceptions, God-awful brainy women with vaginal atrophy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Entirely on your own initiative,”said Oiie. “It is the only initiative I acknowledge,”Shevek said, smiling, in dead earnest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All such luxuries which if freely allowed to the public would tend to drain irreplaceable natural resources or to foul the environment with waste products were strictly controlled by regulation and taxation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from What Got You Here Won&#39;t Get You There</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-what-got-you-here-wont-get-you-there/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Nov 2017 17:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5861</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful people consistently compare themselves favorably to their peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who believe they can succeed see opportunities where others see threats. They’re not afraid of uncertainty or ambiguity. They embrace it. They want to take greater risks and achieve greater returns. Given the choice, they will always bet on themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successful people have a unique distaste for feeling controlled or manipulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you press people to identify the motives behind their self-interest it usually boils down to four items: money, power, status, and popularity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Discontent and its Civilizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-discontent-and-its-civilizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 10:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5856</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if globalization is capable of holding out any fundamental promise to us, any temptation to go along with its havoc, then surely that promise ought to be this: we will be more free to invent ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What distinguishes the “war on terror”is that it is a war against a concept, not a nation. And the enemy concept, it seems to me, is pluralism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Civilizations are illusions, but these illusions are pervasive, dangerous, and powerful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Reinventing Organizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-reinventing-organizations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 09:02:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5853</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe it has to do with the belief system of our times: in a hierarchical worldview, there can be only one brain in command, just as there must be a single boss at the head of every organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then suddenly, almost out of nowhere, modernity has brought us unprecedented wealth and life expectancy in the last two centuries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is probably no exaggeration, but sad reality, that the very survival of many species, ecosystems, and perhaps the human race itself hinges on our ability to move to higher forms of consciousness and from there collaborate in new ways to heal our relationship with the world and the damage we’ve caused.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Principles of Product Development Flow</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-principles-of-product-development-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 08:56:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5823</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I believe that the dominant paradigm for managing product development is fundamentally wrong.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In practice, sensible behavior prevails, despite the presence of a dysfunctional formal procedure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Third, with a little help from option pricing theory, we will discover that we can actually design development processes such that increases in variability will improve, rather than worsen, our economic performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We favor highly granular planning because we don’t understand the statistics of variability.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Homage to Catalonia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-homage-to-catalonia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 20:26:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5845</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Spaniards are good at many things, but not at making war. All foreigners alike are appalled by their inefficiency, above all their maddening unpunctuality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for some reason all the best matadors were Fascists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When a man refused to obey an order you did not immediately get him punished; you first appealed to him in the name of comradeship. Cynical people with no experience of handling men will say instantly that this would never &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo;, but as a matter of fact it does &amp;lsquo;work&amp;rsquo; in the long run.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Rules for Radicals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-rules-for-radicals/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 20:24:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5846</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The establishment in many ways is as suicidal as some of the far left&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we fail to communicate with them, if we don&amp;rsquo;t encourage them to form alliances with us, they will move to the right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We must first see the world as it is and not as we would like it to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political realists see the world as it is: an arena of power politics moved primarily by perceived immediate self-interests, where morality is rhetorical rationale for expedient action and self-interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from the God of Small Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-god-of-small-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 21:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5839</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Inspector Thomas Mathew seemed to know whom he could pick on and whom he couldn’t. Policemen have that instinct.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some days he walked along the banks of the river that smelled of shit and pesticides bought with World Bank loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He oiled himself with warm, peppered coconut oil, kneading his old, loose flesh that stretched willingly off his bones like chewing gum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the Loss of Sophie Mol grew robust and alive. It was always there. Like a fruit in season. Every season. As permanent as a government job.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Name of the Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/name-of-the-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 21:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5836</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m putting this here so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to keep looking it up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name of the game by John Boyd is moral leverage for grand strategy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preserve or build up our moral authority while compromising that of our adversaries in order to pump up our resolve, drain away adversaries&amp;rsquo; resolve, and attract them as well as others to our cause and way of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Truth of Suffering and the Path of Liberation</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-truth-of-suffering-and-the-path-of-liberation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 21:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5831</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ï»¿&amp;ldquo;Association with those you hate is suffering.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is very hard. It turns out to be quite a handful, quite a project, for us to keep everything at the ideal level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conclusion is that everybody is neurotic, that neurosis creates discomfort and anxiety, and that basic anxiety is happening all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can’t just practice passion, aggression, and ignorance on ourselves alone; we do it to somebody else as well, and someone always gets hurt.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Managing Humans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-managing-humans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 21:26:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5822</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ï»¿&amp;ldquo;You must see the people who work with you.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The presence of rigid, e-mail-based status reports comes down to control, a lack of imagination, and a lack of trust in the organization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The courage it takes to stop this meeting five minutes into the scheduled hour because there is no discernible way to make progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s great that your freak has chosen to freak out. The alternative is that they’re not saying a thing and have decided to leave the company.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Unfortunately, It Was Paradise</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-unfortunately-it-was-paradise/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2017 21:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5809</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here or there, our blood will plant olive trees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ours is a country of words: Talk. Talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ask: Is it true, good ladies and gentlemen, that the earth of Man is for all human beings as you say? In that case, where is my little cottage, and where am I?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can a people be born on a guillotine? We have the right to die any way we wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this hymn we lay a dream, we raise a victory sign, we hold a key to the last door, to lock ourselves in a dream.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from This Earth of Mankind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-this-earth-of-mankind/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 20:53:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5797</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern! How quickly that word had surged forward and multiplied itself like bacteria throughout the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thomas Aquinas, she said, once saw two people who were born in the same year, in the same month, on the same day and at the same hour, even in the same place. The joke played by astrology was that one became a great landowner and the other his slave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his body ran some Native blood. Who knows how many drops or clots.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kritiek naar aanleiding van Hallo Witte Mensen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kritiek-naar-aanleiding-van-hallo-witte-mensen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 14:42:48 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5780</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik heb me de afgelopen weken geërgerd aan en gegeneerd voor de domme venijnige kritieken die het boek &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.aup.nl/books/9789462984141-hallo-witte-mensen.html&#34;&gt;‘Hallo Witte Mensen’ van Anousha Nzume&lt;/a&gt; kreeg. Zoals de uitgever van het boek Ebissé Rouw zegt: Nederland is een &lt;em&gt;intellectual wasteland&lt;/em&gt;. We zijn nu eenmaal een klein taalgebied waar iedereen zich heel slim en onschuldig kan voelen door het Engelstalige debat over een onderwerp compleet te missen en zelf wat bij elkaar te verzinnen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from We Have Never Been Modern</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-we-have-never-been-modern/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2017 09:36:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5777</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Let us not mix up heaven and earth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In works produced by anthropologists abroad, you will not find a single trait that is not simultaneously real, social and narrated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ethnologist will certainly not write three separate books: one dealing with knowledge, another with power, yet another with practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the representation of nonhumans belongs to science, but science is not allowed to appeal to politics; the representation of citizens belongs to politics, but politics is not allowed to have any relation to the nonhumans produced and mobilized by science and technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Name of the Rose</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-name-of-the-rose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 14:53:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5743</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ï»¿&amp;ldquo;there are also visions of books as yet unwritten.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He seemed unable to think save with his hands, an attribute I considered then worthier of a mechanic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such is the power of the truth that, like good, it is its own propagator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It does not seem to me that they were preaching things contrary to the Gospel, but when the session of earthly things is in question, it is difficult for men to reason justly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Open City</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-open-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2017 18:51:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5733</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A grouch through and through, but it was he who first taught me the value of memory, and how to think of it as mental music, a setting to iambs and trochees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were all confused about what was happening; we were American, had always thought ourselves so, and not Japanese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was I, no less solitary than he but having made the lesser use of the morning, who was to be pitied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Blue Mars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-blue-mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2017 11:21:44 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5706</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it might have been only a temporary confluence of interests, but everything was temporary now— with so many traditions broken or vanished, it left what John used to call the necessity of creation;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were apolitical, supposedly, like civil servants— empiricists, who only wanted things managed in a rational scientific style, the greatest good for the greatest number, which ought to be fairly simple to arrange, if people were not so trapped in emotions, religions, governments, and other mass delusional systems of that sort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Extreme Ownership: How U.S. Navy SEALs Lead and Win</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-extreme-ownership-how-u-s-navy-seals-lead-and-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 15:15:10 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5704</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right decision, even when all seems lost, can snatch victory from the jaws of defeat. The wrong decision, even when a victorious outcome seems all but certain, can result in deadly, catastrophic failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They must literally risk life and limb to accomplish the mission. For this reason, they must believe in the cause for which they are fighting. They must believe in the plan they are asked to execute, and most important, they must believe in and trust the leader they are asked to follow.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Lathe of Heaven</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-lathe-of-heaven/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2017 15:03:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5701</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The insistent permissiveness of the late Twentieth Century had produced fully as much sex-guilt and sex-fear in its heirs as had the insistent repressiveness of the late Nineteenth Century.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was an acceptant, passive quality about him that seemed feminine, or even childish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No doubt Haber had a lot of ambition and found it hard to believe that a man could be without it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He arrived at ideas the slow way, never skating over the clear, hard ice of logic, nor soaring on the slipstreams of imagination, but slogging, plodding along on the heavy ground of existence.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books and movies of 2016</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/books-and-movies-of-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 13:16:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5691</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Like every year the books I read and the movies I watched. Recommended ones are in bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;books&#34;&gt;Books&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book situation was shameful but instead of reading a lot of books, I wrote &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32560547-designing-conversational-interfaces?from_search=true&#34;&gt;“Designing Conversational Interfaces”&lt;/a&gt;, so I&amp;rsquo;ll call that even.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;PACE: A Small Business Owner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to Complete Cash Flow Clarity&amp;rdquo; Jesse Mecham&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Agile Game Development with Scrum&amp;rdquo; by Keith Clinton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Americanah&amp;rdquo; by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The $1 Prototype: A Modern Approach to Mobile UX Design and Rapid Innovation&amp;rdquo; by Greg Nudelman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Slouching Towards Bethlehem&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Joan Didion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;The iPhone App Design Manual: Create Perfect Designs for Effortless Coding and App Store Success&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mobile Web Designer&amp;rsquo;s Idea Book: The Ultimate Guide to Trends, Themes and Styles in Mobile Web Design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Factotum&amp;rdquo; by Charles Bukowski&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Mobile Design Pattern Gallery: UI Patterns for Smartphone Apps&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Master and Margarita&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Mikhail Bulgakov&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Science, Strategy and War: The Strategic Theory of John Boyd&amp;rdquo; by Frans Osinga&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;So Good They Can&amp;rsquo;t Ignore You: Why Skills Trump Passion in the Quest for Work You Love&amp;rdquo; by Cal Newport&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Green Mars&amp;rdquo; by Kim Stanley Robinson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Dictator&amp;rsquo;s Handbook: Why Bad Behavior is Almost Always Good Politics&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; by Bruce Bueno de Mesquita&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;movies&#34;&gt;Movies&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This went a lot better with 72 if you count the individual installments of the Decalogue.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Lean UX</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-lean-ux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 12:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5683</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We went over to the client’s office and spent an entire eight-hour day going over each and every pixel and word in that deck. When it was over, the client clapped (really). They loved it. We were relieved. And we never looked at that deck again. Six months after that meeting, nothing had changed on the client’s site. I don’t think they ever looked at that deck again, either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s also for developers who understand that a collaborative team environment leads to better code and more meaningful work.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Green Mars</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-green-mars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 11:58:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5681</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kuhn had written about Priestley— that a scientist who continued to resist after his whole profession had been converted to a new paradigm might be perfectly logical and reasonable, but had ipso facto ceased to be a scientist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He won every argument but never got anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So in the current political situation, information technology was creating not totalization but balkanization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was fairly humorous to see how responsive mood was to chemical manipulation, despite what it implied about the precarious balance of one’s emotional equanimity, even sanity itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Dictator&#39;s Handbook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-dictators-handbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:39:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5676</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In fact, bad behavior is more often than not good politics.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It is hard to imagine that anyone, including ourselves, cares much about what we think ought to be. Neither do we exhort others to be better than they are.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Why do leaders do what they do? To come to power, to stay in power and, to the extent that they can, to keep control over money.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If we are going to play the game of politics, and we all must from time to time, then we ought to learn how to win the game.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Science, Strategy and War by Frans Osinga</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-science-strategy-and-war-by-frans-osinga/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 12:41:20 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5624</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This network is the seat of scientific opinion; it is split into thousands of fragments, held by a multitude of individuals, each of whom endorses the others’ opinion at second hand, by relying on the consensual chains which link him to all the others through a sequence of overlapping neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of science/engineering and the pursuit of technology permit us to continually rematch our mental/physical orientation with that of the changing world so that we can continue to thrive and grow in it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Master and Margarita by MikhaÃ­l Afanasyevich Bulgakov</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-master-and-margarita-by-mikhail-afanasyevich-bulgakov/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2016 14:30:05 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5622</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Riukhin sat in complete solitude, hunched over his bream, drinking glass after glass, understanding and recognizing that it was no longer possible to set anything right in his life, that it was only possible to forget.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘Yesterday, in your office, I saw this individuum briefly, but it only takes a fleeting glance at his face to understand that he is a bastard, a squabbler, a trimmer and a toady.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today I’m an unofficial person, and tomorrow, lo and behold, I’m an official one! And it also happens the other way round — oh, how it does!’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Slouching Towards Bethlehem by Joan Didion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-slouching-towards-bethlehem-by-joan-didion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 21:48:56 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5620</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is one last thing to remember: writers are always selling somebody out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The future always looks good in the golden land, because no one remembers the past.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a place where little is bright or graceful, where it is routine to misplace the future and easy to start looking for it in bed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joan Baez was a personality before she was entirely a person, and, like anyone to whom that happens, she is in a sense the hapless victim of what others have seen in her, written about her, wanted her to be and not to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Americanah by Chimamanda Ngozi Adichie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-americanah-by-chimamanda-ngozi-adichie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 21:36:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5617</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was something immodest about her modesty: it announced itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But Ifemelu had always sensed, in Sister Ibinabo, a deep-sown, simmering hostility to young girls. Sister Ibinabo did not like them, she merely watched them and warned them, as though offended by what in them was still fresh and in her was long dried up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the easy relationship between two people who carefully avoided conversations of any depth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was tall and rangy, with the easy manner of the entitled.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Ancillary Justice by Ann Leckie</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-ancillary-justice-by-ann-leckie/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 21:32:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5615</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you shoot a person, you say why and do it, without excuse. This is how the Radchaai are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was old enough to know firsthand that we had, indeed, shot people in the past. She could hardly be blamed for fearing we might do so in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There had been a time when a property owner like her would have been shot early on, so someone’s client could take over her plantation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Invisible Cities by Italo Calvino</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-for-invisible-cities-by-italo-calvino/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 15:39:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5613</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory is redundant: it repeats signs so that the city can begin to exist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps, Kublai thought, the empire is nothing but a zodiac of the mind’s phantasms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the emperor is he who is a foreigner to each of his subjects,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;that the more one was lost in unfamiliar quarters of distant cities, the more one understood the other cities he had crossed to arrive there;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, from that real or hypothetical past of his, he is excluded; he cannot stop; he must go on to another city, where another of his pasts awaits him, or something perhaps that had been a possible future of his and is now someone else’s present.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Certain to Win by Chet Richards</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-for-certain-to-win-by-chet-richards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 14:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5608</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;War strategies, however, rest on a deeper foundation of people working together under stress and uncertainty, and good ones shape the terms of the conflict to their liking before combat begins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the commanders had, at best, was information about the enemy within a few miles of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than dig in and “consolidate his position,”or otherwise savor the fruits of victory, he proceeded to use his advantage in time to neutralize his opponents’ forces and weapons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights for Red Mars by Kim Stanley Robinson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-for-red-mars-by-kim-stanley-robinson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 14:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5606</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Whenever scientists say they’re Christian,”Sax said, “I take it to be an aesthetic statement.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You Americans would like to end politics and history, so you can stay in a world you dominate!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evolution is a matter of environment and chance, acting over millions of years. But history is a matter of environment and choice, acting within lifetimes, and sometimes within years, or months, or days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mutual professional respect, a great maker of friendships. And so nice to talk nothing but business.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New book â€œDesigning Conversational Interfacesâ€</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/writing-a-book-on-conversational-interfaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 16:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5581</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spent June until October writing a brief but comprehensive book called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.convbook.com/&#34;&gt;“Designing Conversational Interfaces”&lt;/a&gt; introducing the creation of messaging applications and chatbots to a non-technical audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can purchase the book on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.convbook.com/&#34;&gt;Gumroad&lt;/a&gt; or review it on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/32560547-designing-conversational-interfaces&#34;&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gumroad.com/l/convbook&#34;&gt;Loading&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The year in culture</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-year-in-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2015 15:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5450</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a personal log of culture consumed going back to 2003. This year was a particular low on many counts. I have been busy and I don&amp;rsquo;t ascribe the same value to consuming culture pure for the goal of consuming it anymore. Been there, done that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve read eleven books (see my &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/user/show/841048-alper-ugun&#34;&gt;Goodreads&lt;/a&gt;) which is more than I had expected but nothing compared compared to the bookwormy prowess of people like &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.hansdezwart.nl/2015/12/31/the-books-i-read-in-2015/&#34;&gt;Hans&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;http://leapfrog.nl/blog/archives/2015/12/31/books-ive-read-in-2015/&#34;&gt;Kars&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terry Pratchett</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/terry-pratchett/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2015 17:19:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5192</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the best photo ever taken of Terry Pratchett, and indeed one of the best photos ever taken of anybody &lt;a href=&#34;http://t.co/p1JCQtfX05&#34;&gt;pic.twitter.com/p1JCQtfX05&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— Mitch Edgeworth (@mitchedgeworth) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mitchedgeworth/status/576134285268262913&#34;&gt;March 12, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I didn&amp;rsquo;t read him for very long, Terry Pratchett&amp;rsquo;s books in the local library translated to Dutch were my introduction to both fantasy and a certain kind of critical way of looking at the world. Only now I&amp;rsquo;m finding out how many other people were deeply influenced by Pratchett. I&amp;rsquo;m also glad to see how a literary establishment that had studiously ignored him and all genre fiction for all that time now has no other choice but to admit that they were wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acemoglu&#39;s Critique on Piketty</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/acemoglus-critique-on-piketty/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Aug 2014 15:09:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5030</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read &lt;a href=&#34;http://economics.mit.edu/files/9834&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; by Acemoglu and Robinson right after I read the book by Piketty thinking that there would be some interesting economic debate. Unfortunately I was proved wrong and this seems to be exemplary for the stagnation of the economic field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s extremely selective nitpicking, some qualms with definitions and arguing about semantics. In those places where Piketty actually writes the same thing as them, they don&amp;rsquo;t mention it in their paper. This means that they have either not read the book or that they are being disingenuous.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Holiday Reading: The Information by James Gleick</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/holiday-reading-the-information-by-james-gleick/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 11:15:59 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=5022</guid> 
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The new technology was both the virus and the vector of transmission.”— Walter J. Ong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;Shannonmouse.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Shannonmouse&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/holiday-reading-the-information-by-james-gleick/Shannonmouse.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was one of the three books I read during my holiday in a cabin on the Austrian Alps. To hedge against a lack of sun hours to charge my reading device with I brought some physical books that had been lingering on my moribund to-read pile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure if ‘The Information’ would be worth reading as a graduate in computer science but it turns out that it is as fantastic a book as everybody said it was.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading more about the social</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/reading-more-about-the-social/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 10:08:58 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4911</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As of right now I&amp;rsquo;m frightfully behind on my Latour MOOC. What I have been doing instead is reading up old articles in my Instapaper. One such is this &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vn.nl/Archief/Samenleving/Artikel-Samenleving/Laten-we-weer-utopisch-denken.htm&#34;&gt;interview with Dutch sociologist/philosopher Willem Schinkel in Vrij Nederland&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s good to read a fresh Dutch thinker who seems to understand things (and who also &lt;a href=&#34;http://scholar.google.de/scholar?hl=en&amp;amp;q=willem+schinkel+latour&amp;amp;btnG=&amp;amp;as_sdt=1%2C5&amp;amp;as_sdtp=&#34;&gt;is in with Latour&lt;/a&gt;). Calling Geert Wilders a proto-fascist and the Netherlands a museum are only a couple of the ringers in there.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Unwinding by George Packer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-unwinding-by-george-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 08:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4869</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This got stuck in my draft queue but I have no idea what to meaningfully add to this absurd amount of highlights. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/17139513-the-unwinding&#34;&gt;The Unwinding by George Packer&lt;/a&gt; is a massive and amazing work with turns of phrase worth remembering on every page. It also shows very precisely how amazingly fucked up the USA is right about now. Here is the book cut up through my lens, but I would highly encourage you to read the whole thing (I tore through it in a couple of days).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from The Pleasures and Sorrows of Work by Alain de Botton</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-pleasures-and-sorrows-of-work-by-alain-de-botton/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2014 08:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4864</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This book by Alain de Botton started out slowly for me because I am already quite familiar with the global logistical infrastructure and the various ways our food is made (thanks to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://keuringsdienstvanwaarde.kro.nl/&#34;&gt;Keuringsdienst van Waarde&lt;/a&gt;). In the second half though with its focus on the moral and spiritual aspects did it pick up and became a very worthwhile read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How ignorant most of us are by contrast, surrounded by machines and processes of which we have only the loosest grasp;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from The Drowned Cities by Paulo Bacigalupi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-drowned-cities-by-paulo-bacigalupi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 00:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4861</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not hugely satisfying but still a nice read. Supposedly the first book in this series is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A hasty temper was one of the greatest faults a general could have, and people who were provoked by insults were easy to defeat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You think China’s sending in peacekeepers again?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the sea levels rose, they built huge dikes to protect their coastlines, and floated their greatest cities on the waves, like they did with Island Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes for Against the Smart City by Adam Greenfield</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-for-against-the-smart-city-by-adam-greenfield/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2013 08:23:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4839</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://speedbird.wordpress.com/2013/09/28/against-the-smart-city-now-available-for-purchase-in-kindle/&#34;&gt;pamphlet by Adam Greenfield&lt;/a&gt;, the first of more is a concise and enjoyable distillation of his politics when it concerns the smart city and also features a number of similarly inclined thinkers:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this light, the casual contempt for history that is part and parcel of Koolhaas&amp;rsquo;s generic city and the comparable conceptions of urbanity we find in the canonical smart cities feels particularly glib, adolescent and unsatisfactory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a city can even be said to have any such quality as intelligence to begin with, that intelligence is bound to be singular, something that subsists in the unique lifeways, cultures and pragmatic local adaptations that have evolved in a particular place.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from the Rum Diary by Hunter S. Thompson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-the-rum-diary-by-hunter-s-thompson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2013 18:22:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4836</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a tremendously enjoyable read. I wonder why my English teacher never pointed us in this literary direction for things to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He cursed the “goddamn shitting heat”with such violence and such hatred that it sometimes ruined the atmosphere of the place&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;everything from wild young Turks who wanted to rip the world in half and start all over again &amp;ndash; to tired, beer-bellied old hacks who wanted nothing more than to live out their days in peace before a bunch of lunatics ripped the world in half.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lazy intellectualism exposed (probably without consequences)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/lazy-intellectualism-exposed-probably-without-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 16:05:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4830</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Funny to come across three pieces today wherein a bunch of fashionable faux-intellectuals are taken apart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lrb.co.uk/v35/n21/joshua-cohen/no-one-hates-him-more&#34;&gt;Franzen in the LRB&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He writes against blogs, yet allows a comparison between Die Fackel and blogs; he writes about the way the internet disturbs the reading experience, but does it in pages bracketed into German and English sections and in notes that confuse me more than anything I read online — that confuse me more than the Talmud. He writes about competition and the work ethic, but never mentions his own Heine: David Foster Wallace, a master of the nuanced citation who managed to be both smarter and more casual, crazier and kinder.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Infinite Jest by David Foster Wallace</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-infinite-jest-by-david-foster-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 15:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4470</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reading this book took me quite some time since it &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3200604927/&#34;&gt;arrived in my mailbox&lt;/a&gt; some four years ago. I only picked it up after acquiring an epub version of it that I could read in &lt;a href=&#34;https://readmill.com/books/infinite-jest&#34;&gt;Readmill&lt;/a&gt; wherever I happened to find myself (so also really after Readmill launched their iPhone app). It takes some getting into but this book is hugely rewarding and a pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;it was somehow sadistic-seeming, like drilling a peephole in the wall of a handicapped bathroom.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Boyd: The Fighter Pilot Who Changed the Art of War</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-boyd-the-fighter-pilot-who-changed-the-art-of-war/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2013 07:28:54 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4814</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another long overdue post with notes from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/38840.Boyd?ac=1&#34;&gt;the biography of Colonel John Boyd&lt;/a&gt;. This is partially so long overdue because extracting quotes from Readmill is somewhat annoying and the excellent API integration &lt;a href=&#34;http://boxofquotes.javierarce.com/&#34;&gt;Box of Quotes&lt;/a&gt; no longer works ((Building things on top of APIs looks to be a thing of the past for anything serious or meant to run longer than one week.)).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He quoted Sophocles: “One must wait until the evening to see how splendid the day has been.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Aramis by Bruno Latour</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-aramis-by-bruno-latour/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 19:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4812</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I finished Aramis ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://dss-edit.com/plu/Latour-B_Aramis-or-Love-of-Technology_1996.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;) a couple of weeks ago and this is absolutely essential reading for anybody involved with technology in a wider sense than just technology. It is also quite funny. I look forward to reading more by Bruno Latour, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bruno-latour.fr/node/252&#34;&gt;An Inquiry into the Modes of Existence&lt;/a&gt; is high on my list ((Though unfortunately not available as an ebook.)) and I&amp;rsquo;ve registered to join &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.france-universite-numerique-mooc.fr/courses/SciencesPo/05004/Trimestre_1_2014/about&#34;&gt;his MOOC on the Scientific Humanities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for life is a state of uncertainty and risk, of fragile adaptation to a past and present environment that the future cannot judge.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dark Matter &amp; Trojan Horses Highlights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dark-matter-trojan-horses-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 07:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4244</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Odd that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gotten around to blogging these notes from Dan Hill&amp;rsquo;s brilliant book, but here they are then finally:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is all underscored by an optimistic belief in progressive change, that the current conditions are changeable for the better, that the present can be transformed into multiple positive futures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the mental agility to generate ideas — to see design as cultural invention — is directly linked to the craft skills of design practice&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Apply your philosophy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/apply-your-philosophy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2013 15:12:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4738</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been on something of an applied philosophy ((I&amp;rsquo;m not a big fan of the other kind.)) binge recently and after almost finishing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.de/Boyd-The-Fighter-Pilot-Changed/dp/0316796883/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1376991962&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=Boyd%3A+The+Fighter+Pilot+Who+Changed+the+Art+of+War&#34;&gt;“Boyd: The Fighter Pilot Who Changed the Art of War”&lt;/a&gt; ((This is actually a biography and not exactly the kind of book I was looking for but it provides a good overview of the various disciplines that Boyd influenced. I will have to and will read the PhD thesis “Science Strategy and War”by Frans Osinga for the in depth treatment of his theories.)) I am now starting to read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/667397.Aramis_or_the_Love_of_Technology&#34;&gt;Aramis&lt;/a&gt; which Latour opens with:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from The Quantum Thief by Hannu Rajaniemi</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-quantum-thief-highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2013 09:34:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4562</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Quantum_Thief&#34;&gt;The Quantum Thief&lt;/a&gt; was a very stimulating read. Make no mistake. However far off the events in this book may seem, Rajaniemi manages to evoke concepts and create language for issues that we are already dealing with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The All-Defector. The thing that never cooperates and gets away with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;summons the combat autism the pellegrini built into her. It enfolds her like a cool blanket, turns the world into vectors and gravity wells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from the Elementary Particles by Michel Houellebecq</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-the-elementary-particles-by-michel-houellebecq/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2013 07:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4467</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an interesting read and only strengthens my resolve to read most of the things Houellebecq has written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It required no creativity, no imagination and only the most basic second-rate intellect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would be true to say that in the last years of Western civilization it contributed to a general mood of depression bordering on masochism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happiness is an intense, all-consuming feeling of joyous fulfillment akin to inebriation, rapture or ecstasy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books read in 2012</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/books-read-in-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2013 08:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4218</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All of the books I read are to be found &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/user/show/841048-alper-ugun&#34;&gt;on Goodreads&lt;/a&gt; but here is my year&amp;rsquo;s overview because it is customary to do these things. I count 23 which is not too shabby but should be improved upon (always).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sandman: Endless Nights Gaiman, Neil&lt;/strong&gt; Getting around to finishing all of the Sandman. Somewhat indulgent but still a very well done multi-mythology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Invisibles Omnibus Morrison, Grant&lt;/strong&gt; A hugely important graphic novel. Also mind expanding in all the good ways that are necessary for a broad view of the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who still thinks in Germany?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/who-still-thinks-in-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2013 10:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4066</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;German friends some things need to be written but don&amp;rsquo;t take them personally. If anything, as I write below, this presents a very large opportunity for who will take it.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had my misgivings about what passes for intellectualism in Germany both in the newspapers and in the public debate. Germans pride themselves on being a country of &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dichter_und_Denker&#34;&gt;Dichter und Denker&lt;/a&gt; (poets and thinkers) but traces of both are thin on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mailing books within Germany</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/mailing-books-within-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2013 15:25:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4022</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/3200604927/&#34; title=&#34;Amazon.com by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Amazon.com&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.staticflickr.com/3346/3200604927_5508e9388d.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I learned that the German mail service has a special rate for mailing books because if you use normal package rates, shipping books becomes prohibitively difficult for more purposes ((Something I found out when I tried to sell my library second hand. Besides the absurd amount of work, sending books away in the Netherlands amounted to taking a loss.)). So there&amp;rsquo;s a special tariff for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deutschepost.de/dpag?xmlFile=link1015117_893&#34;&gt;“Büchersendung”&lt;/a&gt; and it is incredibly cheap: €1,00 for a half kilo book or €1,65 to ship a kilogram of paper anywhere you would like within Germany.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes from Consider the Lobsterâ€¦</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-from-consider-the-lobster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 08:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=4004</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read Consider the Lobster as a bit of a reprieve from the book guilt Infinite Jest still casts over my night stand and as a long overdue requiem to the literary colossus DFW is. Here&amp;rsquo;s the stuff I found noteworthy:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;forked dorsally over the knee of a morbidly obese cellphone retailer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turned out that the LAPD detective found adult films moving, in fact far more so than most mainstream Hollywood movies&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality (until chapter 85)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-harry-potter-and-the-methods-of-rationality-until-chapter-85/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 07:58:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3897</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently discovered the fan fiction &lt;a href=&#34;http://hpmor.com/&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality&lt;/a&gt; by the esteemed &lt;a href=&#34;http://wiki.lesswrong.com/wiki/Eliezer&#34;&gt;Eliezer Yudkowsky&lt;/a&gt; (I used to read his friendly AI stuff back in the day) and having never read any Harry Potter ((I watched the movies.)) I still immensely enjoyed this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In science our powers wax by the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to rule the universe. I just think it could be more sensibly organised.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star Wars was the only universe in which the answer actually was that you were supposed to cut yourself off completely from negative emotions&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from Common Sense</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/highlights-from-common-sense/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2012 07:51:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3893</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I read this pamphlet (at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gutenberg.org/ebooks/3755&#34;&gt;Gutenberg&lt;/a&gt;) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thomas_Paine&#34;&gt;Thomas Paine&lt;/a&gt; a while back on a mountain. However short it may be it packs a massive punch and is brimful with powerful rhetoric. It also contains a rather definitive argument against monarchy. Highly recommended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, Because it tends to the decrease and reproach of all religion whatever, and is of the utmost danger to society to make it a party in political disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the very publishing it proves, that either, ye do not believe what ye profess, or have not virtue enough to practise what ye believe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Prince of Networks Notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/the-prince-of-networks-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2012 21:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3592</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I finished the Prince of Networks (which is in fact &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.re-press.org/book-files/OA_Version_780980544060_Prince_of_Networks.pdf&#34;&gt;available for free online&lt;/a&gt; and I recommend you read it, though &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bogost.com/blog/alien_phenomenology_or_what_it.shtml&#34;&gt;Alien Phenomenology&lt;/a&gt; may be a more concise and lighter introduction into speculative realism) by &lt;a href=&#34;http://doctorzamalek2.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Graham Harman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I must say I&amp;rsquo;m quite impressed by the clarity and breadth of thought that Harman and many of the philosophers in that current express. This interview ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2012/06/an-interview-with-graham-harman/&#34;&gt;my excerpts from it&lt;/a&gt;) with him contained some insights and phrases that I had not seen expressed before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An interview with Graham Harman</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/an-interview-with-graham-harman/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2012 12:34:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3587</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&#34;http://skepoet.wordpress.com/2012/06/01/marginalia-on-radical-thinking-an-interview-with-graham-harman/&#34;&gt;interview with Graham Harman&lt;/a&gt; is filled with valuable tidbits, some of which I wanted to collect and share for your reading pleasure as much as mine:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And like it or not, Apple and Amazon are stirring up more interest, even among intellectuals, than most academic critiques of capitalism. Is that just because we are all a bunch of brainwashed idiots locked in on our own trivial conveniences? Hardly. It’s because these companies are also doing something exciting that addresses where consciousness really is today, and which it didn’t know that it wanted. Did I know in advance that my brain would catch fire as soon as I had a smartphone and a tablet computer? Not at all. I initially thought both of these things were consumerist pseudo-needs, just like the academic Left still does. But I was wrong, and so were they. To have the right electronic device in your hands can sharpen your brain as much as the discovery of an important new author.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cultural Consumption 2011</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/cultural-consumption-2011/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2012 16:49:47 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3205</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I dived into my log to make the yearly tally of what I did and saw. All in all 2011 has proven to be a good year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a bit of a slow movie year though. I only saw 56, the best of which were: &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/drive&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Drive&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/melancholia&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Melancholia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/once-upon-time-anatolia&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once Upon a Time in Anatolia&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/blue-valentine&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Blue Valentine&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/norwegian-wood&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Norwegian Wood&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/true-grit&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;True Grit&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/almanya&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Almanya&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cineville.nl/films/tinker-tailor-soldier-spy&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Tinker Tailor Soldier Spy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt1371574/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Kosmos&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to 32 plays in 2011. The best ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.schaubuehne.de/de_DE/program/detail/9131246&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Die Macht der Finsternis&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; in die Schaubühne&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ntgent.be/productie/het-meisje-dat-te-veel-van-lucifers-hield&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Het meisje dat teveel van lucifers hield&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by NTGent in Frascati WG&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wunderbaum.nl/Songs%20at%20the%20end%20of%20the%20world.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Songs at the End of the World&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Wunderbaum in SSBA&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.toneelgroepamsterdam.nl/default.asp?path=cb3a2j7l&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;De Russen!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Toneelgroep Amsterdam at the Holland Festival&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.g-v.fr/creations/ve-thisishowyouwilldisappear-frameset.htm&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;This is how you will disappear&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by Gisèle Vienne in Stadsschouwburg Utrecht (back at the Kaai &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.g-v.fr/ve-agenda.htm&#34;&gt;in February&lt;/a&gt;!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.barreland.nl/content/langs-de-grote-weg&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Langs de grote weg&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; by de Vere in Frascati&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read 21 books in 2011. The most notable of those were:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Week 247</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/week-247/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 17:49:26 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=3134</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Another week and another change at the office. One thing that does define the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opencooperatie.nl/&#34;&gt;Open Coop&lt;/a&gt; is that everything is in a constant state of flux adding jitter so none of us remain stuck in a local optimum. The global optimum we are shooting for in and around our location in North is rather ridiculous but best not shared in public.
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/6460706915/&#34; title=&#34;Yet another new desk by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Yet another new desk&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm8.staticflickr.com/7164/6460706915_a8b6b72e48.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De studio uit, de wereld in</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-studio-uit-de-wereld-in/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 07:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2843</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ian Bogost, videogame-filosoof, publiceerde een tijdje geleden een kritiek op de geesteswetenschappen (&lt;a href=&#34;http://bogost.com&#34;&gt;http://bogost.com&lt;/a&gt; — “Beyond the Elbow-patched Playground”) die moeite hebben uit te leggen waar ze voor dienen ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bogost.com/blog/beyond_the_elbow-patched_playg.shtml&#34;&gt;deel 1&lt;/a&gt;) en niet weten wat ze met het internet aan moeten ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bogost.com/blog/beyond_the_elbow-patched_playg_1.shtml&#34;&gt;deel 2&lt;/a&gt;). Bogost rekent af met academici die zich afzonderen in de ondoordringbare vestingen van hun vakgebied en te weinig relevant zijn voor mensen daarbuiten. Bas Heijnes recent verschenen essay &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bol.com/nl/p/nederlandse-boeken/echt-zien/1001004006945732/index.html&#34;&gt;‘Echt zien’&lt;/a&gt; past eenzelfde redenering toe op de ‘zieke’ roman. Het is nuttig om deze twee redeneringen tegen de kunst- en cultuursector aan te houden. Na de debatten heeft die zich teruggetrokken maar —het lijkt— geen echte lessen getrokken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victims of Extremistan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/victims-of-extremistan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2011 14:03:32 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2960</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought this piece: &lt;a href=&#34;http://fantasticlife.posterous.com/amazon-and-the-reintermediation-of-the-specta&#34;&gt;“Amazon and the reintermediation of the spectacle”&lt;/a&gt; my Michael Smethurst was well worth reading. Here are some choice excerpts, but these are mainly for me. You should read the entire thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software is what we write to extract information from data. The worse your data model is, the more software you have to write.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fact that we will not enter a Golden Age of Reading because of corporate control, may be the greatest loss (in opportunity cost) the digitization of books will bring us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De science-fiction van nu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-science-fiction-van-nu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2011 06:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2951</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik probeer mijn &lt;a href=&#34;http://literaturfest.nl/&#34;&gt;literaire vrienden&lt;/a&gt; aan het verstand te brengen dat door de technologisering van de samenleving science-fiction een niet meer te negeren onderdeel van de cultuur aan het worden is.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeken zoals &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Super_Sad_True_Love_Story&#34;&gt;‘Super Sad True Love Story’&lt;/a&gt; van Shteyngart en &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.vn.nl/boeken/fictie/de-kaart-en-het-gebied-michel-houellebecq/&#34;&gt;‘De kaart en het gebied’&lt;/a&gt; van Houellebecq zijn feitelijk al science-fiction. Aan de andere kant is er science-fiction die de rand van het nu mogelijke bewandelt en ons laat zien hoe de nabije toekomst eruit zou kunnen zien.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes about Thoughts on Interaction Design by John Kolko</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/notes-about-thoughts-on-interaction-design-by-john-kolko/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jun 2011 11:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2647</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We read &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thoughtsoninteraction.com/&#34;&gt;Thoughts on Interaction Design&lt;/a&gt; 2nd edition as the fifth book for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/groups?mostPopular=&amp;amp;gid=1795982&#34;&gt;UX Book Club Amsterdam&lt;/a&gt; and reviewed it yesterday. Here are my noteworthy passages from the book, which is not without its issues, but it does give a credible philosophical foundation for our practice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;p.34 A mature designer respects and embraces the often ill-structured nature of the process and —because he knows to expect messiness during the act of creation— he promptly forgets about it completely. Process becomes innate, and the phenomenon of design intuition takes over.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1001 boeken die je gelezen moet hebben</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/1001-boeken-die-je-gelezen-moet-hebben/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 10:31:17 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=295</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Een rare lijst &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kottke.org/remainder/08/05/15642.html&#34;&gt;via Kottke&lt;/a&gt;, maar er staan wel wat goede boeken op (dat kan ook niet anders als je 1001 boeken op een lijst zet). Ik kom op 33.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything is Illuminated — Jonathan Safran Foer*
Atonement — Ian McEwan*
Life of Pi — Yann Martel*
House of Leaves — Mark Z. Danielewski
Cryptonomicon — Neal Stephenson*
Disgrace — J.M. Coetzee*
The Discovery of Heaven — Harry Mulisch
American Psycho — Bret Easton Ellis
Love in the Time of Cholera — Gabriel GarcÃ­a Márquez
The Wasp Factory — Iain Banks
The Unbearable Lightness of Being — Milan Kundera
Neuromancer — William Gibson
Waiting for the Barbarians — J.M. Coetzee*
The Crying of Lot 49 — Thomas Pynchon
Cat’s Cradle — Kurt Vonnegut*
Stranger in a Strange Land — Robert Heinlein
Catch-22 — Joseph Heller ((Ik zet hem er alvast op omdat ik hem in een week of twee ga lezen. Ligt bovenop mijn stapeltje.))
The Lord of the Rings — J.R.R. Tolkien
Lolita — Vladimir Nabokov
Lord of the Flies — William Golding
The Old Man and the Sea — Ernest Hemingway
The Catcher in the Rye — J.D. Salinger
Nineteen Eighty-Four — George Orwell
Animal Farm — George Orwell
The Hobbit — J.R.R. Tolkien
At the Mountains of Madness — H.P. Lovecraft
Brave New World — Aldous Huxley*
The Trial — Franz Kafka ((In het Duits.))
The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn — Mark Twain
Through the Looking Glass, and What Alice Found There — Lewis Carroll
Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland — Lewis Carroll
Max Havelaar — Multatuli ((Ik heb medelijden met de niet-Nederlanders die dit gaan lezen.))
Metamorphoses — Ovid ((Wat verhalen gelezen in het Latijn.))&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carr&#39;s self-interest</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/carrs-self-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2011 15:58:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2505</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a bunch being said about Nicholas Carr&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theshallowsbook.com/&#34;&gt;“The Shallows”&lt;/a&gt;. Most notably a lot of print media jumping onto the the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/arts/critics/atlarge/2011/02/14/110214crat_atlarge_gopnik&#34;&gt;Ever-Betters&lt;/a&gt; bandwagon. Obviously Carr stating that reading long form print is being drowned out by the internet is right up the alley of the old media in their death throes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That clinging of the moribund is however just a side-effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carr&amp;rsquo;s argument is wholly one of self-preservation. If you are an old media and old academia educated intellectual, you will be passed by left and right by those that &lt;em&gt;are&lt;/em&gt; able to strike the right balance between the old and the new. Those that use Twitter and Wikipedia to their full extents while still reflecting on their relative merits, those that can process megatons of information every day while doing their best jobs and retreat from time to time still to read a book or write a piece.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gelezen in 2010</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/gelezen-in-2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2011 21:32:34 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2370</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Naar aanleiding van &lt;a href=&#34;http://interconnected.org/home/2011/01/01/books_read_in_2010&#34;&gt;dit lijstje van meneer Webb&lt;/a&gt;. Ik heb elf boeken uitgelezen in 2010. Schandelijk schamel aantal, ver van de 1 boek per week waar ik naar streef (maar ik heb wél 73 films gezien).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Zero History&amp;rdquo; door William Gibson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.williamgibsonbooks.com/books/spook.asp&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Spook Country&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; door William Gibson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Red ons Maria Montanelli&amp;rdquo; door Herman Koch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cooper.com/journal/2009/01/designing_for_the_digital_age.html&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Designing for the Digital Age&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; door Kim Goodwin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Senorita&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; door Christophe Vekeman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.patternlanguage.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Pattern Language&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; door Christopher Alexander&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theoryoffun.com/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;A Theory of Fun for Game Design&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; door Raph Koster&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sonneten en andere gedichten&amp;rdquo; door F. Petrarca&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Het Diner&amp;rdquo; door Herman Koch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://oreilly.com/catalog/9780596514556/&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Visualizing Data&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; door Ben Fry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;Makers&amp;rdquo; door Cory Doctorow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weinig meer over te zeggen dan dat de boeken die vetgedrukt zijn aanraders zijn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spook Country</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/spook-country/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2010 13:05:45 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2315</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to read Zero History and found out I hadn&amp;rsquo;t read Spook Country yet, so I did. Unfortunately Stanza does not allow a batch export of annotations, but fortunately I did not make that many.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Secrets,”said the Bigend beside her, “are the very root of cool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because that is exactly, specifically, his goal, his only goal: to frighten you into surrendering the rule of law. That’s why they call him ‘terrorist.’ He uses terrifying threats to induce you to degrade your own society.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Een grijs-bruin vaderland</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/een-grijs-bruin-vaderland/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Oct 2010 10:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2257</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik schreef een tijdje geleden al bij &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/4476314878/&#34;&gt;mijn foto&lt;/a&gt; over de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linksehobby.nu/&#34;&gt;Linkse Hobby&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zonder linkse hobby&amp;rsquo;s krijgen we een grijs-bruin land van spruitjeslucht en vlagparades. ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/4476314878/&#34;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;En dat is bewaarheid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maar gelukkig hebben we onze Dichter des Vaderlands, scherpzinnig en met dichterlijke vrijheid als wapen. Na het &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2010/06/het-manifest-van-terschelling/&#34;&gt;manifest van Terschelling&lt;/a&gt;, is het fijn dat Nasr er op en er overheen gaat met &lt;a href=&#34;http://pauwenwitteman.vara.nl/Fragment-detail.1548.0.html?&amp;amp;tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D=18690&amp;amp;tx_ttnews%5BbackPid%5D=116&amp;amp;cHash=78ad049899e85691807acc7ad7a712be&#34;&gt;het gedicht ‘Mijn nieuwe vaderland’&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hele &lt;a href=&#34;http://pauwenwitteman.vara.nl/Fragment-detail.1548.0.html?&amp;amp;tx_ttnews%5Btt_news%5D=18690&amp;amp;tx_ttnews%5BbackPid%5D=116&amp;amp;cHash=78ad049899e85691807acc7ad7a712be&#34;&gt;tekst bij P&amp;amp;W&lt;/a&gt; en op de &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ramseynasr.nl/boekboek/show/id=148263&#34;&gt;site van de Dichter des Vaderlands&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ontwerp en complexiteit als journalistieke kansen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/ontwerp-en-complexiteit-als-journalistieke-kansen/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 21:29:30 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2177</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;De laatste dagen staan een beetje in het teken van gelekte e-mailtjes van, naar en door invloedrijke mensen in Nederland. Een van de recentere is die van de nieuwe hoofdredacteur van het &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nrc.nl&#34;&gt;NRC&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://nl.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peter_Vandermeersch&#34;&gt;Peter Vandermeersch&lt;/a&gt;, naar zijn redactie, hieronder ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/#!/LeviBottle/status/26646195262&#34;&gt;via&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;briefvandermeesch.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/ontwerp-en-complexiteit-als-journalistieke-kansen/briefvandermeesch.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Klik voor groter. Vandermeersch benoemt een serie dingen die de krant zou kunnen en moeten verbeteren om ‘het centrum van het politieke en intellectuele debat’ in Nederland te worden. Ik denk dat weinig mensen echt problemen zouden hebben met deze punten, veel ervan zijn nogal voor de hand liggend: sneller, beter, harder nieuws, geen primeurs laten afpakken, geen dingen laten liggen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zuiverheid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/2043/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2010 10:45:13 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=2043</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In de nacht van vrijdag op zaterdag kreeg onze &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ramseynasr.nl&#34;&gt;Dichter des Vaderlands&lt;/a&gt; een blok van anderhalf uur radio in Zomernachten om te vertellen wat hij wilde. Ik had me in de dag vergist, maar het stond vannacht ook &lt;a href=&#34;http://casaluna.ncrv.nl/pagina/ramsey-nasr&#34;&gt;al op de website&lt;/a&gt;. De MP3 is hier uit de podcast te vissen: &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.ncrv.nl/download/podcast_tool/casaluna_2010_08_21_1282352652_Zomernachten_Ramsey__-_.MP3&#34;&gt;Zomernacht van Ramsey Nasr&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het mag &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/index.php?s=nasr&#34;&gt;hier&lt;/a&gt; al duidelijk zijn dat ik een fan ben van Nasr. Als je die anderhalf uur luistert, word je het waarschijnlijk ook. Een prettige aanklacht tegen de huidige stand van zaken in Nederland, niet populair maar wel goed onderbouwd. Alleen ben ik bang dat hij er geen nieuw publiek mee bereikt. Zolang wij zó in de minderheid zijn kunnen we zeggen wat we willen maar denk ik niet dat we er iets mee bereiken.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check in / Check Out - Design Principles for Camera Surveillance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/check-in-check-out-design-principles-for-camera-surveillance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2010 08:20:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1989</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here the first of my English translations of the design principles outlined in the Dutch book by Rathenau about the digitalization of society and its implications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book is quite good and I think these design principles deserve a wider audience. I&amp;rsquo;ll get to noting down the ones from chapter 0001 in a bit, now just the ones from the (second) chapter 0010 which was unfortunately of somewhat meager interest.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check in / Check Out, Case by Case â€” Case 0010, â€œStraatbeeldenâ€</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/check-in-check-out-case-by-case--case-0010-straatbeelden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2010 17:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1985</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Niet zoveel aan te merken op dit hoofdstuk. Ook niet heel erg mijn interessegebied.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Algemeen over de huidige stand van zaken wat betreft het camera-toezicht, de wettelijke kaders en hier en daar wat dingen over het concept &lt;em&gt;panopticon&lt;/em&gt; en in hoeverre dit geldt wanneer het verzamelen en het bekijken van de beelden gedistribueerd zijn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frappantste is dat de grootste ontwikkeling in het camera-toezicht komt door het internet omdat nu waarschijnlijk het grootste deel van de camera-beelden over internetverbindingen met redelijke standaardprotocollen zal gebeuren. Ik neem aan dat het hiervoor met veel proprietaire systemen gebeurde, die daardoor moeilijk aan elkaar te koppelen waren. Hier dus ook weer IP als grote gelijkmaker.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>â€œit&#39;s more of a very expensive docking station than anythingâ€</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/-its-more-of-a-very-expensive-docking-station-than-anything/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2010 13:36:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1905</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What &lt;a href=&#34;http://ben.hammersley.usesthis.com/&#34;&gt;Ben Hammersley uses&lt;/a&gt; (besides &lt;a href=&#34;http://benhammersley.com/post/718362399/better-out-than-in&#34;&gt;the travel drug&lt;/a&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had an epiphany about 8 years ago, when my home office went from having 4 big tower PCs in various states of repair and OS, along with my own servers and NAS and lots of cable runs and so on, to a single &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IBook&#34; title=&#34;Apple&#39;s old consumer laptop.&#34;&gt;iBook&lt;/a&gt; running off WiFi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Same here. I had this futile attempt at running Linux on the desktop which was a perpetual cause of pain and frustration. I still love that first 12&amp;quot; iBook that saved me from it all.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Check in / Check Out, Case by Case â€” Case 0001, â€œPasjes en poortjesâ€</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/check-in-check-out-case-by-case--case-0001-pasjes-en-poortjes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2010 07:04:24 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1889</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik ben &lt;a href=&#34;http://rathenauinstituut.nl/en/themes/project/digitalisering-van-de-openbare-ruimte-1.html&#34;&gt;het boek&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.naipublishers.nl/checkin_checkuit/index.html&#34;&gt;“Check in / Check out”&lt;/a&gt; van &lt;a href=&#34;http://rathenauinstituut.nl/&#34;&gt;het Rathenau Instituut&lt;/a&gt; aan het lezen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het boek gaat over de digitalisering van de openbare ruimte en welke gevolgen dat heeft voor de privacy van de Nederlanders. Het boek is opgebouwd uit een serie cases en die zal ik hier één voor één lezen en mijn opmerkingen plaatsen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-0001--pasjes-en-poortjes&#34;&gt;Case 0001 — “Pasjes en poortjes”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Er worden zes doelstellingen genoemd ‘van de vervoerder en technologie-aanbieders’:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Het Manifest van Terschelling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/het-manifest-van-terschelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2010 10:44:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1853</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lees het gedicht van Nasr (Ù†Ø³Ø± ) op &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manifestvanterschelling.nl/het_manifest.html&#34;&gt;het Manifest van Terschelling&lt;/a&gt; en &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.manifestvanterschelling.nl/onderteken_het_manifest.html&#34;&gt;onderteken&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;uit nutteloze noodzaak
schiep kunst de mens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Precies dat.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dead trees</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dead-trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2010 09:22:01 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1808</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think I disagree with anything Craig Mod writes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his: &lt;a href=&#34;http://craigmod.com/journal/ipad_and_books/&#34;&gt;“Books in the age of the iPad”&lt;/a&gt; he argues succinctly for the abolishment of most printed books in favor of those that are properly designed for the medium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I myself am going to get rid of all of my books save the design, poetry and photography ones. Because:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The convenience of digital text — on demand, lightweight (in file size and physicality), searchable — already far trumps that of traditional printed matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vrijheid herdenken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/vrijheid-herdenken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2010 15:37:39 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1764</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Een nieuw gedicht van onze Dichter des Vaderlands “Een mooie dag om stilte te verscheuren”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik stond trouwens dinsdagavond ook op de Dam.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Passacaglia</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/passacaglia/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2010 08:32:25 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1698</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dit gedicht van Ramsey Nasr had ik gemist. Hier &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrc.tv/video/nrcnu_/article1366385.ece/Het_hemelse_leven&#34;&gt;het Hemelse Leven&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Van een bijzondere schoonheid weer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nasr doet een nieuwjaarsgroet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/nasr-doet-een-nieuwjaarsgroet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2010 19:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1537</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aangezien onze dichter des vaderlands zijn eigen blog niet zo goed bijhoudt moet het goede volk zijn gedichten hier en daar bij elkaar schrapen of speciaal voor dat handjevol een abonnement nemen op de NRC. Geen doen dus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speciaal voor de fans herhaal en link ik zijn gedichten hier ook maar. Dan heb ik ze tenminste ergens waar ik erbij kan, en jullie ook. Hieronder ook het fragment waar Ramsey Nasr het zelf voordraagt:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Necessities for digital magazines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/necessities-for-digital-magazines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2009 21:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1417</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://benhammersley.com/2009/12/e-books-the-bigger-problem-part-one-of-three/&#34;&gt;Ben Hammersley poses the question&lt;/a&gt; which has been on my mind for a while ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/alper/status/6767585114&#34;&gt;tweet&lt;/a&gt;) now after seeing the various concept demoes of rich magazines on high resolution tablets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been a couple of these concepts floated around recently among which the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.observer.com/2009/media/demo-future-sports-illustrated-tablet&#34;&gt;digital Sports Illustrated&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://berglondon.com/blog/2009/12/17/magplus/&#34;&gt;Mag+ demo for Bonnier&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/8217311&#34;&gt;Mag+&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/bonnier&#34;&gt;Bonnier&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com&#34;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These magazines with rich media and builtin games and other interactions look great, but who&amp;rsquo;s going to make them? From what I know assembling a publication is an efficient but quite messy proces. It gets the thing out the door before the deadline, but not much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kansen in de journalistiek</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/kansen-in-de-journalistiek/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2009 14:15:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1418</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Leuk om &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.werktitel.be/2009/12/%E2%80%98mediacrisis-schept-fantastische-kansen-voor-jonge-journalisten%E2%80%99/comment-page-1/#comment-865&#34;&gt;een link&lt;/a&gt; en een commentaar naar mijn &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2009/10/de-anatomie-van-het-nieuws/&#34;&gt;‘anatomie van het nieuws’ stukje&lt;/a&gt; te krijgen van &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/obk&#34;&gt;Olaf Koens&lt;/a&gt; op het Vlaamse weblog &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.werktitel.be/2009/12/%E2%80%98mediacrisis-schept-fantastische-kansen-voor-jonge-journalisten%E2%80%99/&#34;&gt;Werktitel&lt;/a&gt; over journalistieke vernieuwing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dat boek &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.luuksengers.nl/?page_id=853&#34;&gt;‘Onderzoeksjournalistiek’&lt;/a&gt; van Luuk Sengers wil ik trouwens wel hebben.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Some salon reading</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/some-salon-reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2009 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1400</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Never enough time for reading, but thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.instapaper.com/&#34;&gt;Instapaper&lt;/a&gt; got around to reading some stuff that was due coincidentally both of these are from Salon:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Book review: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dir.salon.com/story/books/review/2004/01/30/frum_perle/index.html&#34;&gt;“An End to Evil”by David Frum and Richard Perle&lt;/a&gt; — Very interesting to read these neocon perspectives in an time when the world and America have shifted away from a position when those points of view were desirable and feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.salon.com/health/sex/urge/2000/01/18/hustler/index.html&#34;&gt;Maxed out&lt;/a&gt; — Interesting take on pornography and how it reflects on society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De anatomie van het nieuws</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-anatomie-van-het-nieuws/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Nov 2009 22:39:18 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1329</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shirky schreef pas zijn anatomie van het nieuws in: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shirky.com/weblog/2009/10/rescuing-the-reporters/&#34;&gt;“Rescuing the Reporters”&lt;/a&gt; waarin hij een krant ontleed in nieuws en restmateriaal en dan ook nog dat nieuws splitst in zelf-gemaakt en uit andere bronnen afkomstig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Het leek me boeiend om dat hier ook te doen, dus kocht ik afgelopen vrijdag twee gedrukte exemplaren van &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nrcnext.nl/&#34;&gt;nrc.next&lt;/a&gt; en wegens tijdgebrek knipte ik ze dinsdag aan stukken. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/4048416724/&#34; title=&#34;Start by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Start&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2578/4048416724_f8a6513a48.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik kwam daarbij wat interessante dilemma&amp;rsquo;s tegen. Wat Shirky hard nieuws noemt komt voor, maar daarnaast staat er in onze kranten ook veel lifestyle-achtig achtergrond materiaal. Het is dus een beetje onduidelijk in sommige gevallen waar dat bij zou moeten.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>een stittie die stilstaat</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/een-stittie-die-stilstaat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2009 10:21:35 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1286</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ramseynasr.nl/&#34;&gt;Ramsey Nasr&lt;/a&gt; bewijst met zijn nieuwste gedicht ‘mi have een droom’ dat hij overduidelijk de beste Dichter des Vaderlands is die we ons maar hadden kunnen wensen:
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nrcnext.nl/blog/2009/09/25/ramsey-nasr-mi-have-een-droom/&#34;&gt;Volledige tekst en meer uitleg&lt;/a&gt; op nrcnext en &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrc.tv/video/nrcnu_/article1363856.ece/mi_have_een_droom&#34;&gt;op nrc.tv wat achtergrond&lt;/a&gt; met ook zijn andere &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kb.nl/dichters/nasr/nasr-inhetland.html&#34;&gt;Koninginnedag-gedicht ‘In het land der koningen’&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;De combinatie straattaal ((Ik kan het volgen maar ik hou me aanbevolen voor een goede gids straattaal.)) en lyriek wordt heel soms wat dissonant maar toch biggie props hoe hij het zich eigen heeft gemaakt. Ik ben wel een beetje benieuwd hoe hij dat gedaan heeft. In &lt;a href=&#34;http://nrc.tv/video/nrcnu_/article1363856.ece/mi_have_een_droom&#34;&gt;het andere filmpje&lt;/a&gt; kun je zien dat hij in Antwerpen woont en bijna alleen maar klassieke muziek heeft.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sketching User Experiences part I â€”Â notes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/sketching-user-experiences-part-i-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2009 12:09:04 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1173</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently reread part I of Sketching User Experiences by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.billbuxton.com/&#34;&gt;Bill Buxton&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxbookclub.org/doku.php?id=zuid-holland&#34;&gt;UX Book Club Zuid-Holland&lt;/a&gt; and made notes during the proces. ‘Sketching’ is one of my favorite UX books and well worth a reread which I found reveals different layers and gets you to reflect differently with the experience you have accumulated since the last time I read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought it may be worthwhile to share those notes here, so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De krant is stuk. Wat nu?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-krant-is-stuk-wat-nu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2009 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=1161</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Van het weekend gebeurden er weer een paar dingen die me met de neus op de feiten drukten hoe kapot ((Als in &lt;em&gt;disfunctioneel&lt;/em&gt;.)) het concept ‘papieren krant’ wel niet is. Ik zeg het al een tijdje en heb opgeschreven waarom ik principieel tegen de papieren krant ben ( &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/dingen/2008/12/quit-your-newspaper-euthanize-a-dead-tree-media-dinosaur/&#34;&gt;alle argumenten&lt;/a&gt;), maar dit was wel saillant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;plek-in-het-leven&#34;&gt;Plek in het leven&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Net een stuk in de Times dat het ochtendritueel van veel Amerikaanse gezinnen wordt verstoord door gadgets en sociale media:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dichter des Vaderlands</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/dichter-des-vaderlands/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2009 10:12:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=751</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik heb de hele verkiezingen rond de dichter des vaderlands gemist ((Één van de weinige nadelige gevolgen van het je onttrekken aan massamedia.)) ((Én blijkbaar ga ik met niemand om die zich bezig houdt met poëzie (dat kan wel kloppen). )) maar ik ben nog steeds blij en ik vind dat ik er iets over moet schrijven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik hoorde het en de dichter zelf woensdagnacht op de radio. Die donderdag ging ik naar Londen en stond op Rotterdam Centraal te wachten op de trein naar Brussel. Ik ging even zitten om mijn rugtas recht te zetten en ik zag naast me op het bankje dezelfde Nasr zitten waar ik de vorige avond &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ramseynasr.nl/&#34;&gt;op de website&lt;/a&gt; ((Erg goed portret, trouwens.)) tegenaan had gekeken.
Ik was stomverbaasd en wist een paar woorden uit te brengen en hem te feliciteren met zijn verkiezing ((Het was niet ondenkbaar geweest dat ik een bundel van hem bij me had gehad door die verkiezing.)). Hij was waarschijnlijk op weg naar Antwerpen en het schijnt &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/obk/status/1158613634&#34;&gt;een vriendelijke man&lt;/a&gt; te zijn.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tax on knowledge</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/tax-on-knowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 16:07:12 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=566</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I called with the taxman yesterday to clarify some stuff. I had surmised that profesionally relevant books could be deducted as expenses. Now it seems there is a very fine distinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profesionally relevant books which are being used to remain up to date in a given field of knowledge are deductable. Books which you are using to deepen and widen your knowledge however are &lt;em&gt;study&lt;/em&gt; books and these as such are not deductable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books read August 2008</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/books-read-august-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 08:25:36 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=376</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the only month where I somewhat approach Matt Webb&amp;rsquo;s amount of reading, he just goes and &lt;a href=&#34;http://interconnected.org/home/2008/08/30/books_read_august_2008&#34;&gt;ups his count&lt;/a&gt; to nearly double mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway here&amp;rsquo;s my list for August. I think the fact that this is an extremely slow summer both in terms of weather and waves somewhat explains this amount. Also that I&amp;rsquo;ve refound a lot of focus in reading and fun in keeping track of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.anobii.com/alper/books&#34;&gt;my shelf on Anobii&lt;/a&gt; ((This probably won&amp;rsquo;t become a regular thing. You can keep track of my reading at Anobii, a site which I recommend.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Onderlezer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/onderlezer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 May 2008 06:49:55 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/?p=291</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deze &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newyorker.com/talk/2008/03/10/080310ta_talk_widdicombe&#34;&gt;baan als culturele attaché&lt;/a&gt; in dienst van &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/name/nm0004976/&#34;&gt;Brian Grazer&lt;/a&gt; lijkt mij ideaal. In ieder geval totdat ik zelf in de positie ben om zo iemand in te huren voor mezelf.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik ben nieuwsgierig, spreek een handjevol talen, ben alpha+bèta+gamma onderlegd, kan moeilijke dingen snel leren en weer goed uitleggen, kan uit de voeten met de meeste nieuwe media en ik vind het niet erg om veel boeken te moeten lezen of om fysiek op stap te moeten gaan om die afspraak te regelen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Een studie in smaragd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/een-studie-in-smaragd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2008 20:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/een-studie-in-smaragd/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Een Sherlock Holmes-pastiche voor de donkere zondagavond ((En voor de mensen met House-ontwenningsverschijnselen.)) geschreven door Neil Gaiman en voorgelezen door hemzelf zoals alleen hij dat kan (via &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.boingboing.net/2008/01/26/gaimans-cthulusherlo.html&#34;&gt;BoingBoing&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hier de &lt;a href=&#34;http://harpercoln.vo.llnwd.net/o16/StudyInEmerald_full.mp3&#34;&gt;audio-file&lt;/a&gt; van het verhaal “A Study in Emerald”en een mooie &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.neilgaiman.com/mediafiles/exclusive/shortstories/emerald.pdf&#34;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt; om op mee te lezen als je wilt. Het kost wat tijd en concentratie maar het is een erg leuk verhaal met veel onthullingen tot de laatste zin. Een bekendheid met het Cthulhu-mythos is niet weg, maar lees de &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Study_In_Emerald&#34;&gt;Wikipedia-pagina&lt;/a&gt; over het verhaal &lt;strong&gt;niet&lt;/strong&gt; (spoilers!) tot je het hebt gelezen/gehoord.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leeslijsten</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/leeslijsten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:54:21 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/leeslijsten/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Van de week bij de IKEA een klein kastje gekocht om mijn boeken dichter bij de hand te hebben.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2226455019/&#34; title=&#34;Books by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Books&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2139/2226455019_468a1dd612.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dat is ongeveer een verzameling boeken waar ik aan begonnen ben (sommigen waarvan ik nog uit wil lezen, anderen&amp;hellip;), boeken die ik op dit moment lees en boeken die binnenkort gelezen gaan worden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Om dit soort lijsten handig bij te houden kwam ik via &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.zog.org/2008/01/boeggn-2.html&#34;&gt;Michel&lt;/a&gt; de site &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.goodreads.com/&#34;&gt;goodreads&lt;/a&gt; tegen. Je kunt lijsten van boeken bijhouden, wanneer je ze hebt gelezen en wat je ervan vond. Dit alles met een sociaal sausje ((Wordt lid en wordt mijn vriend!)), al ken ik denk ik niet meer dan 5 mensen die boeken lezen ((D.w.z. die serieus boeken lezen en/of serieuze boeken lezen.)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Autodidact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/autodidact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2008 23:30:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/autodidact/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Het leuke aan klaar zijn met studeren is dat je dingen kunt gaan leren die jÃ­j belangrijk vindt. En ik leer sneller als ik zelf mag bepalen hoe en hoe snel. Dus hier twee boeken in een serie voor het komende jaar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/alper/2226450077/&#34; title=&#34;Books by illustir, on Flickr&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Books&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2102/2226450077_013b2b9a3b.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veel designboeken uit de usability-, interaction- en experience-hoek met daarbij een grote stapel non-fictie: filosofie, politiek, geschiedenis, economie, nieuwe media en meer. Breed ge-orienteerd zoals altijd, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wordspy.com/words/T-shaped.asp&#34;&gt;t-shaped&lt;/a&gt; noemen ze dat geloof ik.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Leesboeken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/leesboeken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2008 18:33:57 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/leesboeken/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Deze week ben ik langs &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.abc.nl&#34;&gt;ABC&lt;/a&gt; Den Haag geweest om een paar boeken te kopen om nú te lezen ((De boeken die ik normaal zou lezen zitten nog ingepakt, en ik moet toch iets lezen.)). Ik koop liever niets meer bij normale winkels tenzij ze tof zijn zoals de ABC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ik wilde kopen: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FBlack-Swan-Impact-Highly-Improbable%2Fdp%2F1400063515&amp;amp;tag=alpercugun-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=alpercugun-20&amp;l=ur2&amp;o=1&#34;&gt; en &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/redirect.html?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;location=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.amazon.com%2FAm-America-So-Can-You%2Fdp%2F0446580503&amp;amp;tag=alpercugun-20&amp;amp;linkCode=ur2&amp;amp;camp=1789&amp;amp;creative=9325&#34;&gt;I Am America (And So Can You!)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://www.assoc-amazon.com/e/ir?t=alpercugun-20&amp;l=ur2&amp;o=1&#34;&gt;. Van the Black Swan hadden ze alleen maar de hardcover versie van €30 ((Boeken zijn ook bij de ABC bizar duur. The Black Swan is omgerekend €10 bij Amazon.com.)) liggen en I Am America was uitverkocht.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boekenlijst</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/boekenlijst/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2008 11:39:02 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2008/01/boekenlijst/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik zat het einde van het jaar mijn lijstjes door te kijken en ik zag dat ik in 2007 maar vier (!) boeken heb gelezen. Dan zie je iemand als Aaronsw die er 70 consumeert en dat weinig vindt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Afstuderen slokt je leven op en met vier boeken scoor ik nog steeds hoger dan mijn meeste vrienden maar dit jaar ga ik meer lezen ((Minder kan haast niet.)). Ik heb gisternacht Der Prozess van Kafka uitgelezen ((En me de volgende dag half verslapen.)) dus dit jaar op schema: één week, één boek.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Popper over de noodzaak van vrede en rationalisme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/popper-over-de-noodzaak-van-vrede-en-rationalisme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2007 22:22:19 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/10/popper-over-de-noodzaak-van-vrede-en-rationalisme/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In het hoofdstuk &amp;lsquo;Waging Wars for Peace&amp;rsquo; ((Een interview van Popper voor Der Spiegel in 1992)) legt Popper uit dat het ons gerechtvaardigd is om desnoods geweld te gebruiken en oorlog te voeren als we de verspreiding en het gebruik van kernwapens maar kunnen tegengaan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over de milieubeweging:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There is an anti-rationalist kernel in the Greens that leads to the exact opposite of what they are supposed to want. They also want power themselves, and are as hypocritical as they claim their opponents to be.
Environmental disasters are largely due to the population explosion, which we must solve ethically. Really, only children who are wanted should come into the world ((Hiermee raakt hij aan de in Freakonomics besproken correlatie tussen de legalisatie van abortus en de neerwaartse misdaadtrend.)).”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De Profeet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/de-profeet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2007 14:37:28 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/08/de-profeet/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Maandag &lt;a href=&#34;http://leb.net/gibran/works/prophet/prophet.html&#34;&gt;The Prophet&lt;/a&gt; van &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Khalil_Gibran&#34;&gt;Khalil Gibran&lt;/a&gt; uitgelezen. Aardige teksten en immens quotebaar. Hier twee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you cannot work with love but only with distaste, it is better that you should leave your work and sit at the gate of the temple and take alms of those who work with joy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For what is your friend that you should seek him with hours to kill? Seek him always with hours to live.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drie Werelden over Waarheid en Menselijkheid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/drie-werelden-over-waarheid-en-menselijkheid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2007 14:40:38 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/07/drie-werelden-over-waarheid-en-menselijkheid/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik lees nu &amp;ldquo;All life is problem solving&amp;rdquo; ((Vertaald, maar ik had hem al gekocht.)) van &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Karl_Popper&#34;&gt;Karl Popper&lt;/a&gt; en het is zware kost ((Gelukkig niet zo zwaar als &amp;ldquo;Objective Knowledge&amp;rdquo;)) maar ook erg waardevol en boeiend. Vergeef het vage gezwam, maar ik ga af en toe wat inhoud van wat ik lees hier verwerken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zojuist heb ik de lezing over het Geest-Lichaamprobleem uit en daar komen wel wat interessante ideeën uit voort. Popper pakt dit probleem aan door alles te verdelen in drie werelden.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Macbook ingeleverd</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/macbook-ingeleverd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 May 2007 20:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
       <guid isPermaLink="false">http://alper.nl/dingen/2007/05/macbook-ingeleverd/</guid> 
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ik heb vanochtend vroeg ((Erg verdomde vroeg als je vier uur slaapt.)) mijn Macbook ingeleverd bij &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ljs.nl&#34;&gt;LJS&lt;/a&gt; op de Lutherse Burgwal. Daarna koffie gedronken in Florencia, grappige tent en aparte interpretatie van het concept cappuccino.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In tegenstelling tot wat ik dacht krijg ik mijn Macbook niet in de loop van de dag terug omdat ze al vermoeden wat er mis is met de batterij, die meteen gaan bestellen en hem dan morgenmiddag met nieuwe batterij aan me teruggeven. Dat zou wel heel fijn zijn. Dan kan ik eindelijk die beloofde zes uur lang in het park zitten werken ((Zodra het weer droog is.))&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
